<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TED_EXPORT xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://publications.europa.eu/resource/schema/ted/R2.0.9/publication" xmlns:n2016="http://publications.europa.eu/resource/schema/ted/2016/nuts" xsi:schemaLocation="http://publications.europa.eu/resource/schema/ted/R2.0.9/publication TED_EXPORT.xsd" VERSION="R2.0.9.S03.E01" DOC_ID="041988-2019" EDITION="2019020"><TECHNICAL_SECTION><RECEPTION_ID>19-029132-001</RECEPTION_ID><DELETION_DATE>20190427</DELETION_DATE><FORM_LG_LIST>DA DE EN ES FI FR EL IT NL PT SV CS ET HU LT LV MT PL SK SL GA BG RO HR </FORM_LG_LIST><COMMENTS>From Convertor</COMMENTS></TECHNICAL_SECTION><LINKS_SECTION><XML_SCHEMA_DEFINITION_LINK xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://ted.europa.eu" xlink:title="TED WEBSITE"/><OFFICIAL_FORMS_LINK xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://ted.europa.eu"/><FORMS_LABELS_LINK xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://ted.europa.eu"/><ORIGINAL_CPV_LINK xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://ted.europa.eu"/><ORIGINAL_NUTS_LINK xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://ted.europa.eu"/></LINKS_SECTION><CODED_DATA_SECTION><REF_OJS><COLL_OJ>S</COLL_OJ><NO_OJ>20</NO_OJ><DATE_PUB>20190129</DATE_PUB></REF_OJS><NOTICE_DATA><NO_DOC_OJS>2019/S 020-041988</NO_DOC_OJS><URI_LIST><URI_DOC LG="DA">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:DA:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="DE">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:DE:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="EN">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:EN:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="ES">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:ES:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="FI">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:FI:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="FR">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:FR:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="EL">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:EL:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="IT">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:IT:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="NL">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:NL:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="PT">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:PT:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="SV">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:SV:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="CS">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:CS:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="ET">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:ET:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="HU">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:HU:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="LT">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:LT:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="LV">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:LV:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="MT">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:MT:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="PL">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:PL:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="SK">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:SK:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="SL">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:SL:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="GA">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:GA:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="BG">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:BG:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="RO">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:RO:HTML</URI_DOC><URI_DOC LG="HR">http://ted.europa.eu/udl?uri=TED:NOTICE:041988-2019:TEXT:HR:HTML</URI_DOC></URI_LIST><LG_ORIG>EN</LG_ORIG><ISO_COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><IA_URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</IA_URL_GENERAL><ORIGINAL_CPV CODE="48463000">Statistical software package</ORIGINAL_CPV><n2016:PERFORMANCE_NUTS CODE="PL">POLSKA</n2016:PERFORMANCE_NUTS><n2016:CA_CE_NUTS CODE="PL911">Miasto Warszawa</n2016:CA_CE_NUTS><n2016:TENDERER_NUTS CODE="PL">POLSKA</n2016:TENDERER_NUTS><VALUES><VALUE TYPE="PROCUREMENT_TOTAL" CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VALUE></VALUES></NOTICE_DATA><CODIF_DATA><DS_DATE_DISPATCH>20190117</DS_DATE_DISPATCH><AA_AUTHORITY_TYPE CODE="5">European Institution/Agency or International Organisation</AA_AUTHORITY_TYPE><TD_DOCUMENT_TYPE CODE="7">Contract award notice</TD_DOCUMENT_TYPE><NC_CONTRACT_NATURE CODE="4">Services</NC_CONTRACT_NATURE><PR_PROC CODE="T">Negotiated without a prior call for competition</PR_PROC><RP_REGULATION CODE="3">European Institution/Agency or International Organisation</RP_REGULATION><TY_TYPE_BID CODE="9">Not applicable</TY_TYPE_BID><AC_AWARD_CRIT CODE="2">The most economic tender</AC_AWARD_CRIT><MA_MAIN_ACTIVITIES CODE="S">General public services</MA_MAIN_ACTIVITIES><HEADING>AGC03</HEADING><INITIATOR>AG</INITIATOR></CODIF_DATA></CODED_DATA_SECTION><TRANSLATION_SECTION><ML_TITLES><ML_TI_DOC LG="DA"><TI_CY>Polen</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Rammeaftale vedrørende indkøb af SAS-softwarelicenser</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="DE"><TI_CY>Polen</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Rahmenvertrag über die Beschaffung von SAS-Software-Lizenzen</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="EN"><TI_CY>Poland</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Framework Contract for the acquisition of SAS software licences</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="ES"><TI_CY>Polonia</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Contrato marco para la adquisición de licencias de software SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="FI"><TI_CY>Puola</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Puitesopimus SAS-ohjelmistolisenssien hankintaa varten</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="FR"><TI_CY>Pologne</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Contrat-cadre relatif à l'acquisition de licences logicielles SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="EL"><TI_CY>Πολωνία</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Σύμβαση-πλαίσιο για την αγορά αδειών λογισμικού SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="IT"><TI_CY>Polonia</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Contratto quadro per l'acquisizione di licenze software SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="NL"><TI_CY>Polen</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Raamovereenkomst voor de verwerving van SAS-softwarelicenties</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="PT"><TI_CY>Polónia</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Contrato-quadro para a aquisição de licenças de software SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="SV"><TI_CY>Polen</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Ramavtal för anskaffande av programvarulicenser avseende SAS (Statistical Analysis System)</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="CS"><TI_CY>Polsko</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Rámcová smlouva na pořízení licencí na software SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="ET"><TI_CY>Poola</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Raamleping SASi tarkvaralitsentside hankimise kohta</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="HU"><TI_CY>Lengyelország</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>SAS szoftverlicencek beszerzésére irányuló keretszerződés</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="LT"><TI_CY>Lenkija</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Preliminarioji sutartis dėl SAS programinės įrangos licencijos įsigijimo</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="LV"><TI_CY>Polija</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Pamatnolīgums par SAS programmatūras licenču iegādi</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="MT"><TI_CY>il-Polonja</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Qafas ta' Kuntratt għall-ksib ta' liċenzji tas-softwer SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="PL"><TI_CY>Polska</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Umowa ramowa o zakup licencji oprogramowania SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="SK"><TI_CY>Poľsko</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Rámcová zmluva na obstaranie softvérových licencií SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="SL"><TI_CY>Poljska</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Okvirno naročilo za nakup licenc za programsko opremo SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="GA"><TI_CY>Pholainn, an</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Creatchonradh le haghaidh ceadúnas bogearraí SAS a fháil</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="BG"><TI_CY>Полша</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Рамков договор за набавяне на лицензи за софтуер SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="RO"><TI_CY>Polonia</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Contract-cadru pentru achiziționarea de licențe de software SAS</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC><ML_TI_DOC LG="HR"><TI_CY>Poljska</TI_CY><TI_TOWN>Warszawa</TI_TOWN><TI_TEXT><P>Okvirni ugovor za nabavu licenci za softver sustava za statističku analizu (Statistical Analysis System — SAS)</P></TI_TEXT></ML_TI_DOC></ML_TITLES><ML_AA_NAMES><AA_NAME LG="DA">Frontex — Det Europæiske Agentur for Grænse- og Kystbevogtning</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="DE">Frontex — Europäische Agentur für die Grenz- und Küstenwache</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="EN">Frontex — European Border and Coast Guard Agency</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="ES">Agencia Europea de la Guardia de Fronteras y Costas (Frontex)</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="FI">Frontex – Euroopan raja- ja merivartiovirasto</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="FR">Frontex — Agence européenne de garde-frontières et de garde-côtes</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="EL">Frontex — Ευρωπαϊκός Οργανισμός Συνοριοφυλακής και Ακτοφυλακής</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="IT">Frontex — Agenzia europea della guardia di frontiera e costiera</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="NL">Frontex — Europees grens- en kustwachtagentschap</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="PT">Frontex — Agência Europeia da Guarda de Fronteiras e Costeira</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="SV">Frontex — Europeiska gräns- och kustbevakningsbyrån</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="CS">Frontex – Evropská agentura pro pohraniční a pobřežní stráž</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="ET">Frontex – Euroopa Piiri- ja Rannikuvalve Amet</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="HU">Frontex – Európai Határ- és Partvédelmi Ügynökség</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="LT">Frontex – Europos sienų ir pakrančių apsaugos agentūra</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="LV">Frontex – Eiropas Robežu un krasta apsardzes aģentūra</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="MT">Frontex — L-Aġenzija Ewropea għall-Gwardja tal-Fruntiera u tal-Kosta</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="PL">Frontex – Europejska Agencja Straży Granicznej i Przybrzeżnej</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="SK">Frontex – Európska agentúra pre pohraničnú a pobrežnú stráž</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="SL">Frontex – Evropska agencija za mejno in obalno stražo</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="GA">Frontex — an Ghníomhaireacht Eorpach um an nGarda Teorann agus Cósta</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="BG">Frontex — Европейска агенция за гранична и брегова охрана</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="RO">Frontex – Agenția Europeană pentru Poliția de Frontieră și Garda de Coastă</AA_NAME><AA_NAME LG="HR">Frontex — Agencija za europsku graničnu i obalnu stražu</AA_NAME></ML_AA_NAMES></TRANSLATION_SECTION><FORM_SECTION><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="DA"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Det Europæiske Agentur for Grænse- og Kystbevogtning</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Rammeaftale vedrørende indkøb af SAS-softwarelicenser</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Kontraktens formål er oprettelsen af en indkøbskanal i medfør af en rammeaftale, der muliggør indkøb af SAS-softwarelicenser:</P><P>1) med henblik på fornyelse og vedligeholdelse af SAS-softwarelicenssæt, der anvendes hos Frontex;</P><P>2) med henblik på udvidelsesoption for SAS-softwarelicenssæt, der anvendes hos Frontex:</P><P>(a) Indkøb af yderligere licenser til produkter, der allerede anvendes og/eller</P><P>(b) Indkøb af licenser til andre SAS-softwareprodukter.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLEN</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Kontraktens formål er levering af SAS-softwarekontrakter i medfør af en rammeaftale.</P><P>Tilbudsgiver blev anmodet om at levere følgende tjenester og leverancer:</P><P>A. Fornyelsesgebyr for Frontex' licenser til SAS-lagringssystemer</P><P>(a) Forslaget skal indeholde en detaljeret specifikation af SAS-softwaren og dens delkomponenter, herunder antallet af relaterede softwarelicenser, der indgår i Frontex' SAS-lagringssystem.</P><P>(b) Forslaget skal udelukkende indeholde fornyelsesgebyrer.</P><P>B. Forslag der indeholder ekstra SAS-softwarelicenssæt til supplering af Frontex' licenser til SAS-lagringssystem med henblik på at øge dets databehandlingskapacitet og/eller -adgang.</P><P>(a) Tilbudsgiver anmodes om kun at foreslå teknisk udførlige løsninger.</P><P>(b) Forslaget skal indeholde en detaljeret specifikation af SAS-softwaren og dens delkomponenter, herunder antallet af relaterede softwarelicenser, som er nødvendige for opnåelsen af den planlagte forøgelse af databehandlingskapaciteten og/eller -adgangen.</P><P>(c) Tilbudsgiver anmodes om at foreslå et lille antal teknisk udførlige varianter, der muliggør en forøgelse af databehandlingskapaciteten og/eller -adgangen med f.eks.: 10%, 20% og 50%. Varianterne skal beskrives nøje og mærkes i det tekniske forslag og finansieringsforslaget som f.eks. B1, B2 osv.</P><P>(d) Forslaget skal indeholde begge følgende pristyper: Førsteårsgebyr og fornyelsesgebyr.</P><P>(e) Om nødvendigt skal forslaget indeholde en pris på en relevant installationstjeneste.</P><P>C. Forslag der indeholder ekstra licenssæt til SAS-software og dens delkomponenter med henblik på at udvide Frontex' SAS-lagringssystem ved tilføjelse af andre SAS-softwareprodukter for at øge Frontex' SAS-lagringssystem via ekstra softwaremoduler og dertil knyttede delkomponenter, der muliggør en bedre dataforvaltning i form af et integreret, virksomhedsorienteret, moderne ETL-værktøj, der støtter GUI-baseret udvikling. Tilbudsgiver anmodes om at foreslå softwarelicenssæt til:</P><P>(i) SAS-dataintegration</P><P>(ii) SAS-datakvalitet</P><P>Sættene skal beskrives nøje og mærkes i det tekniske forslag og finansieringsforslaget som f.eks. C1 og C2.</P><P>(a) De foreslåede softwarelicenssæt skal være fuldt overensstemmende med Frontex' SAS-lagringssystem, dvs. være teknisk anvendeligt i dette system.</P><P>(b) Forslaget skal indeholde en fortegnelse over alle obligatoriske krav/betingelser, der skal opfyldes for at gennemføre udvidelsen (f.eks. tekniske minimumskrav til servere osv.).</P><P>(c) Forslaget skal være tilpasset til Frontex' SAS-lagringssystem, hvad angår dets størrelse og mængden af behandlet data, samt være egnet til formålet.</P><P>(d) Gennemførelsen, ibrugtagelsen og det forventede daglige arbejdsomfang i forbindelse med de foreslåede komponenter må ikke medføre nogen negativ indvirkning på effektiviteten af de eksisterende SAS-systemløsninger hos Frontex (f.eks. svartider, databehandlingsresultater, lagringskapacitet, rapportadgang og interaktivitet).</P><P>(e) Den foreslåede løsning skal muliggøre en rimelig forhøjelse af brugen af systemet som følge af potentielt forøgede datamængder, et forøget antal brugere, ny systemapplikationsområder osv.</P><P>(f) Den foreslåede udvælgelse af komponenter samt det foreslåede antal licenser skal begrundes kort i forslaget.</P><P>(g) Forslaget skal indeholde en detaljeret specifikation af SAS-softwaren og dens delkomponenter, herunder antallet af relaterede softwarelicenser, som er nødvendige for at udvide Frontex' SAS-lagringssystem med den tilsigtede funktionalitet.</P><P>(h) Forslaget skal indeholde begge følgende pristyper: Førsteårsgebyr og fornyelsesgebyr.</P><P>(i) Om nødvendigt skal forslaget indeholde en pris på en relevant installationstjeneste.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Kontrahentens kvalifikationer, ekspertise, egnethed og faglige kompetencer, det samlede tekniske forslags klarhed og præcision samt forståelsen af formålene.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Lige fra Frontex' start har risikoanalyse været én af de vigtigste operationelle aktiviteter og udgangspunktet for andre aktiviteter. Opgaver relateret til risikoanalyse, der skal udføres af Frontex, blev fastlagt i den første Frontex-forordning (EF) 2007/2004. I den ny Frontex-forordning (EU) 2016/1624 er opgaverne relateret til risikoanalyse endog udvidet i forhold til tidligere. Frontex' organisationsstruktur er for nyligt blevet ændret, og der er blevet oprettet en afdeling for situtationsbevidsthed og overvågning med henblik på opfyldelse af de ny krav.</P><P>SAS-softwarens rolle og betydning hvad angår risikoanalyseprocessen hos Frontex</P><P>SAS-teknologi er støtteværktøj for risikoanalyseopgaver hos Frontex. Den første indførelse af SAS-teknologi fandt sted i 2008. Siden 2008 har Frontex investeret en betragtelig mængde ressourcer, hvad angår tid, menneskelige ressourcer og finansielle midler til:</P><P>— SAS-softwarelicenser og deres integration i Frontex' arkitektur,</P><P>— Specifik hardware med henblik på opfyldelse af krav til anvendt SAS-software,</P><P>— Undervisning og workshopper der gennemføres med henblik på lettelse af Frontex-personalets tilgang til passende viden. Der er nu et vigtigt SAS-baseret vidensgrundlag hos Frontex.</P><P>I dag er SAS-teknologi en af de afgørende kærnekomponenter i risikoanalyseprocessen.</P><P>En potentiel erstatning af SAS-teknologi med en tilsvarende teknologi ville kræve en strategisk beslutning for at iværksætte processen, som ville vare flere år og kræve betragtelige finansielle og ikke-finansielle investeringer med henblik på at opnå en modenhedsgrad, som svar til den eksisterende. I løbet af denne periode ville løsninger baseret på SAS-teknologi som minimum kræve vedligeholdelse.</P><P>SAS Institute og dets markedsposition.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. er enefabrikant og -udgiver af SAS-software. SAS Institute Inc. besidder den intellektuelle ejendomsret over SAS-software. SAS Institute sp. z o.o. et datterselskab af SAS Institute Inc., har enerettighed angående tildeling af licenser til SAS-software til brug for enheder, som er forpligtet til at anvende loven om offentlige indkøb i Polen.</P><P>Valg af udbudsprocedure.</P><P>Udbudsproceduren vedrørende SAS-softwarelicenser vil være udbud med forhandling uden forudgående offentliggørelse af udbudsbekendtgørelse i overensstemmelse med punkt 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) i bilag I FR (tidligere artikel 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) i gennemførelsesbestemmelserne), af tekniske årsager og behov for beskyttelse af enerettigheder. Kontrakten kan således kun tildeles én bestemt økonomisk aktør. Ovennævnte procedure er blevet valgt, da SAS Institute er eneejer af licenserne.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Rammeaftale vedrørende indkøb af SAS-softwarelicenser</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Retten</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Retten</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Retten</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="DE"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Europäische Agentur für die Grenz- und Küstenwache</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Rahmenvertrag über die Beschaffung von SAS-Software-Lizenzen</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Gegenstand dieses Auftrags ist die Einrichtung eines Beschaffungskanals in Form eines Rahmenvertrags, der den Kauf von SAS-Software-Lizenzen ermöglicht:</P><P>1) um die von Frontex genutzten SAS-Software-Lizenzen zu erneuern und zu pflegen;</P><P>2) um die von Frontex genutzten SAS-Software-Lizenzen optional zu verlängern durch:</P><P>a) den Kauf weiterer Lizenzen für genutzte Produkte und/oder</P><P>b) den Kauf von Lizenzen für andere SAS-Software-Produkte.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLEN.</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Gegenstand dieses Auftrags ist die Bereitstellung von SAS-Software-Lizenzen im Rahmen eines Rahmenvertrags.</P><P>Der Bieter wurde aufgefordert, die folgenden Dienstleistungen und Lieferungen zu erbringen:</P><P>A. Verlängerungsgebühr für die wesentlichen SAS-Systemlizenzen von Frontex</P><P>(a) Das Angebot muss eine detaillierte Beschreibung der SAS-Software und Teilkomponenten einschließlich der Anzahl der damit verbundenen Software-Lizenzen, die das SAS-Kernsystem von Frontex ausmachen, enthalten.</P><P>(b) Das Angebot darf nur Verlängerungsgebühren enthalten.</P><P>B. Angebot über eine zusätzliche Reihe von SAS-Software-Lizenzen zur Ergänzung des SAS-Kernsystems von Frontex, um dessen Verarbeitungskapazität und/oder Verfügbarkeit zu steigern.</P><P>(a) Der Bieter wird aufgefordert, nur technisch anwendbare Lösungen anzubieten.</P><P>(b) Das Angebot muss eine detaillierte Beschreibung der SAS-Software und Teilkomponenten einschließlich der Anzahl der damit verbundenen Software-Lizenzen enthalten, die erforderlich sind, um die geplante Steigerung der Verarbeitungskapazität und/oder Verfügbarkeit zu erzielen.</P><P>(c) Der Bieter wird aufgefordert, einige technisch anwendbare Varianten anzubieten, die eine Steigerung der Verarbeitungskapazität und/oder Verfügbarkeit ermöglichen, z. B. um: 10 %, 20 % und 50 %. Die Varianten sind deutlich zu beschreiben und im technischen Angebot und im finanziellen Angebot als B1, B2, usw. zu kennzeichnen.</P><P>(d) Das Angebot enthält beide Arten von Preisen: Erstjahresgebühr (First Year Fee (FYF)) und Verlängerungsgebühr (Renewal Fee (RF)).</P><P>(e) Falls erforderlich, enthält das Angebot den Preis für den jeweiligen Installationsdienst.</P><P>C. Angebot über eine zusätzliche Reihe von SAS-Software-Lizenzen und deren Teilkomponenten zur Erweiterung des SAS-Kernsystems von Frontex durch Einführung weiterer SAS-Software-Produkte und zur Erweiterung des aktuellen SAS-Kernsystems von Frontex durch zusätzliche Software-Module und die damit verbundenen Teilkomponenten, die eine bessere Datensteuerung durch ein integriertes, modernes ETL-Tool für Unternehmen, das die Entwicklung auf GUI-Basis unterstützt, ermöglichen. Der Bieter wird aufgefordert, Software-Lizenzen für Folgendes anzubieten:</P><P>(i) SAS-Datenintegration</P><P>(iii) SAS-Datenqualität</P><P>Die Lizenzen sind deutlich zu beschreiben und im technischen Angebot und im finanziellen Angebot als C1, C2, usw. zu kennzeichnen.</P><P>(a) Die angebotenen Software-Lizenzen müssen vollständig konform mit dem SAS-Kernsystem von Frontex sein, d. h. sie müssen technisch in diesem System anwendbar sein.</P><P>(b) Das Angebot muss eine Liste aller verbindlichen Anforderungen/Bedingungen enthalten, um eine Erweiterung umzusetzen (d. h. technische Mindestanforderungen für Server, usw.).</P><P>(c) Das Angebot muss dem SAS-Kernsystem von Frontex hinsichtlich der Größenordnung und Mengen der verarbeiteten Daten entsprechen und für den Zweck geeignet sein.</P><P>(d) Die angebotene Integration, Umsetzung und das erwartete tägliche Arbeitsvolumen der Komponenten darf sich nicht negativ auf die Effizienz der bestehenden SAS-Systemlösungen von Frontex auswirken (z. B. Reaktionszeiten, Leistungsfähigkeit der Datenverarbeitung, Speicherkapazität, Zugänglichkeit der Berichte und Interaktivität).</P><P>(e) Die angebotene Lösung muss ein berechtigtes Wachstum der Systemnutzung aufgrund durch ein erhöhtes Datenvolumen, eine größere Anzahl von Nutzern, neuen Bereichen der Systemanwendung, usw. ermöglichen.</P><P>(f) Die angebotene Auswahl an Komponenten sowie die angebotene Anzahl an Lizenzen muss im Angebot kurz begründet sein.</P><P>(g) Das Angebot muss eine detaillierte Beschreibung der SAS-Software und Teilkomponenten einschließlich der Anzahl der damit verbundenen Software-Lizenzen enthalten, die erforderlich sind, um das SAS-Kernsystem von Frontex um die beabsichtigte Funktionalität zu erweitern.</P><P>(h) Das Angebot enthält beide Arten von Preisen: Erstjahresgebühr (First Year Fee (FYF)) und Verlängerungsgebühr (Renewal Fee (RF)).</P><P>(i) Falls erforderlich, enthält das Angebot den Preis für den jeweiligen Installationsdienst.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Qualifikationen, Fachwissen, Eignung und berufliche Leistungsfähigkeit des Auftragnehmers, Klarheit und Prägnanz des gesamten technischen Angebots und Verständnis der Zielvorgaben.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Seit der Gründung von Frontex ist die Risikoanalyse eine der betrieblichen Kernaktivitäten, die die Grundlage für andere Aktivitäten bildet. Die von Frontex durchgeführten Aufgaben in Bezug auf die Risikoanalyse wurden in der ersten Frontex-Verordnung (EG) 2007/2004 festgelegt. In der neuen Frontex-Verordnung (EU) 2016/1624 wurden die Aufgaben in Bezug auf die Risikoanalyse im Vergleich zum vorherigen Stand sogar noch erweitert. Die Firmenstruktur von Frontex wurde kürzlich geändert und die Abteilungen Situationsbewusstsein (Situational Awareness) und Überwachung (Monitoring) wurden geschaffen, um die neuen Anforderungen zu erfüllen.</P><P>Die Rolle von SAS-Software und ihre Bedeutung für den Prozess der Risikoanalyse bei Frontex</P><P>Die SAS-Technologie ist das Hilfsmittel zur Unterstützung der Aufgaben in Bezug auf die Risikoanalyse bei Frontex. Die erste Einführung der SAS-Technologie erfolgte im Jahr 2008. Seit 2008 hat Frontex bedeutende Ressourcen im Hinblick auf Zeit, Humanressourcen und finanzielle Mittel für Folgendes investiert:</P><P>— SAS-Software-Lizenzen und deren Integration in die Frontex-Architektur,</P><P>— Spezifische Hardware, um die Anforderungen für die verwendete SAS-Software zu erfüllen,</P><P>— Schulungen und Workshops, die durchgeführt wurden, um dem Frontex-Personal zu helfen, die entsprechenden Kenntnisse zu erlangen. Nun wurde bei Frontex ein beachtlicher Wissensfundus basierend auf der SAS-Technologie zusammengetragen.</P><P>Heute ist die SAS-Technologie eine der Kernkomponenten der Risikoanalyse.</P><P>Ein Austausch der SAS-Technologie durch eine äquivalente Technologie erfordert eine strategische Entscheidung für die Einleitung eines Prozesses, der mehrere Jahre andauert und erhebliche finanzielle und nicht-finanzielle Investitionen erfordert, um eine Ausgereiftheit zu erreichen, die der aktuellen gleichkommt. Während dieses Zeitraums müssten die auf der SAS-Technologie basierenden Lösungen mindestens gepflegt werden.</P><P>SAS Institute und seine Marktlage.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. ist der einzige Hersteller und Anbieter von SAS-Software. SAS Institute Inc. ist Besitzer der geistigen Eigentumsrechte an SAS-Software. SAS Institute sp. z o.o. ist ein Tochterunternehmen von SAS Institute Inc., hat das exklusive Recht zur Gewährung von Lizenzen für SAS-Software zugunsten von Rechtsträgern, die verpflichtet sind, das öffentliche Beschaffungswesen in Polen zu verwenden.</P><P>Wahl des Beschaffungsverfahrens.</P><P>Das Beschaffungsverfahren für SAS-Software-Lizenzen ist ein Verhandlungsverfahren ohne vorherige Veröffentlichung einer Auftragsbekanntmachung in Übereinstimmung mit Ziffer 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) des Anhangs I FR (zuvor Art. 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) der Anwendungsbestimmungen (RAP)), und dies beruht auf technischen Gründen und der Erfordernis des Schutzes von ausschließlichen Rechten. Deshalb kann der Auftrag nur an einen bestimmten Wirtschaftsteilnehmer vergeben werden. Da SAS Institute der alleinige Besitzer der Lizenzen ist, wurde das oben erwähnte Verfahren gewählt.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Rahmenvertrag über die Beschaffung von SAS-Software-Lizenzen</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Gericht</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Gericht</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Gericht</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="ORIGINAL" FORM="F03" LG="EN"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — European Border and Coast Guard Agency</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Framework Contract for the acquisition of SAS software licences</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>The subject of this Contract is to establish an acquisition channel in a form of a Framework Contract enabling purchase of SAS Software licenses:</P><P>1) in order to renew and maintain the set of SAS Software licenses which is in use in Frontex;</P><P>2) in order to optionally extend the set of SAS Software licenses which is in use in Frontex by:</P><P>(a) Purchasing more licenses for products being in use and/or</P><P>(b) Purchasing licenses for other SAS Software products.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, Poland</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>The subject of this Contract is provision of SAS Software licenses under FWC.</P><P>The tenderer was requested to provide the following services and supplies:</P><P>A. Renewal fee (RF) for Frontex’ core SAS system licenses</P><P>(a) The proposal shall contain a detailed specification of SAS Software and subcomponents including the number of related software licenses which compose Frontex’ core SAS system.</P><P>(b) The proposal shall contain only Renewal Fee (RF).</P><P>B. Proposal containing an additional sets of SAS Software licenses to supplement Frontex’ core SAS system in order to increase its processing capacity and/or availability.</P><P>(a) The Tenderer is requested to propose the technically applicable solutions only.</P><P>(b) The proposal shall contain a detailed specification of SAS Software and subcomponents including the number of related software licenses which are needed to achieve the planned increase of a processing capacity and/or availability.</P><P>(c) Tenderer is requested to propose a few technically applicable variants enabling an increase of processing capacity and/or availability by e.g.: 10 %, 20 % and 50 %. The variants should be clearly described and marked in technical proposal and in financial proposal as B1, B2, etc.</P><P>(d) The proposal shall contain both types of prices: First Year Fee (FYF) and Renewal Fee (RF).</P><P>(e) If needed the proposal should contain a price of a relevant installation service.</P><P>C. Proposal containing additional sets of licenses for SAS Software and its subcomponents, in order to extend Frontex’ core SAS system by introducing other SAS Software products To extend the current Frontex’ core SAS system by additional software modules and the related subcomponents enabling better data governance by integrated, enterprise-class, modern ETL tool that supports GUI-based development. The Tenderer is requested to propose sets of software licenses for:</P><P>(i) SAS Data Integration</P><P>(ii) SAS Data Quality</P><P>The sets should be clearly described and marked in technical proposal and in financial proposal as C1 and C2.</P><P>(a) The proposed sets of software licenses must be fully compliant with Frontex’ core SAS system i.e. must be technically applicable to this system.</P><P>(b) The proposal must contain a list of all the mandatory requirements/conditions to be met in order to implement an extension (e.g. minimum technical requirements for servers, etc.).</P><P>(c) The proposal shall be adequate to Frontex core SAS system in terms of its scale and amounts of data processed as well as to fit for purpose.</P><P>(d) The proposed components’ implementation, deployment and expected daily workload cannot introduce negative impact on the existing Frontex SAS system solutions’ effectiveness (e.g. response times, data processing performance, storage capacity, reports accessibility and interactivity).</P><P>(e) The proposed solution should enable a justifiable growth of the system utilization due to potentially increased volume of data, increased number of users, new areas of system’s application, etc.</P><P>(f) The proposed components’ selection as well as proposed number of licenses shall be briefly justified in the proposal.</P><P>(g) The proposal shall contain a detailed specification of SAS Software and subcomponents including the number of related software licenses which are needed to extend Frontex’ core SAS system by the intended functionality.</P><P>(h) The proposal shall contain both types of prices: First Year Fee (FYF) and Renewal Fee (RF).</P><P>(i) If needed the proposal should contain a price of a relevant installation service.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Qualifications, expertise, suitability and professional competences of Contractor, the clarity and conciseness of the overall technical proposal and understanding of the objectives.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Since the very beginning of Frontex the risk analysis is one of the key operational activity which constitute a basis for other activities. Tasks related to risk analysis, to be performed by Frontex, were defined in the first Frontex Regulation (EC) 2007/2004. In the new Frontex Regulation (EU) 2016/1624 the tasks related to risk analysis are even extended in comparison to the previous state. Frontex organizational structure has been recently changed and Situational Awareness and Monitoring Division has been created in order to fulfill the new requirements.</P><P>The role of SAS Software and its importance for risk analysis process in Frontex</P><P>SAS technology is the tool which supports risk analysis tasks in Frontex. The first implementation of SAS technology took place in 2008. Since 2008 Frontex has invested a significant amount of resources in terms of time, human resources and financial means for:</P><P>— SAS Software licenses and its integration to Frontex architecture,</P><P>— Specific hardware in order to meet the requirements of the SAS Software utilized,</P><P>— Trainings and workshops which were conducted to facilitate Frontex staff to acquire the appropriate knowledge. There is now a substantial body of knowledge established in Frontex based on the SAS technology.</P><P>Nowadays SAS technology is one of the core and critical component of risk analysis process.</P><P>Potential replacement of SAS technology for an equivalent technology would require a strategic decision in order to initiate a process which will last several years and would require significant financial and non-financial investments in order to reach a level of maturity similar to the current one. During this period the solutions based on SAS technology would require at least to be maintained.</P><P>SAS Institute and its market position.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. is the sole manufacturer and publisher of SAS Software. SAS Institute Inc. is the owner of the intellectual property rights in SAS Software. SAS Institute sp. z o.o. a subsidiary of SAS Institute Inc., has the exclusive right to grant licenses to SAS Software for the benefit of entities obliged to use Public Procurement Law in Poland.</P><P>Choice of procurement procedure.</P><P>The procurement procedure for SAS Software licenses will be negotiated procedure without prior publication of a contract notice in accordance with Point 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) of Annex I FR (previously Art. 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) RAP), due to the existence of technical reasons and the need of protection of exclusive rights. Thus the contract can be only awarded to one particular economic operator. Given the fact that SAS Institute is the sole owner of the licences the above mentioned procedure has been chosen.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Framework Contract for the acquisition of SAS software licences</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>General Court</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L - 2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>General Court</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L - 2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>General Court</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L - 2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="ES"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Agencia Europea de la Guardia de Fronteras y Costas (Frontex)</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Contrato marco para la adquisición de licencias de software SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>El objeto del presente contrato es establecer un canal de adquisición en forma de contrato marco que permita la adquisición de licencias de software SAS:</P><P>1) para renovar y mantener el conjunto de licencias de software SAS actualmente en uso en Frontex;</P><P>2) para extender de forma opcional el conjunto de licencias de software SAS actualmente en uso en Frontex mediante la:</P><P>(a) compra de más licencias para productos que están en uso y/o</P><P>(b) compra de licencias para otros productos de software SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLONIA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>El objeto del presente contrato es la provisión de licencias de software SAS bajo el contrato marco.</P><P>Se solicitó al licitador que proporcionara los siguientes servicios y suministros:</P><P>A. Tarifa de renovación (RF) para las licencias del sistema SAS central de Frontex</P><P>(a) La propuesta deberá contener una especificación detallada del software SAS y sus subcomponentes, incluyendo la cantidad de licencias de software relacionadas que forman el sistema SAS central de Frontex.</P><P>(b) La propuesta deberá contener únicamente la Tarifa de Renovación (RF).</P><P>B. Propuesta con un conjunto adicional de licencias de software SAS para complementar el sistema SAS central de Frontex a fin de aumentar su capacidad de procesamiento y/o disponibilidad.</P><P>(a) Se solicita al Licitador que proponga solo las soluciones técnicamente aplicables.</P><P>(b) La propuesta deberá contener una especificación detallada del software SAS y sus subcomponentes, incluyendo la cantidad de licencias de software relacionadas que son necesarias para lograr el aumento planificado de la capacidad de procesamiento y/o disponibilidad.</P><P>(c) Se solicita al licitador que proponga variantes técnicamente aplicables que permitan un aumento de la capacidad de procesamiento y/o disponibilidad, por ejemplo: 10 %, 20 % y 50 %. Las variantes deben estar claramente descritas y marcadas en la propuesta técnica y en la propuesta financiera como B1, B2, etc.</P><P>(d) La propuesta contendrá ambos tipos de precios: Tarifa de primer año (FYF) y tarifa de renovación (RF).</P><P>(e) En caso necesario, la propuesta deberá contener el precio de un servicio de instalación relevante.</P><P>C. Propuesta con conjuntos adicionales de licencias para el software SAS y sus subcomponentes, con el fin de ampliar el sistema SAS central de Frontex mediante la introducción de otros productos de software SAS. Para ampliar el sistema SAS central de Frontex actual mediante módulos de software adicionales y subcomponentes relacionados que permiten una mejor gestión de los datos mediante una herramienta ETL moderna, integrada y de clase empresarial que admita el desarrollo basado en GUI. El licitador debe proponer conjuntos de licencias de software para:</P><P>(i) Integración de datos SAS</P><P>(ii) Calidad de datos SAS</P><P>Los conjuntos deben estar claramente descritos y marcados en la propuesta técnica y en la propuesta financiera como C1 y C2.</P><P>(a) Los conjuntos de licencias de software propuestos deben ser totalmente compatibles con el sistema SAS central de Frontex, es decir, deben ser técnicamente aplicables a este sistema.</P><P>(b) La propuesta debe contener una lista de todos los requisitos/condiciones obligatorias que deben cumplirse para implementar una extensión (por ejemplo, requisitos técnicos mínimos para servidores, etc.).</P><P>(c) La propuesta deberá ser adecuada para el sistema SAS principal de Frontex en términos de su escala y cantidad de datos procesados, y deberá ser apropiada para cumplir con su cometido.</P><P>(d) La implementación, utilización y carga de trabajo diaria esperada de los componentes propuestos no puede generar un impacto negativo en la efectividad de las soluciones del sistema Frontex SAS existentes (por ejemplo, tiempos de respuesta, rendimiento de procesamiento de datos, capacidad de almacenamiento, accesibilidad e interactividad de informes).</P><P>(e) La solución propuesta debe permitir un crecimiento justificable de la utilización del sistema debido a un volumen de datos potencialmente mayor, un mayor número de usuarios, nuevas áreas de aplicación del sistema, etc.</P><P>(f) La selección de los componentes propuestos, así como el número de licencias propuesto, se justificarán brevemente en la propuesta.</P><P>(g) La propuesta deberá contener una especificación detallada del software SAS y los subcomponentes, incluyendo la cantidad de licencias de software relacionadas que son necesarias para extender el sistema SAS central de Frontex por la funcionalidad deseada.</P><P>(h) La propuesta contendrá ambos tipos de precios: Tarifa de primer año (FYF) y tarifa de renovación (RF).</P><P>(i) En caso necesario, la propuesta deberá contener el precio de un servicio de instalación relevante.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Cualificaciones, experiencia, idoneidad y competencias profesionales del contratista, claridad y concisión de la propuesta técnica general y comprensión de los objetivos.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Desde el comienzo de Frontex, el análisis de riesgos es una de las actividades operativas clave que constituyen una base para otras actividades. Las tareas relacionadas con el análisis de riesgos a realizar por parte de Frontex se definieron en el primer Reglamento Frontex (CE) 2007/2004. En el nuevo Reglamento Frontex (UE) 2016/1624, las tareas relacionadas con el análisis de riesgos se amplían incluso en comparación con el estado anterior. La estructura organizativa de Frontex ha sido recientemente modificada y se ha creado la División de Concientización y Monitorización Situacional para cumplir con los nuevos requisitos.</P><P>El papel del software SAS y su importancia para el proceso de análisis de riesgos en Frontex</P><P>La tecnología SAS es la herramienta que sustenta la realización de las tareas de análisis de riesgos en Frontex. La primera implementación de la tecnología SAS tuvo lugar en 2008. Desde 2008, Frontex ha invertido una notable cantidad de recursos en términos de tiempo, recursos humanos y medios financieros para:</P><P>— las licencias de software SAS y su integración en la arquitectura Frontex,</P><P>— el hardware específico para cumplir con los requisitos del software SAS utilizado,</P><P>— la realización de formaciones y talleres llevados a cabo para facilitar que el personal de Frontex adquiera los conocimientos adecuados. Actualmente, existe un acervo notable de conocimiento en Frontex basado en la tecnología SAS.</P><P>Hoy en día, la tecnología SAS es uno de los componentes centrales y críticos del proceso de análisis de riesgos.</P><P>El potencial reemplazo de la tecnología SAS por una tecnología equivalente requeriría una decisión estratégica para iniciar un proceso que duraría varios años y requeriría inversiones financieras y no financieras significativas para alcanzar un nivel de madurez similar al actual. Durante este período, las soluciones basadas en tecnología SAS requerirán un nivel que permita, como mínimo, mantenerlas.</P><P>SAS Institute y su posición en el mercado.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. es el único fabricante y editor único de software SAS. SAS Institute Inc. es el propietario de los derechos de propiedad intelectual de software SAS. SAS Institute sp. zoo., filial de SAS Institute Inc., cuenta con el derecho exclusivo de otorgar licencias de software SAS en beneficio de las entidades obligadas a utilizar la Ley de Contratación Pública en Polonia.</P><P>Elección del procedimiento de contratación.</P><P>El procedimiento de adquisición para las licencias de software SAS se negociará sin la publicación previa de un anuncio de contrato de conformidad con el punto 11, apartado (1), letra (b), inciso (ii), subinciso (iii) del Anexo I FR (anteriormente art. 134 (1) (b) (ii) (iii) de las normas de desarrollo), debido a la existencia de razones técnicas y la necesidad de protección de derechos exclusivos. Por lo tanto, el contrato solo puede adjudicarse a un operador económico en particular. Dado que SAS Institute es el único propietario de las licencias, se ha elegido el procedimiento mencionado anteriormente.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Contrato marco para la adquisición de licencias de software SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunal General</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunal General</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunal General</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="FI"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Euroopan raja- ja merivartiovirasto</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Puitesopimus SAS-ohjelmistolisenssien hankintaa varten</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Tämän sopimuksen kohteena on perustaa puitesopimuksen avulla hankintakanava, joka mahdollistaisi SAS-ohjelmistolisenssien ostamisen:</P><P>1) Frontexin käytössä olevien SAS-ohjelmistolisenssien uusiminen ja voimassa pitäminen,</P><P>2) Frontexin käytössä olevien SAS-ohjelmistolisenssien mahdollinen laajentaminen</P><P>a) ostamalla lisälisenssejä jo käytössä oleville tuotteille ja/tai</P><P>b) ostamalla muiden SAS-ohjelmistotuotteiden lisenssejä.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, PUOLA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Tämän sopimuksen kohteena on puitesopimuksen perusteella ostettujen SAS-ohjelmistolisenssien hankinta.</P><P>Tarjoajalta edellytettiin seuraavia palveluja ja toimituksia:</P><P>A. Frontexin SAS-järjestelmän ydinlisenssien uusimisen kustannus</P><P>a) Ehdotuksen tulee sisältää yksityiskohtainen SAS-ohjelmistojen ja sen eri alikomponenttien erittely mukaan luettuna ne siihen liittyvät ohjelmistolisenssit, jotka muodostavat Frontexin SAS-järjestelmän ytimen.</P><P>b) Ehdotus on ainoastaan uusimisen kustannuksen summa.</P><P>B. SAS-lisäohjelmistolisenssien sellaisia kokonaisuuksia koskeva ehdotus, joilla täydennetään Frontexin SAS-järjestelmän ydintä, jotta voitaisiin lisätä sen käsittelytehoa ja/tai saatavuutta.</P><P>a) Tarjoajalta edellytetään ehdotuksia ainoastaan teknisesti soveltuvista ratkaisuista.</P><P>b) Ehdotuksen tulee sisältää yksityiskohtainen SAS-ohjelmistojen ja sen eri alikomponenttien erittely mukaan luettuna ne siihen liittyvät ohjelmistolisenssit, joita tarvitaan suunnitellun käsittelytehon ja/tai saatavuuden aikaansaamiseksi.</P><P>c) Tarjoajalta edellytetään ehdotuksia muutamista teknisesti soveltuvista muunnelmista, joilla voitaisiin lisätä käsittelytehoa ja/tai saatavuutta esim. 10, 20 tai 50 prosentin verran. Kyseisten muunnelmien tulisi olla selkeästi kuvattuja ja merkittyjä teknisessä ja hintaehdotuksessa (B1, B2 jne.).</P><P>d) Ehdotuksen tulee sisältää kahdentyyppiset hinnat: ensimmäisen vuoden maksu sekä uusimisen kustannus.</P><P>e) Tarvittaessa ehdotuksen tulisi sisältää asiaankuuluvan asennuspalvelun hinta.</P><P>C. SAS-ohjelmiston ja sen alikomponenttien lisälisenssisarjoja sisältävä ehdotus, jolla on tarkoitus laajentaa Frontexin SAS-järjestelmän ydintä lisäämällä siihen muita SAS-ohjelmistotuotteita nykyisen SAS-ydinjärjestelmän laajentamiseksi lisäohjelmistomoduuleilla sekä niihin liittyvillä alikomponenteilla, jotta saavutettaisiin parempi tiedon hallinta integroidun, suurorganisaatioluokan modernin GUI-perusteista kehitystyötä tukevan ETL-työkalun (ETL – extract, transform, and load (eli poimi, muunna ja lataa)) avulla. Tarjoajalta edellytetään ehdotuksia ohjelmistolisenssisarjoiksi seuraavista:</P><P>i) SAS tiedon integraatio sekä</P><P>ii) SAS tiedon laatu.</P><P>Kyseisten sarjaehdotusten tulisi olla selkeästi kuvattuja ja merkittyjä teknisessä ja hintaehdotuksessa (C1, C2 jne.).</P><P>a) Ehdotettujen ohjelmistolisenssisarjojen tulee olla täysin yhteensopivia Frontexin SAS-ydinjärjestelmän kanssa, eli niiden tulee teknisesti sopia tähän järjestelmään,</P><P>b) ehdotuksen tulee sisältää luettelo kaikista pakollisista vaatimuksista/ehdoista, jotka tulee täyttää laajennuksen toteuttamiseksi (esim. palvelinten tekniset minimivaatimukset jne.),</P><P>c) ehdotuksen tulee olla laajuudeltaan ja tietojen käsittelymäärältään riittävä sekä tarkoituksenmukainen Frontexin SAS-ydinjärjestelmän kanssa käytettäväksi,</P><P>d) komponenttien ehdotettu toteutus, käyttöönotto ja odotettu päivittäinen työkuorma ei saa aiheuttaa negatiivisia vaikutuksia olemassa olevien Frontexin SAS-järjestelmäratkaisujen tehokkuuteen (esim. vasteajat, tietojenkäsittelyn tehokkuus, tallennuskapasiteetti, raporttien saatavuus ja vuorovaikutteisuus),</P><P>e) ehdotetun ratkaisun tulisi mahdollistaa perusteltu järjestelmän käytön kasvu, joka voi mahdollisesti johtua lisääntyneestä tiedon ja käyttäjien määristä, uusista järjestelmän soveltamisaloista jne.,</P><P>f) ehdotettu komponenttivalikoima sekä ehdotettu lisenssien määrä tulee lyhyesti perustella ehdotuksessa,</P><P>g) ehdotuksen tulee sisältää yksityiskohtainen SAS-ohjelmistojen ja sen eri alikomponenttien erittely mukaan luettuna ne siihen liittyvät ohjelmistolisenssit, joita tarvitaan Frontexin SAS-järjestelmän ytimen laajentamiseksi aiotuilla toiminnoilla,</P><P>h) ehdotuksen tulee sisältää kahdentyyppiset hinnat: ensimmäisen vuoden maksu sekä uusimisen kustannus.</P><P>i) tarvittaessa ehdotuksen tulisi sisältää asiaankuuluvan asennuspalvelun hinta.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>sopimusosapuolen todistuksilla osoitettu kelpoisuus, asiantuntemus, soveltuvuus ja ammattipätevyys, koko teknisen ehdotuksen selkeys ja tiiviys sekä tavoitteiden ymmärtäminen</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Aivan Frontexin alusta alkaen riskianalyysi on eräs avaintoiminto, joka on muiden toimintojen perustana. Frontexin tehtäväksi annetut riskianalyysiin liittyvät tehtävät määriteltiin ensimmäisessä Frontex-asetuksessa (EY) 2007/2004. Uudessa Frontex-asetuksessa (EY) 2016/1624 riskianalyysiin liittyviä tehtäviä on jopa laajennettu aiempaan verrattuna. Frontexin organisaatiorakennetta on hiljan muutettu ja tilannetietoisuus- ja seurantayksikkö on luotu uusien vaatimusten täyttämiseksi.</P><P>SAS-ohjelmiston rooli ja merkitys Frontexin riskianalyysiprosessille:</P><P>SAS-teknologia on se työkalu, joka tukee Frontexin riskianalyyttisiä tehtäviä. Ensimmäinen SAS-teknologian toteutus tapahtui vuonna 2008. Vuoden 2008 jälkeen Frontex on sijoittanut huomattavan määrän aika-, henkilöstö- ja rahavararesursseja</P><P>— SAS-ohjelmistolisensseihin ja ohjelmiston integrointiin Frontexin arkkitehtuuriin,</P><P>— erityisiin atk-laitteistoihin, joita tarvitaan käytetyn SAS-ohjelmiston vaatimusten täyttämiseksi,</P><P>— koulutuksiin ja työpajoihin, joita on pidetty Frontexin henkilöstön asiaankuuluvien tietojen hankkimisen helpottamiseksi. Tällä hetkellä Frontexissa on huomattava määrä SAS-teknologiaan perustuvaa kertynyttä tietämystä.</P><P>Nyt SAS-teknologia on eräs riskianalyysiprosessin ydin- ja kriittisistä komponenteista.</P><P>SAS-teknologian mahdollinen korvaaminen vastaavalla teknologialla vaatisi strategista päätöstä, jotta voitaisiin käynnistää monivuotinen huomattavia rahallisia ja muita panostuksia vaativa prosessi nykyistä vastaavan kypsyysasteen saavuttamiseksi. Tämän ajanjakson aikana SAS-teknologiaan perustuvia ratkaisuja olisi ainakin ylläpidettävä.</P><P>SAS Institute ja sen markkina-asema:</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. on SAS-ohjelmistojen ainut valmistaja ja julkaisija. SAS Institute Inc.:llä on SAS-ohjelmistojen kaikki immateriaalioikeudet. SAS Institute sp. z o.o.:lla, SAS Institute Inc.:n haaraliikkeellä, on yksinomainen oikeus myöntää SAS-ohjelmistojen lisenssejä niille yksiköille, jotka joutuvat noudattamaan julkisia hankintoja koskevaa Puolan lakia.</P><P>Valittu hankintamenettely:</P><P>SAS-ohjelmistolisenssien hankintamenettelynä käytetään neuvottelumenettelyä ilman aiemman hankintailmoituksen julkaisua noudattaen varainhoitoasetuksen liitteen kohtaa 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) (aiemmin soveltamissääntöjen 134 artiklan kohta (1)(b)(ii)(iii)) teknisistä syistä sekä yksinoikeuksien suojaustarpeen takia.  Näin ollen sopimus voidaan tehdä vain yhden tietyn talouden toimijan kanssa. Yllä mainittu hankintamenettely on valittu, koska SAS Institute on lisenssien ainut omistaja.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Puitesopimus SAS-ohjelmistolisenssien hankintaa varten</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Unionin yleinen tuomioistuin</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Unionin yleinen tuomioistuin</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Unionin yleinen tuomioistuin</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="FR"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Agence européenne de garde-frontières et de garde-côtes</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Contrat-cadre relatif à l'acquisition de licences logicielles SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>L'objet du présent Contrat est d'établir un canal d'acquisition sous la forme d'un Contrat Cadre permettant l'achat de licences logicielles SAS :</P><P>1) afin de renouveler et de maintenir l'ensemble des licences logicielles SAS utilisées par Frontex ;</P><P>2) afin d'étendre facultativement l'ensemble des licences logicielles SAS qui est utilisé dans Frontex par :</P><P>a) Acheter davantage de licences pour des produits en cours d'utilisation et/ou</P><P>(b) Achat de licences pour d'autres produits des logiciels SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLOGNE</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>L'objet du présent Contrat est la fourniture de licences logicielles SAS au titre d’un contrat-cadre.</P><P>Le soumissionnaire a été invité à fournir les services et le matériel suivants :</P><P>A. Redevance de renouvellement (RF) pour les licences SAS du système central de Frontex</P><P>a) La proposition contient une spécification détaillée des logiciels et sous-composants de SAS, y compris le nombre de licences de logiciels connexes qui composent le système SAS central de Frontex.</P><P>b) La proposition ne doit contenir que la taxe de renouvellement (RF).</P><P>B. Proposition contenant un ensemble supplémentaire de licences logicielles SAS pour compléter le système SAS central de Frontex afin d'augmenter sa capacité de traitement et/ou sa disponibilité.</P><P>a) Le soumissionnaire est prié de ne proposer que les solutions techniques réalisables.</P><P>b) La proposition contient une spécification détaillée des logiciels et sous-composants de SAS, y compris le nombre de licences de logiciels connexes qui sont nécessaires pour atteindre l'augmentation prévue de la capacité de traitement et/ou de la disponibilité.</P><P>c) Il est demandé au soumissionnaire de proposer quelques variantes techniquement réalisables permettant d'augmenter la capacité de traitement et/ou la disponibilité, par exemple 10 %, 20 % et 50 %. Les variantes doivent être clairement décrites et marquées dans la proposition technique et dans la proposition financière comme B1, B2, etc.</P><P>d) La proposition doit contenir les deux types de prix : Frais pour la première année (FYF) et frais de renouvellement (RF).</P><P>e) Le cas échéant, la proposition devrait contenir le prix d'un service d'installation pertinent.</P><P>C. Proposition contenant des ensembles supplémentaires de licences pour logiciels SAS et ses sous-composants, afin d'étendre le système SAS central de Frontex en introduisant d'autres produits de logiciels SAS pour étendre le système SAS central actuel de Frontex par des modules logiciels supplémentaires et les sous-composants associés permettant une meilleure gouvernance des données grâce à un outil ETL moderne, intégré, de classe entreprise, qui prend en charge le développement basé sur une interface graphique. Le soumissionnaire est invité à proposer des ensembles de licences logicielles pour les noms de domaine en :</P><P>(i) Intégration de données SAS</P><P>(ii) Qualité des données SAS</P><P>Les variantes doivent être clairement décrites et marquées dans la proposition technique et dans la proposition financière comme C1, C2, etc.</P><P>a) Les ensembles de licences de logiciels proposés doivent être pleinement conformes au système SAS central de Frontex, c'est-à-dire qu'ils doivent être techniquement applicables à ce système.</P><P>b) La proposition doit contenir une liste de toutes les exigences/conditions obligatoires à remplir pour mettre en œuvre une extension (par exemple, exigences techniques minimales pour les serveurs, etc.).</P><P>c) La proposition doit être adaptée au système SAS central de Frontex en termes d'ampleur et de quantité de données traitées, ainsi qu'en fonction de l'objectif visé.</P><P>d) La mise en œuvre, le déploiement et la charge de travail quotidienne prévue des composants proposés ne peuvent avoir d'incidence négative sur l'efficacité des solutions système SAS existantes de Frontex (par exemple, temps de réponse, performances du traitement des données, capacité de stockage, accessibilité et interactivité des rapports).</P><P>e) La solution proposée devrait permettre une croissance justifiable de l'utilisation du système en raison de l'augmentation potentielle du volume de données, du nombre d'utilisateurs, des nouveaux domaines d'application du système, etc.</P><P>f) Le choix des composants proposés ainsi que le nombre proposé de licences doivent être brièvement justifiés dans la proposition.</P><P>g) La proposition contient une spécification détaillée du logiciel et des sous-composants de SAS, y compris le nombre de licences logicielles connexes qui sont nécessaires pour étendre le système SAS central de Frontex de la fonctionnalité prévue.</P><P>h) La proposition doit contenir les deux types de prix : Frais pour la première année (FYF) et frais de renouvellement (RF).</P><P>i) Le cas échéant, la proposition devrait contenir le prix d'un service d'installation pertinent.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Qualifications, expertise, aptitude et compétences professionnelles de l'entrepreneur, clarté et concision de la proposition technique globale et compréhension des objectifs.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Depuis le tout début de Frontex, l'analyse des risques est l'une des principales activités opérationnelles qui servent de base à d'autres activités. Les tâches liées à l'analyse des risques, qui doivent être effectuées par Frontex, ont été définies dans le premier règlement Frontex (EC) 2007/2004. Dans le nouveau règlement Frontex (UE) 2016/1624, les tâches liées à l'analyse des risques sont même étendues par rapport à la situation antérieure. La structure organisationnelle de Frontex a récemment été modifiée et la Division de la Connaissance de la Situation et de la Surveillance a été créée afin de répondre aux nouvelles exigences.</P><P>Le rôle des logiciels SAS et son importance pour le processus d'analyse des risques au sein de Frontex</P><P>La technologie SAS est l'outil qui supporte les tâches d'analyse des risques dans Frontex. La première mise en œuvre de la technologie SAS a eu lieu en 2008. Depuis 2008, Frontex a investi des ressources considérables en termes de temps, de ressources humaines et de moyens financiers :</P><P>- SAS et son intégration à l'architecture Frontex,</P><P>- Du matériel spécifique afin de répondre aux exigences du logiciel SAS utilisé,</P><P>- Des formations et des ateliers ont été organisés pour aider le personnel de Frontex à acquérir les connaissances appropriées. Frontex dispose désormais d'un important corpus de connaissances fondé sur la technologie SAS.</P><P>Aujourd'hui, la technologie SAS est l'un des éléments centraux et critiques du processus d'analyse des risques.</P><P>Le remplacement éventuel de la technologie SAS par une technologie équivalente nécessiterait une décision stratégique afin d'engager un processus qui durera plusieurs années et nécessiterait des investissements financiers et non financiers importants pour atteindre un niveau de maturité similaire à celui qui est actuellement en vigueur. Pendant cette période, les solutions basées sur la technologie SAS devraient au moins être maintenues.</P><P>SAS Institute et sa position sur le marché.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. est le seul fabricant et éditeur de SAS Software. SAS Institute Inc. est titulaire des droits de propriété intellectuelle de SAS Software. SAS Institute sp. z o.o., filiale de SAS Institute Inc. a le droit exclusif d'accorder des licences à SAS Software au bénéfice des entités tenues d'utiliser le droit des marchés publics en Pologne.</P><P>Choix de la procédure de passation de marché.</P><P>La procédure de passation de marché pour les licences de SAS Software sera une procédure négociée sans publication préalable d'un avis de marché conformément à l'annexe I, point 11.1 b) ii) iii), du RF (ancien art. 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) RAP), en raison de l'existence de raisons techniques et de la nécessité de protéger les droits exclusifs. Le marché ne peut donc être attribué qu'à un seul opérateur économique. Étant donné que SAS Institute est le seul propriétaire des licences, la procédure susmentionnée a été choisie.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Contrat-cadre relatif à l'acquisition de licences logicielles SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunal</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunal</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunal</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="EL"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Ευρωπαϊκός Οργανισμός Συνοριοφυλακής και Ακτοφυλακής</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Σύμβαση-πλαίσιο για την αγορά αδειών λογισμικού SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Το αντικείμενο της παρούσας σύμβασης είναι να δημιουργήσει έναν δίαυλο αγοράς υπό μορφή σύμβασης-πλαισίου, που θα επιτρέπει την αγορά αδειών λογισμικού SAS:</P><P>1) προκειμένου να ανανεωθεί και να διατηρηθεί το σύνολο των αδειών λογισμικού SAS που χρησιμοποιείται από τον Frontex,</P><P>2) προκειμένου να επεκταθεί προαιρετικά το σύνολο των αδειών λογισμικού SAS που χρησιμοποιείται από τον Frontex με:</P><P>α) αγορά περισσότερων αδειών για τα προϊόντα που χρησιμοποιούνται ή/και</P><P>β) αγορά αδειών για άλλα προϊόντα λογισμικού της SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, Πολωνία</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Το αντικείμενο της παρούσας σύμβασης είναι η παροχή αδειών λογισμικού SAS στο πλαίσιο της σύμβασης-πλαισίου.</P><P>Ο υποψήφιος κλήθηκε να παράσχει τις ακόλουθες υπηρεσίες και προμήθειες:</P><P>Α. Τέλος ανανέωσης (TA) για τις βασικές άδειες του συστήματος SAS του Frontex</P><P>α) Η πρόταση πρέπει να περιλαμβάνει λεπτομερή περιγραφή του λογισμικού και των υποσυστημάτων του SAS, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του αριθμού των σχετικών αδειών λογισμικού που συνθέτουν το βασικό σύστημα SAS του Frontex.</P><P>β) Η πρόταση πρέπει να περιλαμβάνει μόνο Τέλη Ανανέωσης (ΤΑ).</P><P>Β. Πρόταση που περιλαμβάνει πρόσθετες άδειες λογισμικού SAS για τη συμπλήρωση του βασικού συστήματος SAS του Frontex, προκειμένου να αυξηθεί η ικανότητα επεξεργασίας ή/και η διαθεσιμότητά του.</P><P>α) Ο υποψήφιος καλείται να προτείνει μόνο τεχνικά εφαρμόσιμες λύσεις.</P><P>β) Η πρόταση πρέπει να περιλαμβάνει λεπτομερή περιγραφή του λογισμικού και των υποσυστημάτων του SAS, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του αριθμού των σχετικών αδειών λογισμικού που απαιτούνται για την επίτευξη της σχεδιαζόμενης αύξησης της ικανότητας επεξεργασίας ή/και της διαθεσιμότητας.</P><P>γ) Ο υποψήφιος καλείται να προτείνει μερικές τεχνικά εφαρμόσιμες παραλλαγές που θα επιτρέψουν την αύξηση της δυναμικότητας επεξεργασίας ή/και της διαθεσιμότητας, π.χ .: 10 %, 20 % και 50 %. Οι παραλλαγές πρέπει να περιγράφονται με σαφήνεια και να σημειώνονται στην τεχνική πρόταση και στην οικονομική πρόταση ως B1, B2, κ.λπ.</P><P>δ) Η πρόταση περιλαμβάνει και τους δύο τύπους τιμών: Τέλος Πρώτου Έτους (ΦΠΕ) και Τέλος Ανανέωσης (ΤΑ).</P><P>ε) Εάν είναι απαραίτητο, η πρόταση θα πρέπει να περιλαμβάνει τιμή σχετικής υπηρεσίας εγκατάστασης.</P><P>Γ. Η πρόταση περιλαμβάνει πρόσθετα σύνολα αδειών χρήσης του λογισμικού SAS και των υποσυστημάτων του, προκειμένου να επεκταθεί το βασικό σύστημα SAS του Frontex με την εισαγωγή άλλων προϊόντων λογισμικού SAS. Να επεκταθεί το βασικό σύστημα SAS του Frontex με πρόσθετες λειτουργικές μονάδες λογισμικού και τις σχετικές υποσυνιστώσες, με ολοκληρωμένο, επιχειρησιακής κλάσης, σύγχρονο εργαλείο ETL που να υποστηρίζει ανάπτυξη βασισμένη σε GUI. Ο διαγωνιζόμενος καλείται να προτείνει σύνολα αδειών λογισμικού για:</P><P>(i) Ενσωμάτωση δεδομένων SAS</P><P>(ii) Ποιότητα δεδομένων SAS</P><P>Τα σύνολα πρέπει να περιγράφονται με σαφήνεια και να σημειώνονται στην τεχνική πρόταση και στην οικονομική πρόταση ως C1, C2, κ.λπ.</P><P>α) Τα προτεινόμενα σύνολα αδειών λογισμικού πρέπει να είναι πλήρως συμβατά με το βασικό σύστημα SAS του Frontex, δηλαδή πρέπει να είναι τεχνικά εφαρμόσιμα σε αυτό το σύστημα.</P><P>β) Η πρόταση πρέπει να περιλαμβάνει κατάλογο όλων των υποχρεωτικών απαιτήσεων/προϋποθέσεων που πρέπει να πληρούνται για την υλοποίηση μιας επέκτασης (π.χ. ελάχιστες τεχνικές απαιτήσεις για διακομιστές κ.λπ.).</P><P>γ) Η πρόταση πρέπει να είναι επαρκής για το βασικό σύστημα SAS του Frontex όσον αφορά την κλίμακα και τις ποσότητες των δεδομένων που έχουν υποστεί επεξεργασία καθώς και για να ανταποκρίνεται στο σκοπό.</P><P>δ) Η υλοποίηση, η ανάπτυξη και ο αναμενόμενος καθημερινός φόρτος εργασίας των προτεινόμενων στοιχείων, δεν μπορούν να επηρεάσουν αρνητικά την αποτελεσματικότητα των υφιστάμενων λύσεων του συστήματος Frontex SAS (π.χ. χρόνοι απόκρισης, απόδοση επεξεργασίας δεδομένων, χωρητικότητα αποθήκευσης, προσβασιμότητα αναφορών και διαδραστικότητα).</P><P>ε) Η προτεινόμενη λύση θα επιτρέψει μια δικαιολογημένη αύξηση της χρήσης του συστήματος λόγω του δυνητικά αυξημένου όγκου δεδομένων, του αυξημένου αριθμού χρηστών, νέων τομέων εφαρμογής του συστήματος κλπ.</P><P>στ) Η επιλογή των προτεινόμενων κατασκευαστικών στοιχείων, καθώς και ο προτεινόμενος αριθμός αδειών αιτιολογείται εν συντομία στην πρόταση.</P><P>ζ) Η πρόταση πρέπει να περιλαμβάνει λεπτομερή περιγραφή του λογισμικού και των υποσυστημάτων του SAS, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του αριθμού των σχετικών αδειών λογισμικού που απαιτούνται για την επέκταση του βασικού συστήματος SAS του Frontex με την προβλεπόμενη λειτουργικότητα.</P><P>η) Η πρόταση περιλαμβάνει και τους δύο τύπους τιμών: Τέλος Πρώτου Έτους (ΦΠΕ) και Τέλος Ανανέωσης (ΤΑ).</P><P>i) Εάν είναι απαραίτητο, η πρόταση πρέπει να περιλαμβάνει τιμή σχετικής υπηρεσίας εγκατάστασης.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Προσόντα, εμπειρογνωμοσύνη, καταλληλότητα και επαγγελματικές ικανότητες του Αναδόχου, σαφήνεια και συνοπτικότητα της συνολικής τεχνικής πρότασης και κατανόηση των στόχων.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Από την αρχή του Frontex, η ανάλυση κινδύνων αποτελεί μία από τις βασικές λειτουργικές δραστηριότητες, που αποτελούν τη βάση για άλλες δραστηριότητες. Τα καθήκοντα σχετικά με την ανάλυση κινδύνου, που θα εκτελεστούν από τον Frontex, καθορίστηκαν στον πρώτο Κανονισμό (ΕΚ) 2007/2004 του Frontex. Στο νέο Κανονισμό Frontex (ΕΕ) 2016/1624, τα καθήκοντα που σχετίζονται με την ανάλυση κινδύνου έχουν επεκταθεί ακόμα και σε σύγκριση με το προηγούμενο στάδιο. Η οργανωτική δομή του Frontex άλλαξε πρόσφατα και δημιουργήθηκε για να ανταποκριθεί στις νέες απαιτήσεις.</P><P>Ο ρόλος του λογισμικού SAS και η σημασία του για τη διαδικασία ανάλυσης κινδύνου στον Frontex</P><P>Η τεχνολογία SAS είναι το εργαλείο που υποστηρίζει τα καθήκοντα ανάλυσης κινδύνου στον Frontex. Η πρώτη υλοποίηση της τεχνολογίας SAS πραγματοποιήθηκε το 2008. Από το 2008, ο Frontex έχει επενδύσει σημαντικό αριθμό πόρων από άποψη χρόνου, ανθρώπινων πόρων και οικονομικών μέσων για:</P><P>— Άδειες λογισμικού SAS και ενσωμάτωσή της στην αρχιτεκτονική του Frontex,</P><P>— Ειδικό υλικό για την ικανοποίηση των απαιτήσεων του λογισμικού SAS που χρησιμοποιείται,</P><P>— Κατάρτιση και εργαστήρια που διεξήχθησαν για να διευκολύνουν το προσωπικό του Frontex να αποκτήσει τις κατάλληλες γνώσεις. Υπάρχει σήμερα ένα σημαντικό σύνολο γνώσεων που έχει καθιερωθεί στον Frontex με βάση την τεχνολογία SAS.</P><P>Σήμερα η τεχνολογία SAS είναι ένα από τα βασικά και κρίσιμα συστατικά της διαδικασίας ανάλυσης κινδύνου.</P><P>Η πιθανή αντικατάσταση της τεχνολογίας SAS με μια ισοδύναμη τεχνολογία θα απαιτούσε μια στρατηγική απόφαση, προκειμένου να ξεκινήσει μια διαδικασία η οποία θα διαρκέσει αρκετά χρόνια και θα απαιτούσε σημαντικές χρηματοδοτικές και μη χρηματοοικονομικές επενδύσεις, προκειμένου να φθάσει σε επίπεδο ωριμότητας παρόμοιο με το σημερινό. Κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της περιόδου, οι λύσεις που βασίζονται στην τεχνολογία SAS θα πρέπει, τουλάχιστον, να διατηρηθούν.</P><P>SAS Institute και η θέση του στην αγορά.</P><P>Το SAS Institute Inc. είναι ο μόνος κατασκευαστής και εκδότης του λογισμικού της SAS. Το SAS Institute Inc. είναι ο κάτοχος των δικαιωμάτων πνευματικής ιδιοκτησίας του Λογισμικού SAS. Το SAS Institute sp.z.o.o. θυγατρική του SAS Institute Inc., έχει το αποκλειστικό δικαίωμα να χορηγεί άδειες για το λογισμικό SAS, προς όφελος φορέων που υποχρεούνται να χρησιμοποιούν τον νόμο περί Δημοσίων Συμβάσεων στην Πολωνία.</P><P>Επιλογή της διαδικασίας σύναψης συμβάσεων.</P><P>Η διαδικασία σύναψης συμβάσεων για τις άδειες λογισμικού SAS θα είναι διαδικασία διαπραγμάτευσης χωρίς προηγούμενη δημοσίευση προκήρυξης διαγωνισμού, σύμφωνα με το σημείο 11(1)(β)(ii)(iii) του παραρτήματος I του κανονισμού ΕΚ (προηγούμενο Άρθρο 134(1)(β)(ii)(iii) RAP), λόγω της ύπαρξης τεχνικών λόγων και της ανάγκης προστασίας αποκλειστικών δικαιωμάτων. Συνεπώς, η σύμβαση μπορεί να ανατεθεί μόνο σε έναν συγκεκριμένο οικονομικό φορέα. Δεδομένου ότι το SAS Institute είναι ο μοναδικός κάτοχος των αδειών, έχει επιλεγεί η παραπάνω διαδικασία.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Σύμβαση-πλαίσιο για την αγορά αδειών λογισμικού SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Γενικό Δικαστήριο</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Γενικό Δικαστήριο</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Γενικό Δικαστήριο</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="IT"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Agenzia europea della guardia di frontiera e costiera</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Contratto quadro per l'acquisizione di licenze software SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>L'oggetto del presente appalto è stabilire un canale di acquisizione sotto forma di contratto quadro che consenta l'acquisto di licenze software SAS:</P><P>1) al fine di rinnovare e mantenere la serie di licenze software SAS in uso presso Frontex;</P><P>2) al fine di estendere facoltativamente la serie di licenze software SAS in uso presso Frontex tramite:</P><P>(a) l'acquisto di più licenze per prodotti in uso e/o</P><P>(b) l'acquisto di licenze per altri prodotti software SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLONIA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>L'oggetto del presente appalto è la fornitura di licenze software SAS nell'ambito di un contratto quadro.</P><P>L'offerente è stato invitato a fornire i seguenti servizi e forniture:</P><P>A. Tassa di rinnovo per le licenze di sistema SAS core di Frontex</P><P>(a) La proposta deve contenere una specifica dettagliata del software SAS e dei sottocomponenti, compreso il numero di licenze software correlate che costituiscono il sistema SAS core di Frontex.</P><P>(b) La proposta deve contenere solo la tassa di rinnovo.</P><P>B. Proposta contenente una serie aggiuntiva di licenze software SAS per integrare il sistema SAS core di Frontex, al fine di aumentare la sua capacità e/o disponibilità di elaborazione.</P><P>(a) L'offerente è invitato a proporre solo le soluzioni tecnicamente applicabili.</P><P>(b) La proposta deve contenere una specifica dettagliata del software SAS e dei sottocomponenti, compreso il numero di licenze software correlate necessarie per raggiungere l'aumento pianificato della capacità e/o disponibilità di elaborazione.</P><P>(c) L'offerente è invitato a proporre alcune varianti tecnicamente applicabili che consentano un aumento della capacità e/o disponibilità di elaborazione, ad es .: 10 %, 20 % e 50 %. Le varianti devono essere chiaramente descritte e contrassegnate nella proposta tecnica e nella proposta finanziaria come B1, B2, ecc.</P><P>(d) La proposta deve contenere entrambi i tipi di prezzi: tassa del primo anno e tassa di rinnovo.</P><P>(e) Se necessario, la proposta deve contenere il prezzo del servizio di installazione pertinente.</P><P>C. Proposta contenente serie aggiuntive di licenze per software SAS e relativi sottocomponenti, al fine di estendere il sistema SAS core di Frontex introducendo altri prodotti software SAS per estendere l'attuale sistema SAS core di Frontex mediante moduli software aggiuntivi e relativi sottocomponenti, che consentono una migliore governance dei dati da parte dello strumento ETL integrato, di classe aziendale e moderno, che supporta lo sviluppo basato su GUI. L'offerente è invitato a proporre serie di licenze software per:</P><P>(i) l'integrazione dei dati SAS</P><P>(ii) la qualità dei dati SAS</P><P>Le serie devono essere chiaramente descritte e contrassegnate nella proposta tecnica e nella proposta finanziaria come C1 e C2.</P><P>(a) Le serie di licenze software proposte devono essere pienamente conformi al sistema SAS core di Frontex, ossia devono essere tecnicamente applicabili a tale sistema.</P><P>(b) La proposta deve contenere un elenco di tutte le condizioni e i requisiti obbligatori da soddisfare al fine di implementare un'estensione (ad esempio requisiti tecnici minimi per i server, ecc.).</P><P>(c) La proposta deve essere adeguata al sistema SAS core di Frontex, in termini di dimensioni e quantità di dati elaborati, e adatta allo scopo.</P><P>(d) L'implementazione, la distribuzione e il carico di lavoro giornaliero previsto dei componenti proposti non possono avere un impatto negativo sull'efficacia delle soluzioni del sistema SAS di Frontex esistente (ad esempio tempi di risposta, prestazioni di elaborazione dei dati, capacità di archiviazione, accessibilità dei rapporti e interattività).</P><P>(e) La soluzione proposta dovrà consentire una crescita giustificabile dell'utilizzo del sistema a causa dell'aumento del volume di dati, dell'aumento del numero di utenti, di nuove aree di applicazione del sistema, ecc.</P><P>(f) La selezione di componenti proposta e il numero proposto di licenze devono essere brevemente motivati nella proposta.</P><P>(g) La proposta deve contenere una specifica dettagliata del software SAS e dei sottocomponenti, compreso il numero di licenze software correlate necessarie per estendere il sistema SAS core di Frontex con la funzionalità prevista.</P><P>(h) La proposta deve contenere entrambi i tipi di prezzi: tassa del primo anno e tassa di rinnovo.</P><P>(i) Se necessario, la proposta deve contenere il prezzo del servizio di installazione pertinente.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>qualifiche, esperienze, idoneità e competenze professionali del contraente, chiarezza e concisione della proposta tecnica complessiva e comprensione degli obiettivi.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Sin dall'inizio di Frontex, l'analisi dei rischi è una delle attività operative chiave che costituiscono la base per altre attività. Le attività relative all'analisi dei rischi svolte da Frontex sono state definite nel primo regolamento Frontex (CE) 2007/2004. Nel nuovo regolamento Frontex (UE) 2016/1624, le attività relative all'analisi dei rischi sono state ulteriormente estese rispetto allo stato precedente. La struttura organizzativa di Frontex è stata recentemente modificata ed è stata creata la divisione per la consapevolezza situazionale e il monitoraggio per soddisfare i nuovi requisiti.</P><P>Il ruolo del software SAS e la sua importanza per il processo di analisi dei rischi in Frontex</P><P>La tecnologia SAS è lo strumento che supporta le attività di analisi dei rischi in Frontex. La prima implementazione della tecnologia SAS è avvenuta nel 2008. Dal 2008, Frontex ha investito una quantità significativa di risorse in termini di tempo, risorse umane e mezzi finanziari per:</P><P>— licenze software SAS e sua integrazione nell'architettura di Frontex,</P><P>— hardware specifico per soddisfare i requisiti del software SAS utilizzato,</P><P>— formazioni e workshop che sono stati condotti per consentire al personale di Frontex di acquisire le conoscenze appropriate. Ora esiste una notevole quantità di conoscenze consolidate in Frontex basate sulla tecnologia SAS.</P><P>Attualmente, la tecnologia SAS è uno dei componenti chiave e fondamentali del processo di analisi dei rischi.</P><P>La potenziale sostituzione della tecnologia SAS con una tecnologia equivalente richiederebbe una decisione strategica per avviare un processo che durerebbe diversi anni e richiederebbe investimenti finanziari e non finanziari significativi per raggiungere un livello di maturità simile a quello attuale. Durante tale periodo, le soluzioni basate sulla tecnologia SAS richiederebbero almeno di essere mantenute.</P><P>SAS Institute e la sua posizione sul mercato.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. è l'unico produttore ed editore del software SAS. SAS Institute Inc. è il proprietario dei diritti di proprietà intellettuale del software SAS. SAS Institute sp. z o.o., una filiale di SAS Institute Inc., ha il diritto esclusivo di concedere licenze del software SAS a beneficio di entità obbligate a rispettare la legge sugli appalti pubblici in Polonia.</P><P>Scelta della procedura di appalto.</P><P>La procedura di appalto per le licenze software SAS sarà negoziata senza previa pubblicazione di un bando di gara, in conformità al paragrafo 11, comma 1, lettera b), punti (ii) e (iii) dell'allegato I al regolamento finanziario [ex art. 134, paragrafo 1, lettera b), punti (ii) e (iii) delle modalità di applicazione], a causa dell'esistenza di motivi tecnici e della necessità di tutela dei diritti esclusivi. Il contratto, quindi, può essere aggiudicato solo a un particolare operatore economico. Dato che SAS Institute è l'unico proprietario delle licenze, è stata scelta la procedura sopra indicata.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Contratto quadro per l'acquisizione di licenze software SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunale</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunale</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunale</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="NL"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Europees grens- en kustwachtagentschap</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Raamovereenkomst voor de verwerving van SAS-softwarelicenties</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Het onderwerp van de opdracht is het opzetten van een acquisitiekanaal in de vorm van een raamovereenkomst dat de aankoop van SAS-softwarelicenties mogelijk maakt:</P><P>1) Om de SAS-softwarelicenties die in gebruik zijn bij Frontex te vernieuwen en te onderhouden;</P><P>2) Om de reeks SAS-softwarelicenties die door Frontex worden gebruikt, optioneel uit te breiden:</P><P>a) meer licenties kopen voor producten die in gebruik zijn, en/of;</P><P>b) licenties kopen voor andere SAS-softwareproducten.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLEN</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Het onderwerp van de opdracht is het verstrekken van SAS-softwarelicenties in het kader van een raamovereenkomst.</P><P>De inschrijver werd verzocht de volgende diensten en leveringen te verrichten:</P><P>A. Verlengingstarief voor de belangrijkste SAS-systeemlicenties van Frontex</P><P>a) Het voorstel bevat een gedetailleerde specificatie van de SAS-software en -subcomponenten, met inbegrip van het aantal bijbehorende softwarelicenties waaruit het belangrijkste SAS-systeem van Frontex bestaat.</P><P>b) Het voorstel bevat alleen een verlengingstarief</P><P>B. Voorstel met een aanvullende reeks SAS-softwarelicenties ter aanvulling van het belangrijkste SAS-systeem van Frontex om de verwerkingscapaciteit en/of beschikbaarheid ervan te vergroten.</P><P>a) De inschrijver wordt verzocht om alleen de technisch toepasbare oplossingen voor te stellen.</P><P>b) Het voorstel bevat een gedetailleerde specificatie van de SAS-software en subcomponenten, met inbegrip van het aantal bijbehorende softwarelicenties die nodig zijn om de geplande verhoging van de verwerkingscapaciteit en/of beschikbaarheid te realiseren.</P><P>c) De inschrijver wordt verzocht een aantal technisch toepasbare varianten voor te stellen die een verhoging van de verwerkingscapaciteit en/of beschikbaarheid mogelijk maken met bijvoorbeeld: 10 %, 20 % en 50 %. De varianten moeten in het technisch voorstel en in het financieel voorstel duidelijk worden beschreven en gemarkeerd als B1, B2, enz.</P><P>d) Het voorstel bevat beide soorten prijzen: tarief in het eerste jaar en verlengingstarief.</P><P>e) Indien nodig moet het voorstel een prijs van een relevante installatiedienst bevatten.</P><P>C. Voorstel met aanvullende reeksen licenties voor SAS-software en de subcomponenten daarvan, om het kernsysteem van Frontex uit te breiden met andere SAS-softwareproducten en om het huidige kernsysteem van Frontex uit te breiden met aanvullende softwaremodules en de bijbehorende subcomponenten die een beter gegevensbeheer mogelijk maken door middel van geïntegreerde, enterprise-klasse, moderne ETL-tool die op GUI gebaseerde ontwikkeling ondersteunt. De inschrijver wordt verzocht een reeks softwarelicenties voor te stellen voor:</P><P>i) SAS-gegevensintegratie</P><P>ii) SAS-gegevenskwaliteit</P><P>De reeksen moeten in het technisch voorstel en in het financieel voorstel duidelijk worden beschreven en gemarkeerd als C1, C2, enz.</P><P>a) De voorgestelde reeksen softwarelicenties moeten volledig in overeenstemming zijn met het belangrijkste SAS-systeem van Frontex, d.w.z. technisch toepasbaar zijn op dit systeem.</P><P>b) Het voorstel moet een lijst bevatten van alle verplichte eisen/voorwaarden waaraan moet worden voldaan om een uitbreiding uit te voeren (bv. technische minimumeisen voor servers, enz.).</P><P>c) Het voorstel moet aansluiten bij het centrale SAS-systeem van Frontex met betrekking tot de omvang en de hoeveelheid verwerkte gegevens, alsmede de mate van geschiktheid voor het beoogde doel.</P><P>d) De tenuitvoerlegging, invoering en verwachte dagelijkse werklast van de voorgestelde componenten mogen geen negatieve gevolgen hebben voor de doeltreffendheid van de bestaande Frontex SAS-systeemoplossingen (bijv. responstijden, gegevensverwerkingscapaciteit, opslagcapaciteit, toegankelijkheid en interactiviteit van de verslagen).</P><P>e) De voorgestelde oplossing moet een gerechtvaardigde groei van het gebruik van het systeem mogelijk maken als gevolg van een potentieel verhoogd gegevensvolume, een groter aantal gebruikers, nieuwe toepassingsgebieden van het systeem, enz.</P><P>f) De selectie van de voorgestelde componenten en het voorgestelde aantal licenties worden in het voorstel kort gemotiveerd.</P><P>g) Het voorstel bevat een gedetailleerde specificatie van de SAS-software en -subcomponenten, met inbegrip van het aantal bijbehorende softwarelicenties die nodig zijn om het belangrijkste SAS-systeem van Frontex uit te breiden met de beoogde functionaliteit.</P><P>h) Het voorstel bevat beide soorten prijzen: tarief in het eerste jaar en verlengingstarief.</P><P>i) Indien nodig moet het voorstel een prijs van een relevante installatiedienst bevatten.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Kwalificaties, deskundigheid, geschiktheid en professionele competenties van de contractant, de duidelijkheid en beknoptheid van het algemene technische voorstel en het begrip van de doelstellingen.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Van meet af aan is de risicoanalyse voor Frontex een van de belangrijkste operationele activiteiten die de basis vormen voor andere activiteiten. De taken in verband met risicoanalyse, uit te voeren door Frontex, werden gedefinieerd in de eerste Frontex-verordening (EG) 2007/2004. In de nieuwe Frontex-verordening (EU) 2016/1624 zijn de taken in verband met risicoanalyse zelfs uitgebreid in vergelijking met de vorige staat. De organisatiestructuur van Frontex is onlangs gewijzigd en de afdeling „Situational Awareness and Monitoring“ is opgericht om aan de nieuwe eisen te voldoen.</P><P>De rol van SAS-software en het belang ervan voor het risicoanalyseproces in Frontex.</P><P>SAS-technologie is het instrument dat de risicoanalysetaken in Frontex ondersteunt. De eerste invoering van SAS-technologie vond plaats in 2008. Sinds 2008 heeft Frontex een aanzienlijke hoeveelheid middelen geïnvesteerd wat betreft tijd, personele middelen en financiële middelen:</P><P>— SAS-softwarelicenties en de integratie ervan in de architectuur van Frontex,</P><P>— Specifieke hardware om te voldoen aan de eisen van de gebruikte SAS-software,</P><P>— Opleidingen en workshops die werden georganiseerd om het Frontex-personeel te voorzien van de juiste kennis. Er is nu een aanzienlijke hoeveelheid kennis in Frontex gevestigd op basis van de SAS-technologie.</P><P>Tegenwoordig is de SAS-technologie een van de belangrijkste en kritische componenten van het risicoanalyseproces.</P><P>Een mogelijke vervanging van SAS-technologie door een gelijkwaardige technologie zou een strategische beslissing vereisen om een proces op gang te brengen dat meerdere jaren zal duren en aanzienlijke financiële en niet-financiële investeringen zou vereisen om een niveau van maturiteit te bereiken dat vergelijkbaar is met het huidige niveau. Gedurende deze periode zouden de oplossingen op basis van SAS-technologie ten minste moeten worden gehandhaafd.</P><P>SAS Institute en haar marktpositie.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. is de enige fabrikant en uitgever van SAS-software. SAS Institute Inc. is de eigenaar van de intellectuele eigendomsrechten op SAS-software. SAS Institute sp. z o.o., een dochteronderneming van SAS Institute Inc., heeft het exclusieve recht om licenties te verlenen aan SAS-software ten behoeve van entiteiten die verplicht zijn om de wetgeving inzake overheidsopdrachten in Polen te gebruiken.</P><P>Keuze van aanbestedingsprocedure:</P><P>De aanbestedingsprocedure voor SAS-softwarelicenties is een onderhandelingsprocedure zonder voorafgaande bekendmaking van een aankondiging van opdracht overeenkomstig punt 11, lid 1, onder b), ii), iii), van bijlage I van het Financieel Reglement (voorheen art. 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) van de uitvoeringsvoorschriften, wegens het bestaan van technische redenen en de noodzaak van bescherming van exclusieve rechten. De opdracht kan dus slechts aan één bepaalde ondernemer worden gegund. Gezien het feit dat SAS Institute de enige eigenaar van de licenties is, is voor bovengenoemde procedure gekozen.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Raamovereenkomst voor de verwerving van SAS-softwarelicenties</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Gerecht</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Gerecht</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Gerecht</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="PT"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Agência Europeia da Guarda de Fronteiras e Costeira</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Contrato-quadro para a aquisição de licenças de software SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>O objeto deste contrato é estabelecer um canal de aquisição na forma de um contrato-quadro que permita a aquisição de licenças de software SAS:</P><P>1) para renovar e manter o conjunto de licenças de software SAS que está em uso na Frontex;</P><P>2) para, de forma opcional, ampliar o conjunto de licenças de software SAS que está em uso na Frontex ao:</P><P>(a) comprar mais licenças para produtos em uso e/ou</P><P>(b) comprar licenças para outros produtos de software SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLÓNIA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>O objeto do presente contrato é o fornecimento de licenças de software SAS no âmbito do contrato-quadro.</P><P>O proponente foi solicitado a prestar os seguintes serviços e fornecimentos:</P><P>A. Taxa de renovação das licenças do sistema SAS principal da Frontex</P><P>(a) A proposta deve conter uma especificação detalhada do software SAS e subcomponentes, incluindo o número de licenças de software relacionadas que compõem o sistema SAS principal da Frontex.</P><P>(b) A proposta deve conter apenas a taxa de renovação.</P><P>B. Proposta que contém conjuntos adicionais de licenças de software SAS para complementar o sistema SAS principal da Frontex, a fim de aumentar a sua capacidade de processamento e/ou disponibilidade.</P><P>(a) Solicita-se ao proponente que proponha apenas as soluções tecnicamente aplicáveis.</P><P>(b) A proposta deve conter uma especificação detalhada do software SAS e subcomponentes, incluindo o número de licenças de software que são necessárias para alcançar o aumento planeado da capacidade de processamento e/ou disponibilidade.</P><P>(c) Solicita-se ao proponente que proponha algumas variantes tecnicamente aplicáveis que permitam um aumento da capacidade de processamento e/ou disponibilidade, por exemplo: 10%, 20% e 50%. As variantes devem ser claramente descritas e marcadas na proposta técnica e na proposta financeira como B1, B2, etc.</P><P>(d) A proposta deve conter os dois tipos de preços: Taxa do primeiro ano e taxa de renovação.</P><P>(e) Se necessário, a proposta deve conter o preço de um serviço de instalação relevante.</P><P>C. Proposta que contém conjuntos adicionais de licenças de software SAS e os seus subcomponentes, para ampliar o sistema SAS central da Frontex introduzindo outros produtos de software SAS, para ampliar o atual sistema SAS da Frontex através de módulos de software adicionais e subcomponentes relacionados, permitindo uma melhor governação de dados através da ferramenta ETL, moderna, integrada e de classe empresarial que suporta o desenvolvimento baseado em GUI. Solicita-se ao proponente que proponha conjuntos de licenças de software para:</P><P>(i) integração de dados SAS</P><P>(ii) qualidade de dados SAS</P><P>Os conjuntos devem ser claramente descritos e marcados na proposta técnica e na proposta financeira como C1 e C2.</P><P>(a) Os conjuntos de licenças de software propostos devem ser totalmente compatíveis com o sistema SAS central da Frontex, ou seja, devem ser tecnicamente aplicáveis a este sistema.</P><P>(b) A proposta deve conter uma lista de todos os requisitos/condições obrigatórios a serem cumpridos para implementar uma extensão (por exemplo, requisitos técnicos mínimos para servidores, etc.).</P><P>(c) A proposta deve ser adequada ao sistema SAS central da Frontex, em termos da sua escala e quantidade de dados processados, bem como para se adequar à finalidade.</P><P>(d) A implementação, a implantação e a carga de trabalho diária prevista dos componentes propostos não podem introduzir um impacto negativo na eficácia das soluções existentes do sistema SAS da Frontex (por exemplo, tempos de resposta, desempenho de processamento de dados, capacidade de armazenamento, acessibilidade de relatórios e interatividade).</P><P>(e) A solução proposta deve permitir um crescimento justificável da utilização do sistema devido ao volume potencialmente aumentado de dados, aumento do número de utilizadores, novas áreas de aplicação do sistema, etc.</P><P>(f) A seleção dos componentes propostos, bem como o número de licenças proposto, devem ser sucintamente justificados na proposta.</P><P>(g) A proposta deve conter uma especificação detalhada do software SAS e subcomponentes, incluindo o número de licenças de software relacionadas que são necessárias para a extensão do sistema SAS principal da Frontex pela funcionalidade pretendida.</P><P>(h) A proposta deve conter os dois tipos de preços: Taxa do primeiro ano e taxa de renovação.</P><P>(i) Se necessário, a proposta deve conter o preço de um serviço de instalação relevante.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Qualificações, especialização, adequação e competências profissionais do contratante, a clareza e concisão da proposta técnica global e compreensão dos objetivos.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Desde o início da Frontex, a análise de risco é uma das principais atividades operacionais que constituem uma base para outras atividades. As tarefas relacionadas com a análise de risco, a serem realizadas pela Frontex, foram definidas no primeiro Regulamento Frontex (CE) 2007/2004. No novo Regulamento Frontex (UE) 2016/1624, as tarefas relacionadas com a análise de risco estão alargadas em comparação com a situação anterior. A estrutura organizacional da Frontex foi alterada recentemente e foi criada a divisão de monitorização e conhecimento da situação para atender aos novos requisitos.</P><P>O papel do software SAS e a sua importância para o processo de análise de risco na Frontex</P><P>A tecnologia SAS é a ferramenta que suporta tarefas de análise de risco na Frontex. A primeira implementação da tecnologia SAS ocorreu em 2008. Desde 2008, a Frontex tem investido uma quantidade significativa de recursos em termos de tempo, recursos humanos e meios financeiros para:</P><P>— licenças de software SAS e a sua integração na arquitetura Frontex,</P><P>— hardware específico para atender aos requisitos do software SAS utilizado,</P><P>— formações e workshops que foram realizados para facilitar ao pessoal da Frontex a aquisição de conhecimentos apropriados. Existe agora um conjunto substancial de conhecimentos estabelecidos na Frontex com base na tecnologia SAS.</P><P>Atualmente, a tecnologia SAS é um dos componentes principais e críticos do processo de análise de risco.</P><P>A potencial substituição da tecnologia SAS por uma tecnologia equivalente exigiria uma decisão estratégica para dar início a um processo que duraria vários anos e exigiria investimentos financeiros e não financeiros significativos para atingir um nível de maturidade semelhante ao atual. Durante este período, as soluções baseadas na tecnologia SAS exigiriam pelo menos a manutenção.</P><P>O SAS Institute e a sua posição no mercado.</P><P>O SAS Institute Inc. é o único fabricante e editor do software SAS. O SAS Institute Inc. é o proprietário dos direitos de propriedade intelectual do software SAS. O SAS Institute sp. z o.o. uma subsidiária da SAS Institute Inc., tem o direito exclusivo de conceder licenças de software SAS em benefício de entidades obrigadas a utilizar o direito dos contratos públicos na Polónia.</P><P>Escolha do processo de adjudicação.</P><P>O processo de adjudicação para as licenças de software SAS será um processo por negociação sem publicação prévia de um anúncio de concurso em conformidade com o ponto 11, n.º 1, alínea b), subalíneas ii), iii), do anexo I do Regulamento Financeiro (anteriormente, o artigo 134.º, ponto 1, alínea b), b), subalíneas ii), iii) das normas de execução, devido à existência de razões técnicas e à necessidade de proteção dos direitos exclusivos. Assim, o contrato só pode ser adjudicado a um determinado operador económico. Dado o facto de o SAS Institute ser o único proprietário das licenças, o procedimento acima mencionado foi o escolhido.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Contrato-quadro para a aquisição de licenças de software SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunal Geral</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunal Geral</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunal Geral</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="SV"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Europeiska gräns- och kustbevakningsbyrån</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Ramavtal för anskaffande av programvarulicenser avseende SAS (Statistical Analysis System)</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Syftet med detta avtal är att etablera en köpkanal i form av ett ramavtal som möjliggör införskaffande av programvarulicenser avseende SAS:</P><P>1) För att förnya och bibehålla den uppsättning programvarulicenser avseende SAS som används i Frontex;</P><P>2) för att fakultativt utöka uppsättningen programvarulicenser för SAS som används i Frontex genom att:</P><P>(a) införskaffa fler produktlicenser som är i bruk och/eller</P><P>(b) införskaffa licenser för andra -programvaruprodukter.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, PL. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLEN</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Avtalets syfte är att enligt ramavtal införskaffa programvarulicenser för SAS.</P><P>Anbudsgivaren har ombetts att tillhandahålla följande tjänster och varor:</P><P>A. Förnyelseavgift (RF - Renewal fee) för Frontex bassystem avseende programvarulicenser för SAS</P><P>(a) Förslaget ska innehålla en detaljerad specifikation för programvara avseende SAS samt underkomponenter inklusive antal relaterade programvarulicenser som utgör Frontex bassystem för SAS.</P><P>(b) Förslaget ska innehålla endast förnyelseavgift (RF).</P><P>B. Förslag innehållande en tilläggsuppsättning av SAS programvarulicenser som komplement till Frontex bassystem avseende SAS för att höja dess processkapacitet och/eller tillgänglighet.</P><P>(a) Anbudsgivaren ombeds föreslå endast tekniskt tillämpbara lösningar.</P><P>(b) Förslaget ska innehålla en detaljerad specifikation över programvara för SAS samt underkomponenter inklusive antal relaterade programvarulicenser, som krävs för att slutföra den planerade uppgraderingen av processkapacitet och/eller tillgänglighet.</P><P>(c) Anbudsgivaren ombeds föreslå några tekniskt tillämpliga varianter som möjliggör en ökad processkapacitet och/eller tillgänglighet med exempelvis: 10%, 20% och 50%. Varianterna ska noga beskrivas och markeras i det tekniska förslaget och i det finansiella förslaget som B1, B2, etc.</P><P>(d) Förslaget ska innehålla båda pristyperna: Första årets avgift (FYF - First Year Fee) och Förnyelseavgift (RF - Renewal Fee).</P><P>(e) Om så krävs ska förslaget innehålla ett pris på aktuell installationstjänst.</P><P>C. Förslag innehållande kompletterande uppsättningar av licenser för programvara avseende SAS och underkomponenter, för att utöka Frontex bassystem för SAS genom att införa andra programvaruprodukter avseende SAS. För att utöka aktuellt bassystem för SAS genom tilläggsmoduler av programvara och relaterade underkomponenter som möjliggör bättre datastyrning genom integrerade, företagsmässiga, moderna ETL-verktyg som stödjer GUI-baserad utveckling. Anbudsgivaren ombeds föreslå licenser för programvaruuppsättningar för:</P><P>(i) SAS Data Integration</P><P>(ii) Kvalitet på SAS data</P><P>Varianterna ska noga beskrivas och markeras i det tekniska förslaget och i det finansiella förslaget som C1, C2 etc.</P><P>(a) De föreslagna uppsättningarna programvarulicenser ska vara helt i överensstämmelse med Frontex bassystem avseende SAS dvs att måste de vara tekniskt tillämpliga på detta system.</P><P>(b) Förslaget måste innehålla en lista på alla nödvändiga krav/villkor som måste uppfyllas för att genomföra en utökning (t ex tekniska minimikrav för servrar, etc).</P><P>(c) Förslaget ska vara tillämpligt på Frontex bassystem för SAS vad gäller omfång och mängd bearbetad data liksom att passa för syftet.</P><P>(d) Införandet av de föreslagna komponenterna, deras utveckling och förväntad daglig arbetsbörda får inte tillföra negativ påverkan på effektivitet av Frontex befintliga bassystem-lösningar ( t ex svarstid, databehandlingsprestanda, lagringskapacitet, åtkomlighet till rapporter samt interaktivitet).</P><P>(e) Den föreslagna lösningen ska kunna möjliggöra en kraftig tillväxt av systemanvändningen på grund av potentiellt ökad datamängd, ökat antal användare, nya områden för systemapplikationer etc.</P><P>(f) De föreslagna urvalet komponenter liksom föreslaget antal licenser ska kort motiveras i förslaget.</P><P>(g) Förslaget ska innehålla en detaljerad specifikation över programvara för SAS med underkomponenter inklusive det antal relaterade programvarulicenser, som krävs för att med avsedd funktionalitet utöka Frontex bassystem för SAS.</P><P>(h) Förslaget ska innehålla båda pristyperna: Första årets avgift (FYF - First Year Fee) och Förnyelseavgift (RF - Renewal Fee).</P><P>(i) Om så krävs ska förslaget innehålla ett pris på aktuell installationstjänst.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Kvalifikationer, expertis, lämplighet och yrkeskompetens avseende uppdragstagaren, tydlighet och pregnans på hela det tekniska förslaget och förståelse avseende syftena.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Sedan första början av Frontex är det riskanalys som är en av de operativa nyckelverksamheterna, som utgör en bas för andra verksamheter. Uppgifter i samband med riskanalys som ska utföras av Frontex fastställdes i den första Frontex förordningen (EG) 2007/2004. I den nya förordningen avseende Frontex (EU) 2016/1624 har de uppgifter som är relaterade till riskanalys även utökats i jämförelse med det föregående förhållandet. Frontex organisatoriska struktur har nyligen ändrats och situationsmedvetenhets- och övervakningsavdelning har skapats för att uppfylla de nya kraven.</P><P>SAS-programvarans roll och betydelse för riskanalysbehandling i Frontex</P><P>SAS-teknologi är det verktyg som stödjer riskanalysuppgifterna i Frontex. Det första införandet av SAS-teknologi ägde rum 2008. Sedan 2008 har Frontex investerat en betydande mängd medel vad gäller tid, personalresurser och finansiella medel för:</P><P>— SAS-programvarulicenser och integration i Frontexbygget,</P><P>— Särskild maskinvara för att uppfylla kraven för använd SAS-programvara,</P><P>— Utbildningar och workshops som har letts för att underlätta för personal i Frontex att inhämta tillbörlig kunskap. Det finns nu en substantiell kunskapsmängd baserad på SAS-teknologi i Frontex.</P><P>Numera är SAS-teknologi en av de avgörande komponenterna i grunden för, och komponenterna i riskanalysbehandling.</P><P>Eventuellt byte av SAS-teknologi mot en likvärdig teknologi skulle kräva ett strategiskt beslut för att initiera en process som kommer att vara många år och som skulle kräva betydande finansiella och icke finansiella investeringar för att uppnå en utvecklingsnivå likvärdig med den aktuella. Under denna period skulle lösningar baserade på SAS-teknologi minst krävas för att bibehållas.</P><P>SAS Institutet och dess marknadsposition.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. är den enda tillverkare och utgivare av SAS-programvara. SAS Institute Inc. är ägare av immateriella rättigheterna till SAS Software. SAS Institute sp. z o.o. a subsidiary of SAS Instituts Inc., har ensamrätt att bevilja licenser avseende SAS Software till förmån för enheter skyldiga att följa lagen om Offentlig upphandling i Polen.</P><P>Val av upphandlingsförfarande.</P><P>Upphandlingsförfarandet avseende SAS programvarulicenser kommer att bestå av ett förhandlat förfarande utan föregående publicering av meddelande om upphandling i enlighet med punkt 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) i bilaga I FR (tidigare artikel 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) RAP, på grund av tekniska skäl och kravet på skydd av ensamrätt. Således kan kontraktet endast tilldelas till en specifik ekonomisk aktör. Givet att SAS Institute är enda ägare av licenserna, har ovan nämnda förfarande valts.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Ramavtal för anskaffande av programvarulicenser avseende SAS (Statistical Analysis System)</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunalen</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunalen</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunalen</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="CS"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Evropská agentura pro pohraniční a pobřežní stráž</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Rámcová smlouva na pořízení licencí na software SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Předmětem této smlouvy je zřízení akvizičního kanálu v podobě rámcové smlouvy umožňující nákup licencí na software SAS za účelem:</P><P>1) obnovy a údržby sady licencí na software SAS, který se v současnosti ve Frontexu používá;</P><P>2) dobrovolného rozšíření sady licencí na software SAS, který se v současnosti ve Frontexu používá, a to:</P><P>a) nákupem více licencí na v současné době používané produkty a/nebo</P><P>b) nákupem licencí na jiné produkty SAS softwaru.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLSKO</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Předmětem této zakázky je poskytnutí licencí na software SAS prostřednictvím rámcové smlouvy.</P><P>Od uchazeče bylo požadováno poskytnutí následujících služeb a dodávek:</P><P>A. Poplatek za obnovu licencí agentury Frontex k základnímu systému SAS</P><P>a) Návrh musí obsahovat detailní specifikaci softwaru SAS a jeho dílčích složek, včetně počtu souvisejících softwarových licencí, které tvoří základní systém SAS agentury Frontex.</P><P>b) Návrh musí obsahovat pouze poplatek za obnovu.</P><P>B. Návrh zahrnující doplňkové sady licencí na software SAS, který rozšíří stávající základní systém SAS agentury Frontex a zvýší tak jeho zpracovatelskou kapacitu a/nebo dostupnost.</P><P>a) Od uchazeče se vyžaduje pouze poskytnutí technicky použitelných řešení.</P><P>b) Návrh musí obsahovat detailní specifikaci softwaru SAS a jeho dílčích složek, včetně počtu souvisejících softwarových licencí, který je potřebný k dosažení plánovaného navýšení zpracovatelské kapacity a/nebo dostupnosti.</P><P>c) Od uchazeče se vyžaduje navržení několika technicky použitelných variant umožňujících navýšení zpracovatelské kapacity a/nebo dostupnosti, a to například o: 10 %, 20 % a 50 %. Jednotlivé varianty musí být jasně popsány a označeny v technickém a finančním návrhu pod označením B1, B2 atd.</P><P>d) Návrh musí obsahovat oba typy cen, respektive: poplatek za první rok používání a poplatek za obnovu.</P><P>e) V případě potřeby by měl návrh zahrnovat cenu za příslušné instalační služby.</P><P>C. Návrh zahrnující doplňkové sady licencí na software SAS a jeho dílčí složky, který rozšíří stávající základní SAS systém agentury Frontex zavedením jiných produktů softwaru SAS, s cílem rozšířit stávající základní systém SAS agentury Frontex o doplňkové softwarové moduly a související dílčí složky a umožnit tak lepší správu údajů prostřednictvím integrovaného, pro potřeby velkých organizací přizpůsobeného a moderního ETL nástroje, který podpoří vývoj na bázi grafického uživatelského rozhraní. Od uchazeče se vyžaduje předložení licencí na softwarové sady pro:</P><P>i) datovou integraci s použitím SAS</P><P>ii) datovou kvalitu SAS</P><P>Jednotlivé varianty musí být jasně popsány a označeny v technickém a finančním návrhu pod označením C1 a C2.</P><P>a) Navrhovaná sada softwarových licencí musí být plně kompatibilní se základním systémem SAS agentury Frontex, to znamená musí být vzhledem k tomuto systému technicky použitelná.</P><P>b) Návrh musí obsahovat seznam všech povinných požadavků / podmínek, které je nutné splnit za účelem provedení požadovaného rozšíření (jedná se např. o minimální technické požadavky na servery atd.).</P><P>c) Návrh by měl z hlediska svého rozsahu, množství zpracovaných údajů a vhodnosti pro daný účel přiměřeně odpovídat základním systémům SAS agentury Frontex.</P><P>d) Zavedení, rozmístění a očekávaná denní pracovní zátěž nesmí mít negativní dopad na účinnost stávajících řešení systémů SAS agentury Frontex (např. dobu odezvy, výkonnost ohledně zpracování dat, úložnou kapacitu, dostupnost a interaktivitu zpráv).</P><P>e) Předložené řešení by mělo umožnit opodstatněný růst využívání systému vzhledem k potenciálnímu navýšení objemu dat, zvýšenému počtu uživatelů, novým oblastem využití systému atd.</P><P>f) Výběr navržených dílčích částí jakož i navržený počet licencí musí být v návrhu krátce odůvodněn.</P><P>g) Návrh musí obsahovat detailní specifikaci softwaru SAS a jeho dílčích složek, včetně počtu souvisejících softwarových licencí, které jsou potřebné k rozšíření základního systému SAS agentury Frontex a dosažení jeho zamýšlené funkčnosti.</P><P>h) Návrh musí obsahovat oba typy cen, respektive: poplatek za první rok používání a poplatek za obnovu.</P><P>i) V případě potřeby by měl návrh zahrnovat cenu za příslušné instalační služby.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Kvalifikace, odborná kapacita, vhodnost a odborná způsobilost zhotovitele, srozumitelnost a stručnost celkového technického návrhu a pochopení cílů.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Analýza rizik je již od samých počátků existence agentury Frontex jednou z jejích klíčových operativních činností představující podklad pro její další aktivity. Úkoly související s analýzou rizik, které má agentura Frontex plnit, byly vymezeny již v jejím prvním nařízení (ES) 2007/2004. Ve svém novém nařízení (EU) 2016/1624 agentura Frontex zadání související s analýzou rizik ve srovnáním s předchozím stavem dokonce rozšířila. S cílem vyhovět novým požadavkům přistoupila agentura Frontex v nedávné době ke změně svojí organizační struktury ve smyslu zřízení oddělení pro získávání poznatků o současné situaci a její monitorování.</P><P>Úloha a důležitost softwaru SAS v rámci procesu analýzy rizik v agentuře Frontex</P><P>Technologie SAS je nástroj, který podporuje plnění úkolů zaměřených na analýzy rizik v agentuře Frontex. K prvnímu zavedení technologie SAS došlo v roce 2008. Agentura Frontex investovala od roku 2008 značné množství zdrojů v podobě času, lidských zdrojů a finančních prostředků do:</P><P>— licencí na software SAS a jeho začlenění do stávající softwarové architektury agentury Frontex,</P><P>— specifického hardwaru, který by vyhovoval požadavkům používaného softwaru SAS,</P><P>— školení a pracovních setkání realizovaných za účelem usnadnit zaměstnancům agentury Frontex osvojení příslušných znalostí. V současné době je v rámci agentury Frontex ustavený solidní soubor znalostí ve vztahu k technologii SAS.</P><P>SAS technologie je v současnosti jednou ze základních a zásadních složek procesu analýzy rizik.</P><P>Případné nahrazení technologie SAS jinou, ekvivalentní technologií, by vyžadovalo strategické rozhodnutí ohledně zahájení několikaletého procesu a dále značné finanční a nefinanční investice vedoucí k dosažení úrovně vyspělosti podobné úrovni stávající. Během tohoto období by bylo nutné stávající řešení založená na technologii SAS minimálně udržovat.</P><P>SAS Institute a jeho pozice na trhu.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. je výhradním výrobcem a vydavatelem softwaru SAS. SAS Institute Inc. je dále vlastníkem práv k duševnímu vlastnictví na software SAS. SAS Institute sp. z o. o jakožto dceřinná společnost SAS Institute Inc. disponuje výhradním právem na udělování licencí k softwaru SAS ve prospěch subjektů povinných respektovat zákon o veřejných zakázkách v Polsku.</P><P>Výběr zadávacího řízení.</P><P>Zadávací řízení na licence k softwaru SAS bude mít podobu jednacího řízení bez předchozího zveřejnění oznámení o zakázce v souladu s bodem 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) přílohy I finančního nařízení (dříve čl. 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) prováděcích pravidel, a to z důvodu existence technických důvodů a potřeby chránit výhradní práva. Zakázka může být proto zadána pouze jednomu konkrétnímu hospodářskému subjektu. Výše uvedený typ řízení byl zvolen vzhledem ke skutečnosti, že SAS Institute je výhradním vlastníkem potřebných licencí.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Rámcová smlouva na pořízení licencí na software SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunál</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunál</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunál</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="ET"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Euroopa Piiri- ja Rannikuvalve Amet</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Raamleping SASi tarkvaralitsentside hankimise kohta</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Kõnealuse lepingu ese on raamlepingu vormis hankekanali sisseseadmine, mis võimaldaks SASi tarkvaralitsentside ostmist:</P><P>1) Frontexis kasutusel oleva SASi tarkvaralitsentside kogumi pikendamiseks ja teenindamiseks;</P><P>2) Frontexis kasutusel oleva SASi tarkvaralitsentside kogumi valikuliseks pikendamiseks:</P><P>a) kasutusel olevate toodete jaoks litsentside juurdeostmisega ja/või</P><P>b) muude SASi tarkvaratoodete jaoks litsentside ostmisega.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POOLA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Kõnealuse lepingu ese on SASi tarkvaralitsentside hankimine vastavalt raamlepingule.</P><P>Pakkujalt nõuti järgmiste teenuste osutamist ja järgmiste kaupadega varustamist:</P><P>A. Frontexi tuumik-SASi süsteemi litsentside pikendamistasu. </P><P>a) Pakkumine peab sisaldama SASi tarkvara ja selle osiste üksikasjalikku kirjeldust kaasa arvatud Frontexi tuumik-SASi süsteemi moodustavate seotud tarkvaralitsentside kogus.</P><P>b) Pakkumine peab sisaldama ainult pikendamistasu.</P><P>B. Pakkumine, mis sisaldab tarkvaralitsentside täiendavaid kogumeid Frontexi tuumik-SASi süsteemi täiendamiseks, et suurendada selle töötlemisvõimet ja/või käideldavust. </P><P>a) Pakkujalt nõutakse ainult tehniliselt rakendatavate lahenduste esitamist.</P><P>b) Pakkumine peab sisaldama SASi tarkvara ja selle osiste üksikasjalikku kirjeldust, kaasa arvatud kavandatud töötlemisvõime ja/või käideldavuse suurendamise saavutamiseks vajalike seotud tarkvaralitsentside kogus.</P><P>c) Pakkujalt nõutakse mõne tehniliselt rakendatava variandi esitamist, mis võimaldaksid töötlemisvõime ja/või käideldavuse suurendamist nt 10 %, 20 % ja 50 % võrra.  Need variandid peaksid olema tehnilises pakkumises ja finantspakkumises kindlapiiriliselt kirjeldatud ja selgelt tähistatud kui B1, B2 jne.</P><P>d) Pakkumine peab sisaldama mõlemat liiki hindu: esimese aasta litsentsitasu ja litsentsi pikendamistasu. </P><P>e) Vajadusel peaks pakkumine sisaldama asjakohase installimisteenuse hinda.</P><P>C. SASi tarkvara ja selle osiste litsentside täiendavaid kogumeid sisaldav pakkumine, et laiendada Frontexi tuumik SASi süsteemi muude SASi tarkvaratoodete juurutamisega - et laiendada praegust Frontexi tuumik-SASi süsteemi täiendavate tarkvaramoodulite ja seotud osiste lisamisega, mis võimaldab paremat andmevalitsemist, kasutades integreeritud, äriklassi, kaasaegset, graafilise kasutajaliidese põhist arendust toetavat ekstraktivat-teisendavat-laadivat (ETL) töövahendit.  Pakkujalt nõutakse tarkvaralitsentside kogumite esitamist</P><P>i) SASi andmete integreerimise ja</P><P>ii) SASi andmete kvaliteedijaoks.</P><P>Nimetatud kogumid peaksid olema tehnilises pakkumises ja finantspakkumises kindlapiiriliselt kirjeldatud ja selgelt tähistatud kui C1 ja C2.</P><P>a) Pakutud tarkvaralitsentside kogumid peavad olema täielikus vastavuses Frontexi tuumik-SASi süsteemiga, st, peavad olema sellele süsteemile tehniliselt rakendatavad.</P><P>b) Pakkumine peab sisaldama nimekirja kõigist kohustuslikest nõuetest/tingimustest, mida laiendamise rakendamiseks tuleb järgida (nt serveritele esitatavad minimaalsed tehnilised nõuded jne).</P><P>c) Pakkumine peab ulatuselt ja töödeldavate andmete koguselt vastama Frontexi tuumik-SASi süsteemile ning olema otstarbelt sobiv.</P><P>d) Pakutud komponentide teostuse, kasutuselevõtu ja eeldatava päevase koormusega ei tohi kaasneda negatiivset mõju olemasolevatele Frontexi SASi süsteemilahendustele (nt reaktsiooniaeg, andmetöötlusjõudlus, mälu maht, teavitavate kiirandmike kasutushõlpsus ja interaktiivsus).</P><P>e) Pakutud lahendus peaks andma võimaluse süsteemi kasutamise lubatavaks kasvuks tulenevalt potentsiaalselt suurenevast andmemahust, kasutajate arvu kasvust, süsteemi uutest rakendusaladest jne.</P><P>f) Pakkumises peab lühidalt põhjendama pakutud komponentide valikuid ning ka pakutud litsentside kogust.</P><P>a) Pakkumine peab sisaldama SASi tarkvara ja selle osiste üksikasjalikku kirjeldust kaasa arvatud seotud tarkvaralitsentside kogus, mida on tarvis Frontexi tuumik-SASi süsteemi laiendamiseks ettekavatsetud funktsioonistikuga.</P><P>h) Pakkumine peab sisaldama mõlemat liiki hindu: esimese aasta litsentsitasu ja litsentsi pikendamistasu. </P><P>i) Vajadusel peaks pakkumine sisaldama asjakohase installimisteenuse hinda.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>töövõtja kutseoskus, kogemused, sobivus ja ametialane pädevus, üldise tehnilise pakkumuse selgus ja sisutihedus ning eesmärkidest arusaamine</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Frontexi algusajast alates on riskianalüüs üks peamistest operatiivtegevustest, mis on ülejäänud tegevuste aluseks. Riskianalüüsiga seotud ülesanded, mida Frontexil tuleb täita, määratleti esimeses Frontexi määruses (EL) 2007/2004. Uues Frontexi määruses (EL) 2016/1624 on eelneva seisuga võrreldes riskianalüüsiga seotud ülesandeid laiendatud veelgi. Hiljuti muudeti Frontexi organisatsioonilist ülesehitust ning uute nõuete täitmiseks loodi Olukorrateadlikkuse ja situatsioonijälgimise osakond (Situational Awareness and Monitoring Division).</P><P>SASi tarkvara roll ja selle tähtsus riskianalüüsi protsessile Frontexis</P><P>SASi tehnoloogia on Frontexis riskianalüüsi ülesannete täitmist toetav töövahend. SASi tehnoloogia võeti esmakordselt kasutusele 2008. aastal. Alates 2008. aastast, Frontex on sellest aastast saadik investeerinud olulisel määral vahendeid nii aja, inimressursside kui finantsvahendite kujul, järgmisesse:</P><P>– SASi tarkvaralitsentsid ja tarkvara integreerimine Frontexi arhitektuuri;</P><P>– spetsiifiline riistvara kasutusele võetud SASi tarkvara nõuete järgmiseks;</P><P>– koolitused ja õpikojad, mis viidi läbi, et kergendada Frontexi personalil asjakohaste teadmiste omandamist. Praeguseks on Frontexis kujunenud välja SASi tehnoloogiale tuginev märkimisväärne teadmistekogum.</P><P>Tänasel päeval on SASi tehnoloogia üks tuumikelement ning on riskianalüüsi protsessi oluline komponent.</P><P>SASi tehnoloogia võimalik väljavahetamine samaväärse tehnoloogia vastu nõuaks strateegilist otsust, et algatada protsess, mis kestab mitu aastat ja mis nõuaks olulisi rahalisi ja mitterahalisi investeeringuid, et saavutada praegusele valmidustasemele sarnanevale tasemele. Nimetatud ajavahemiku jooksul nõuaksid SASi tehnoloogial põhinevad lahendused vähemalt teenindamist.</P><P>SAS Institute ja selle turupositsioon.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. on SASi tarkvara ainutootja ja väljaandja. SAS Institute Inc. on SASi tarkvaras intellektuaalomandiõiguse omanik. SAS Institute sp. z o.o., ettevõtte SAS Institute Inc. tütarettevõttel, on ainuõigus anda SASi tarkvara kasutuslitsentse, mis on abiks Poolas riigihanke seadust järgima kohustatud majandusüksustele.</P><P>Hankemenetluse valik</P><P>SASi tarkvaralitsentside hankemenetlus toimub väljakuulutamiseta läbirääkimistega hankemenetlusena kooskõlas finantsmääruse I lisa punkti 11.1 punkti b alapunktides ii ja iii (eelnevalt kohaldamise eeskirjade artikli 134 lõike 1 punkti b alapunktid ii ja iii) sätestatuga, tulenevalt tehniliste põhjuste olemasolust ja vajadusest tagada ainuõiguste kaitse.  Seega saab lepingut sõlmida ainult ühe konkreetse ettevõtjaga. Eelnimetatud menetlusliigi väljavalimisel peeti silmas asjaolu, et SAS Institute on litsentside ainuomanik.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Raamleping SASi tarkvaralitsentside hankimise kohta</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Üldkohus</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Üldkohus</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Üldkohus</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="HU"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Európai Határ- és Partvédelmi Ügynökség</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>SAS szoftverlicencek beszerzésére irányuló keretszerződés</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>A szerződés tárgya beszerzési csatorna kialakítása keretszerződés formájában SAS szoftverlicencek beszerzéséhez:</P><P>1) a Frontex által használt SAS szoftverlicencek megújítása és fenntartása érdekében;</P><P>2) a Frontex által használt SAS szoftverlicencek körének opcionális bővítése érdekében a következők által:</P><P>(a) További licencek vásárlása a használatban lévő termékekhez és/vagy</P><P>(b) Licencek vásárlása egyéb SAS szoftvertermékekhez.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, LENGYELORSZÁG</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>A szerződés tárgya SAS szoftverlicencek beszerzése keretszerződés útján.</P><P>A pályázótól az alábbi szolgáltatások nyújtását és áruk beszerzését kérték:</P><P>A. A Frontex központi SAS rendszerének licenceire vonatkozó megújítási költség</P><P>(a) Az ajánlatnak tartalmaznia kell a Frontex központi SAS rendszerét alkotó SAS szoftver és alkomponensek részletes leírását, beleértve a kapcsolódó szoftverlicencek számát.</P><P>(b) Az ajánlatnak kizárólag a megújítási költséget kell tartalmaznia.</P><P>B. További SAS szoftverlicenceket tartalmazó ajánlat a Frontex központi SAS rendszerének kiegészítésére, annak feldolgozási kapacitásának és/vagy rendelkezésre állásának növelése érdekében.</P><P>(a) A pályázótól kizárólag technikailag megfelelő megoldások javaslatát várják.</P><P>(b) Az ajánlatnak tartalmaznia kell az SAS szoftver és alkomponensek részletes leírását, beleértve azon kapcsolódó szoftverlicencek számát, amelyek a feldolgozási kapacitás és/vagy a rendelkezésre állás tervezett növelésének megvalósításához szükségesek.</P><P>(c) A pályázónak több technikailag megfelelő változatot kell javasolnia, amelyek lehetővé teszik a feldolgozási kapacitás és/vagy a rendelkezésre állás alábbi mértékekben történő növelését: 10 %, 20 % és 50 %. A változatok egyértelmű leírását B1, B2 stb. jelöléssel kell megadni a technikai ajánlatban és a pénzügyi ajánlatban.</P><P>(d) Az ajánlatnak mindkét díjtípust tartalmaznia kell: első éves díj és megújítási díj.</P><P>(e) Szükség esetén az ajánlatnak tartalmaznia kell a vonatkozó telepítési szolgáltatás díját.</P><P>C. Az SAS szoftverhez és alkomponensekhez további licenceket tartalmazó ajánlat a Frontex központi SAS rendszerének egyéb SAS szoftvertermékekkel történő bővítéséhez, a Frontex jelenlegi központi SAS rendszerének további szoftvermodulokkal és a kapcsolódó alkomponensekkel történő bővítéséhez a jobb adatkormányzás érdekében, amelyet a GUI-alapú fejlesztést támogató, integrált, vállalati szintű, modern ETL-eszköz tesz lehetővé. A pályázótól szoftverlicencekre vonatkozó ajánlatot várnak a következőkhöz:</P><P>(i) SAS adatintegráció</P><P>(ii) SAS adatminőség</P><P>A licencek egyértelmű leírását C1, C2 stb. jelöléssel kell megadni a technikai ajánlatban és a pénzügyi ajánlatban.</P><P>(a) A javasolt szoftverlicenceknek teljes mértékben meg kell felelniük a Frontex központi SAS rendszerének, azaz technikailag alkalmasnak kell lenniük a rendszerrel történő használatra.</P><P>(b) Az ajánlatnak tartalmaznia kell az összes kötelező követelményt/feltételt, amelyek teljesítése szükséges a bővítés végrehajtásához (pl. szerverekkel kapcsolatos minimális technikai követelmények stb.).</P><P>(c) Az ajánlatnak méretezés, a feldolgozott adatmennyiség és a cél szempontjából megfelelőnek kell lennie a Frontex központi SAS rendszerének.</P><P>(d) Az ajánlott komponensek telepítése, kiépítése és várt napi munkamennyisége nem gyakorolhat kedvezőtlen hatást a meglévő Frontex SAS rendszermegoldások hatékonyságára (pl. válaszidők, adatfeldolgozási teljesítmény, tárolási kapacitás, jelentések hozzáférhetősége és interaktivitás).</P><P>(e) A javasolt megoldásnak lehetővé kell tennie a rendszer kihasználtságának indokolt növelését az adatmennyiség esetleges növekedése, a felhasználók számának növekedése, a rendszer új alkalmazási területei stb. esetén.</P><P>(f) Az ajánlatban röviden meg kell indokolni, hogy miért az ajánlott komponensekre esett a választás, és hogyan határozták meg a licencek ajánlott számát.</P><P>(g) Az ajánlatnak tartalmaznia kell a Frontex központi SAS rendszerének kívánt funkcióval történő bővítéséhez szükséges SAS szoftver és alkomponensek részletes leírását, beleértve a kapcsolódó szoftverlicencek számát.</P><P>(h) Az ajánlatnak mindkét díjtípust tartalmaznia kell: első éves díj és megújítási díj.</P><P>(i) Szükség esetén az ajánlatnak tartalmaznia kell a vonatkozó telepítési szolgáltatás díját.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>A nyertes ajánlattevő képesítései, szakértelme, megfelelősége és szakmai kompetenciái; a teljes technikai ajánlat egyértelműsége és tömörsége; a célkitűzések megértése.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>A kockázatelemzés a kezdetektől fogva a Frontex egyik fő működési tevékenysége, amely egyéb tevékenységek alapját is képezi. A Frontex által végrehajtandó, kockázatelemzéshez kapcsolódó feladatokat az első Frontex-rendelet (2007/2004/EK) tartalmazza. Az új Frontex-rendeletben (2016/1624/EU) a korábbiakhoz képest bővítették a kockázatelemzéshez kapcsolódó feladatokat. A Frontex szervezeti felépítése nemrégiben módosult, és létrejött a Helyzetfelismerési és -felügyeleti részleg, melynek feladata az új követelmények teljesítése.</P><P>Az SAS szoftver szerepe és jelentősége a Frontex kockázatelemzési folyamatában</P><P>Az SAS technológia támogatja a Frontex kockázatelemzési feladatait. Az SAS technológiát 2008-ban építették ki. 2008 óta a Frontex jelentős mennyiségű erőforrást – időt, emberi erőforrást és pénzügyi eszközt – fektetett a következőkbe:</P><P>— SAS szoftverlicencek és azok integrációja a Frontex architektúrájába,</P><P>— Az alkalmazott SAS szoftver követelményeinek megfelelő, meghatározott hardver,</P><P>— Képzések és workshopok szervezése, ahol a Frontex alkalmazottai elsajátíthatták a szükséges ismereteket. A Frontex mára jelentős ismeretanyagot halmozott fel az SAS technológiára alapozva.</P><P>Napjainkban az SAS technológia a kockázatelemzés folyamatának alapvető és kritikus fontosságú alkotóeleme.</P><P>Az SAS technológia egyenértékű technológiára történő cseréjéhez stratégiai döntésre lenne szükség, mivel a jelenlegihez hasonló érettségi szint eléréséhez több éven át tartó, valamint jelentős pénzügyi és nem pénzügyi befektetéseket igénylő folyamat szükséges. Ez alatt az időszak alatt az SAS technológiára épülő megoldásokat legalább fenn kell tartani.</P><P>Az SAS Institute és annak piaci helyzete.</P><P>Az SAS Institute Inc. az SAS szoftver kizárólagos gyártója és forgalmazója. Az SAS szoftver szellemi tulajdonjoga az SAS Institute Inc. vállalatot illeti meg. Az SAS Institute sp. z o.o. az SAS Institute Inc. leányvállalatként kizárólagos joggal rendelkezik az SAS szoftver licenceinek megadásához olyan szervezeteknek, amelyek a lengyel közbeszerzési törvény hatálya alatt állnak.</P><P>A közbeszerzési eljárás választott típusa.</P><P>Műszaki okokból, valamint a kizárólagos jogok védelmének szükségessége miatt az SAS szoftverlicencekre irányuló közbeszerzési eljárás ajánlati felhívás előzetes közzététele nélküli tárgyalásos eljárás keretében zajlik majd, a költségvetési rendelet I. mellékletének 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) pontjának megfelelően (korábban: az alkalmazási szabályok 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) pontja).  Ebből kifolyólag a szerződés kizárólag egy adott gazdasági szereplőnek ítélhető oda. Mivel az SAS Institute a licencek kizárólagos tulajdonosa, a fenti eljárást választották.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>SAS szoftverlicencek beszerzésére irányuló keretszerződés</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Törvényszék</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Törvényszék</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Törvényszék</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="LT"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Europos sienų ir pakrančių apsaugos agentūra</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Preliminarioji sutartis dėl SAS programinės įrangos licencijos įsigijimo</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Šios sutarties objektas – sudaryti įsigijimo kanalą kaip preliminariąją sutartį, pagal kurią būtų galima įsigyti SAS programinės įrangos licencijas:</P><P>1) siekiant atnaujinti ir palaikyti SAS programinės įrangos licencijų rinkinį, kuriomis naudojasi Frontex;</P><P>2) siekiant pasirinktinai pratęsti SAS programinės įrangos licencijų rinkinį, kurį naudoja Frontex:</P><P>(a) įsigydama daugiau naudojamų produktų licencijų ir (arba)</P><P>(b) įsigydama kitų SAS programinės įrangos produktų licencijas.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, LENKIJA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Šios sutarties objektas yra SAS programinės įrangos licencijų teikimas pagal preliminariąją sutartį.</P><P>Konkurso dalyvio prašoma teikti šias paslaugas ir tiekti šiuos reikmenis:</P><P>A. Frontex pagrindinės SAS sistemos licencijų atnaujinimo mokestis.</P><P>(a) Pasiūlyme reikia pateikti smulkią SAS programinės įrangos ir jos sudėtinių dalių specifikaciją, įskaitant susijusios programinės įrangos licencijų, kurios sudaro Frontex pagrindinę SAS sistemą, skaičių.</P><P>(b) Pasiūlyme turi būti nurodytas tik atnaujinimo mokestis.</P><P>B. Pasiūlymas, susijęs su papildomomis SAS programinės įrangos licencijomis, kurios papildo Frontex pagrindinę SAS sistemą, tam, kad padidintų apdorojimo pajėgumą ir (arba) prieinamumą.</P><P>(a) Konkurso dalyvio prašoma pateikti tik techniškai tinkamus sprendimus.</P><P>(b) Pasiūlyme reikia pateikti smulkią SAS programinės įrangos ir jos sudėtinių dalių specifikaciją, įskaitant susijusios programinės įrangos licencijų, kurių reikės, kad būtų pasiektas planuojamas apdorojimo pajėgumų ir (arba) prieinamumo padidėjimas, skaičių.</P><P>(c) Konkurso dalyvio prašoma pasiūlyti kelis techniškai tinkamus variantus, kuriais būtų galima padidinti apdorojimo pajėgumą ir (arba) prieinamumą, pvz., 10 %, 20 % ir 50 %. Variantai techniniame pasiūlyme ir finansiniame pasiūlyme turi būti aiškiai aprašyti ir pažymėti kaip B1, B2 ir t. t.</P><P>(d) Pasiūlyme turi būti nurodytos dviejų tipų kainos: Mokestis už pirmus metus ir atnaujinimo mokestis.</P><P>(e) Jei reikia, pasiūlyme turi būti nurodyta atitinkamos diegimo paslaugos kaina.</P><P>C. Pasiūlymas dėl papildomų SAS programinės įrangos ir jos sudedamųjų dalių licencijų rinkinių, kad būtų galima praplėsti Frontex pagrindinę SAS sistemą, įvedant kitus SAS programinės įrangos produktus; praplėsti turimą Frontex pagrindinę SAS sistemą, įdiegiant papildomus programinės įrangos modulius ir susijusius pagalbinius komponentus, kuriais galima geriau valdyti duomenis integruota, įmonių klasės, modernia ETL programa, kuri padeda plėtoti grafines vartotojo sąsajas. Konkurso dalyvis turi pasiūlyti šių produktų programinės įrangos licencijų rinkinius:</P><P>(i) SAS Data Integration</P><P>(ii) SAS Data Quality</P><P>Rinkiniai turi būti aiškiai aprašyti ir techniniame bei finansiniame pasiūlymuose pažymėti kaip C1 ir C2.</P><P>(a) Siūlomi programinės įrangos licencijų rinkiniai turi visiškai atitikti Frontex pagrindinę sistemą, t. y. turi būti techniškai pritaikomi šiai sistemai.</P><P>(b) Pasiūlyme turi būti pateiktas visų privalomų reikalavimų / sąlygų sąrašas, kurias reikia tenkinti, norint įgyvendinti pratęsimą (pvz., minimalūs techniniai reikalavimai serveriams ir kt.).</P><P>(c) Pasiūlymas turi atitikti Frontex pagrindinę SAS sistemą pagal dydį ir apdorojamų duomenų apimtį, taip pat turi būti tinkamas šiam tikslui.</P><P>(d) Siūlomas sudėtinių dalių įgyvendinimas, diegimas ir tikėtinas kasdienis darbo krūvis negali turėti neigiamo poveikio turimos Frontex SAS sistemos sprendimų veiksmingumui (pvz., reagavimo laikui, duomenų apdorojimo rezultatams, saugojimo pajėgumui, prieinamumui prie ataskaitų ir interaktyvumui).</P><P>(e) Siūlomas sprendimas turi leisti pagrįstai didinti sistemos naudojimą dėl potencialiai didesnio duomenų kiekio, didesnio vartotojų skaičiaus, naujų sistemos taikymo sričių ir kt.</P><P>(f) Siūlomi pasirinkti komponentai ir siūlomas licencijų skaičius pasiūlyme turi būti trumpai pagrįsti.</P><P>(g) Pasiūlyme reikia pateikti smulkią SAS programinės įrangos ir jos sudėtinių dalių specifikaciją, įskaitant susijusios programinės įrangos licencijų, kurių reikia Frontex pagrindinei SAS sistemai praplėsti numatytomis funkcijomis, skaičių.</P><P>(h) Pasiūlyme turi būti nurodytos dviejų tipų kainos: Mokestis už pirmus metus ir atnaujinimo mokestis.</P><P>(i) Jei reikia, pasiūlyme turi būti nurodyta atitinkamos diegimo paslaugos kaina.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Rangovo kvalifikacija, kompetencija, tinkamumas ir profesinė kompetencija, bendro techninio pasiūlymo aiškumas bei glaustumas ir tikslų supratimas.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Nuo pat pradžių Frontex viena pagrindinių veiklų yra rizikos analizė, kuri yra kitos veiklos pagrindas. Užduotys, susijusios su rizikos analize, kurias atlieka Frontex, buvo apibrėžtos pirmajame Frontex reglamente (EB) 2007/2004. Naujajame Frontex reglamente (ES) 2016/1624 su rizikos analize susijusios užduotys dar labiau praplėstos, palyginti su ankstesnėmis. Frontex organizacinė struktūra buvo neseniai pakeista, o naujiems reikalavimams įgyvendinti sukurtas Informavimo apie padėtį ir stebėsenos padalinys.</P><P>SAS programinės įrangos vaidmuo ir jos svarba Frontex rizikos analizavimo procese</P><P>SAS technologija yra programa, padedanti Frontex atlikti rizikos analizės užduotis. Pirmą kartą SAS technologija buvo įgyvendinta 2008 m. Nuo 2008 m. Frontex investavo daug laiko, žmogiškųjų išteklių ir finansinių priemonių į:</P><P>— SAS programinės įrangos licencijas ir jų integravimą į Frontex architektūrą,</P><P>— specifinę aparatinę įrangą, kad tenkintų reikalavimus, keliamus naudojamai SAS programinei įrangai,</P><P>— mokymams ir praktiniams seminarams, kurie buvo vedami tam, kad Frontex darbuotojai lengviau įgytų atitinkamų žinių. Dabar Frontex yra įsteigta svarbi žinių struktūra, grindžiama SAS technologija.</P><P>SAS technologija dabar yra vienas iš pagrindinių ir esminių rizikos analizės procesų komponentų.</P><P>Potencialiam SAS technologijos pakeitimui adekvačia technologija reikėtų priimti strateginį sprendimą, kad būtų pradėtas procesas, truksiantis kelerius metus. Tam reikėtų reikšmingų finansinių ir nefinansinių investicijų, kad būtų pasiektas brandos lygis, panašus į dabartinį. Šiuo laikotarpiu SAS technologija grindžiami sprendimai turėtų būti bent palaikomi.</P><P>SAS Institute ir jo rinkos pozicija.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. yra vienintelis SAS programinės įrangos gamintojas ir leidėjas. SAS Institute Inc. priklauso SAS programinės įrangos intelektinės nuosavybės teisės. SAS Institute sp. z o.o., SAS Institute Inc. patronuojamoji bendrovė, turi išskirtines teises suteikti SAS programinės įrangos licencijas bendrovėms, kurios privalo vadovautis Viešųjų pirkimų įstatymu Lenkijoje.</P><P>Pirkimo procedūros pasirinkimas</P><P>SAS programinės įrangos licencijų pirkimo procedūra bus derybos be išankstinio skelbimo apie pirkimą publikavimo pagal Finansinio reglamento I priedo 11 punkto (1)(b)(ii) ir (iii) dalis (anksčiau taikymo taisyklių 134 straipsnio (1)(b)(ii) ir (iii) dalys) dėl techninių priežasčių ir poreikio apsaugoti išskirtines teises. Todėl sutartis gali būti paskirta tik 1 konkrečiam ekonominės veiklos vykdytojui. Atsižvelgiant į faktą, kad SAS Institute yra vienintelis licencijų savininkas, buvo pasirinkta pirmiau minėta procedūra.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Preliminarioji sutartis dėl SAS programinės įrangos licencijos įsigijimo</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Bendrasis Teismas</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Bendrasis Teismas</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Bendrasis Teismas</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="LV"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Eiropas Robežu un krasta apsardzes aģentūra</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Pamatnolīgums par SAS programmatūras licenču iegādi</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Šī līguma priekšmets ir izveidot iegādes avotu pamatnolīguma veidā SAS programmatūras licenču iegādei:</P><P>1) lai atjaunotu un uzturētu Frontex izmantotās SAS programmatūras licenču kopumu;</P><P>2) lai pēc izvēles paplašinātu Frontex izmantoto SAS programmatūras licenču kopumu:</P><P>a) iegādājoties vairāk licenču produktiem, kas tiek izmantoti, un/vai</P><P>b) iegādājoties citu SAS programmatūras produktu licences.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLIJA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Šī līguma priekšmets ir SAS programmatūras licenču nodrošināšana saskaņā ar pamatnolīgumu.</P><P>Pretendentam tika lūgts nodrošināt turpmāk norādītos pakalpojumus un piegādes.</P><P>A. Frontex galveno SAS sistēmas licenču atjaunošanas maksa (renewal fee – RF)</P><P>a) Piedāvājumā jāiekļauj detalizēta SAS programmatūras un apakškomponentu specifikācija, tostarp saistīto Frontex galveno SAS sistēmu veidojošo programmatūras licenču skaits.</P><P>b) Piedāvājumā jāiekļauj tikai atjaunošanas maksa (renewal fee – RF).</P><P>B. Piedāvājums ar papildu SAS programmatūras licenču kopumiem Frontex galvenās SAS sistēmas papildināšanai, lai palielinātu tās apstrādes jaudu un/vai pieejamību.</P><P>a) Pretendentam ir jāpiedāvā tikai tehniski piemērojamie risinājumi.</P><P>b) Piedāvājumā jāiekļauj detalizēta SAS programmatūras un apakškomponentu specifikācija, tostarp saistīto plānotās apstrādes jaudas un/vai pieejamības palielinājuma sasniegšanai nepieciešamo programmatūras licenču skaits.</P><P>c) Pretendentam ir jāpiedāvā daži tehniski piemērojami varianti, kas ļauj palielināt apstrādes jaudu un/vai pieejamību par, piemēram: 10 %, 20 % un 50 %. Šie varianti ir skaidri jāapraksta un jāapzīmē tehniskajā piedāvājumā un finanšu piedāvājumā kā B1, B2 utt.</P><P>d) Piedāvājumā jāiekļauj abu veidu cenas: pirmā gada maksa (First Year Fee – FYF) un atjaunošanas maksa (Renewal Fee – RF).</P><P>e) Ja nepieciešams, piedāvājumā jāiekļauj attiecīgā uzstādīšanas pakalpojuma cena.</P><P>C. Piedāvājums, kas ietver papildu SAS programmatūras un tās apakškomponentu licenču kopumus Frontex galvenās SAS sistēmas paplašināšanai, ieviešot citus SAS programmatūras produktus, lai papildinātu pašreizējo Frontex SAS sistēmu ar papildu programmatūras moduļiem un saistītajiem apakškomponentiem, kas nodrošina labāku datu pārvaldību ar integrētu, uzņēmumu klases, modernu ETL rīku, kurš atbalsta izstrādi ar grafiskā lietotāja saskarni. Pretendentam ir jāpiedāvā programmatūras licenču kopumi:</P><P>i) SAS datu integrācijai;</P><P>ii) SAS datu kvalitātei.</P><P>Šie kopumi ir skaidri jāapraksta un jāapzīmē tehniskajā piedāvājumā un finanšu piedāvājumā kā C1, C2 utt.</P><P>a) Piedāvātajiem programmatūras licenču kopumiem pilnībā jāatbilst Frontex galvenajai SAS sistēmai, t.i., tiem ir jābūt tehniski piemērojamiem šai sistēmai.</P><P>b) Piedāvājumā jāiekļauj visu obligāto prasību/nosacījumu saraksts, kas ir jāizpilda, lai ieviestu paplašinājumu (piemēram, minimālās tehniskās prasības serveriem utt.).</P><P>c) Piedāvājumam jābūt piemērotam Frontex galvenajai SAS sistēmai tās apjoma un apstrādāto datu apjoma ziņā, kā arī jāatbilst tās mērķim.</P><P>d) Piedāvāto komponentu ieviešana, izvietošana un paredzamā ikdienas darba slodze nevar radīt negatīvu ietekmi uz esošo Frontex SAS sistēmas risinājumu efektivitāti (piemēram, reakcijas laiku, datu apstrādes veiktspēju, atmiņas ietilpību, ziņojumu pieejamību un interaktivitāti).</P><P>e) Piedāvātajam risinājumam būtu jāļauj pamatoti palielināt sistēmas izmantošanu iespējama palielināta datu apjoma, palielināta lietotāju skaita, jaunu sistēmas izmantošanas jomu un citu izmaiņu rezultātā.</P><P>f) Piedāvājumā īsi jāpamato piedāvāto komponentu izvēle, kā arī piedāvāto licenču skaits.</P><P>g) Piedāvājumā jāiekļauj detalizēta SAS programmatūras un apakškomponentu specifikācija, tostarp saistīto programmatūras licenču skaits, kas nepieciešamas Frontex galveno SAS sistēmu papildināšanai ar paredzēto funkcionalitāti.</P><P>h) Piedāvājumā jāiekļauj abu veidu cenas: pirmā gada maksa (First Year Fee – FYF) un atjaunošanas maksa (Renewal Fee – RF).</P><P>i) Ja nepieciešams, piedāvājumā jāiekļauj attiecīgā uzstādīšanas pakalpojuma cena.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Darbuzņēmēja kvalifikācija, kompetence, piemērotība un profesionālās prasmes, vispārējā tehniskā piedāvājuma skaidrība un precizitāte un mērķu izpratne.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Kopš pašiem Frontex pirmsākumiem riska analīze ir viena no galvenajām operatīvajām darbībām, kas kalpo par pamatu citām darbībām. Frontex veicamie ar riska analīzi saistītie uzdevumi tika noteikti pirmajā Frontex Regulā (EK) 2007/2004. Jaunajā Frontex regulā (ES) 2016/1624 ar riska analīzi saistītie uzdevumi ir pat paplašināti, salīdzinot ar iepriekšējo versiju. Frontex organizatoriskā struktūra nesen tika mainīta, un jauno prasību izpildei tika izveidota situācijas izpratnes un uzraudzības nodaļa.</P><P>SAS programmatūras loma un tās nozīme Frontex veiktajā riska analīzes procesā</P><P>SAS tehnoloģija ir Frontex veikto riska analīzes uzdevumu atbalsta instruments. SAS tehnoloģijas pirmoreiz tika ieviestas 2008. gadā. Kopš 2008. gada Frontex ir ieguldījusi ievērojamus laika resursus, cilvēkresursus un finanšu līdzekļus:</P><P>— SAS programmatūras licencēm un tās integrācijai Frontex arhitektūrā,</P><P>— specifiskai aparatūrai izmantotās SAS programmatūras prasību izpildei,</P><P>— apmācībām un semināriem, lai palīdzētu Frontex darbiniekiem iegūt atbilstošas zināšanas. Šobrīd Frontex ir uz SAS tehnoloģiju balstīts plašs zināšanu kopums.</P><P>Mūsdienās SAS tehnoloģija ir viens no riska analīzes procesa galvenajiem un nozīmīgajiem elementiem.</P><P>Iespējamai SAS tehnoloģijas aizstāšanai ar līdzvērtīgu tehnoloģiju būtu nepieciešams stratēģisks lēmums vairāku gadu ilga procesa uzsākšanai, kam būtu nepieciešami ievērojami finanšu un nefinanšu ieguldījumi, lai sasniegtu pašreizējam līdzīgu spēju gatavības līmeni. Šajā laika posmā uz SAS tehnoloģijām balstītie risinājumi vismaz būtu jāsaglabā.</P><P>SAS institūts un tā tirgus pozīcija</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. ir vienīgais SAS programmatūras ražotājs un izdevējs. SAS Institute Inc. pieder SAS programmatūras intelektuālā īpašuma tiesības. SAS Institute sp. z o.o. ir SAS Institute Inc. struktūrvienība, un tai ir ekskluzīvas tiesības piešķirt SAS programmatūras licences uzņēmumiem, kam piemērojams Publisko iepirkumu likums Polijā.</P><P>Iepirkuma procedūras izvēle</P><P>SAS programmatūras licenču iepirkuma procedūra būs sarunu procedūra bez iepriekšēja paziņojuma par līgumu publicēšanas saskaņā ar FR I. pielikuma 11. punkta 1) daļas b) apakšpunkta ii) un iii) punktu (iepriekš Piemērošanas noteikumu 134. panta 1) daļas b) apakšpunkta ii) un iii) punktu) tehnisku iemeslu un ekskluzīvo tiesību aizsardzības nepieciešamības dēļ. Tas nozīmē, ka līgumu var piešķirt tikai vienam konkrētam uzņēmējam. Iepriekš minētā procedūra tika izvēlēta ņemot vērā to, ka SAS institūts ir vienīgais licenču īpašnieks.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Pamatnolīgums par SAS programmatūras licenču iegādi</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Vispārējā tiesa</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Vispārējā tiesa</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Vispārējā tiesa</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="MT"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — L-Aġenzija Ewropea għall-Gwardja tal-Fruntiera u tal-Kosta</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Qafas ta' Kuntratt għall-ksib ta' liċenzji tas-softwer SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>L-għan ta' dan il-Kuntratt hu li jitwaqqaf mezz ta' ksib f'forma ta' Qafas ta' Kuntratt li jippermetti x-xiri ta' liċenzji tas-Softwer SAS:</P><P>1) sabiex jiġġedded u jinżamm is-sett ta' liċenzji tas-Softwer SAS li jintuża fi Frontex;</P><P>2) sabiex jiġi estiż, b'mod fakultattiv, is-sett ta' liċenzji tas-Softwer SAS li jintuża fi Frontex billi:</P><P>(a) Jinxtraw iktar liċenzji għall-prodotti li qed jintużaw u/jew</P><P>(b) Jinxtraw liċenzji għal prodotti oħra tas-Softwer SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, IL-POLONJA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Is-suġġett ta' dan il-Kuntratt hu l-provvista ta' liċenzji tas-Softwer SAS taħt QTK.</P><P>Dak li jitfa' l-offerta ntalab jipprovdi s-servizzi u l-provvisti li ġejjin:</P><P>A. Tariffa ta' tiġdid (RF) għal-liċenzji ewlenin tas-sistema SAS tal-Frontex</P><P>(a) Il-proposta għandha tinkludi speċifikazzjoni ddettaljata tas-Softwer SAS u komponenti sekondarji inkluż in-numru ta' liċenzji tas-softwer relatati li jiffurmaw is-sistema SAS ewlenija tal-Frontex.</P><P>(b) Il-proposta għandha tinkludi Tariffa ta' Tiġdid (RF) biss.</P><P>B. Proposta li fiha settijiet addizzjonali ta' liċenzji tas-Softwer SAS biex tiġi ssupplimentata s-sistema SAS ewlenija tal-Frontex sabiex tiżdied il-kapaċità u/jew id-disponibbiltà tal-ipproċessar tagħha.</P><P>(a) Dak li jitfa' l-offerta jintalab jipproponi s-soluzzjonijiet teknikament applikabbli biss.</P><P>(b) Il-proposta għandha tinkludi speċifikazzjoni ddettaljata tas-Softwer SAS u komponenti sekondarji inkluż in-numru ta' liċenzji tas-softwer relatati li huma meħtieġa biex tinkiseb iż-żieda ppjanata ta' kapaċità u/jew disponibbiltà ta' pproċessar.</P><P>(c) Dak li jitfa' l-offerta jintalab jipproponi ftit varjanti teknikament applikabbli li jippermettu żieda ta' kapaċità u/jew disponibbiltà ta' pproċessar pereżempju bi: 10 %, 20 % u 50 %. Il-varjanti għandhom ikunu deskritti u mmarkati b'mod ċar fil-proposta teknika u fil-proposta finanzjarja bħala B1, B2, eċċ.</P><P>(d) Il-proposta għandha tinkludi ż-żewġ tipi ta' prezzijiet: it-Tariffa tal-Ewwel Sena (FYF) u t-Tariffa ta' Tiġdid (RF).</P><P>(e) Jekk meħtieġ, il-proposta għandha tinkludi prezz ta' servizz ta' installazzjoni rilevanti.</P><P>C. Proposta li fiha settijiet addizzjonali ta' liċenzji għas-softwer SAS u l-komponenti sekondarji tagħhom, sabiex tiġi estiża s-sistema SAS ewlenija tal-Frontex billi jiġu introdotti prodotti oħra tas-Softwer SAS u sabiex tiġi estiża s-sistema SAS ewlenija tal-Frontex b'moduli tas-softwer addizzjonali u l-komponenti sekondarji relatati li jippermettu governanza tad-dejta aħjar permezz ta' għodda ETL integrata, fil-livell ta' intrapriża u moderna li tappoġġa l-iżvilupp ibbażat fuq il-GUI. Dak li jitfa' offerta jintalab jipproponi settijiet ta' liċenzji ta' softwer għal:</P><P>(i) Integrazzjoni tad-Dejta SAS</P><P>(ii) Kwalità tad-Dejta SAS</P><P>Is-settijiet għandhom ikunu deskritti u mmarkati b'mod ċar fil-proposta teknika u fil-proposta finanzjarja bħala C1 u C2.</P><P>(a) Is-settijiet proposti tal-liċenzji ta' softwer għandhom jikkonformaw b'mod sħiħ mas-sistema SAS ewlenija tal-Frontex i.e. għandhom ikunu teknikament applikabbli għal din is-sistema.</P><P>(b) Il-proposta għandha tinkludi lista tar-rekwiżiti/tal-kundizzjonijiet obbligatorji kollha li jridu jintlaħqu sabiex tiġi implimentata estensjoni (eż. rekwiżiti tekniċi minimi għal servers, eċċ.).</P><P>(c) Il-proposta għandha tkun xierqa għas-sistema SAS ewlenija tal-Frontex fit-termini tal-iskala tagħha u l-ammonti ta' dejta pproċessati kif ukoll biex tilħaq l-għan tagħha.</P><P>(d) L-implimentazzjoni, l-iskjerament u t-tagħbija mistennija ta' kuljum tal-komponenti proposti ma jistgħux jintroduċu impatt negattiv fuq l-effettività eżistenti tas-soluzzjonijiet tas-sistema SAS tal-Frontex (eż. ħinijiet ta' reazzjoni, prestazzjoni tal-ipproċessar tad-dejta, kapaċità ta' ħżin, aċċessibbiltà u interattività tar-rapporti).</P><P>(e) Is-soluzzjonijiet proposti għandhom jippermettu tkabbir ġustifikat tal-użu tas-sistema minħabba l-volum potenzjalment miżjud ta' dejta, numru miżjud ta' utenti, oqsma ġodda ta' applikazzjoni tas-sistema, eċċ.</P><P>(f) L-għażla tal-komponenti proposti kif ukoll in-numru propost ta' liċenzji għandha tkun ġġustifikata fil-qosor fil-proposta.</P><P>(g) Il-proposta għandha tinkludi speċifikazzjoni ddettaljata tas-Softwer SAS u komponenti sekondarji inkluż in-numru ta' liċenzji tas-softwer relatati li huma meħtieġa biex tiġi estiża s-sistema SAS ewlenija tal-Frontex bil-funzjonalità maħsuba.</P><P>(h) Il-proposta għandha tinkludi ż-żewġ tipi ta' prezzijiet: it-Tariffa tal-Ewwel Sena (FYF) u t-Tariffa ta' Tiġdid (RF).</P><P>(i) Jekk meħtieġ, il-proposta għandha tinkludi prezz ta' servizz ta' installazzjoni rilevanti.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Il-kwalifiki, l-għarfien, l-adegwatezza u l-kompetenzi professjonali tal-Kuntrattur, iċ-ċarezza u l-qosor tal-proposta teknika globali u l-fehim tal-għanijiet.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Mill-bidu nett tal-Frontex, l-analiżi tar-riskju hija waħda mill-attivitajiet operattivi ewlenin li jiffurmaw il-bażi għal attivitajiet oħra. Ix-xogħlijiet relatati mal-analiżi tar-riskju, li jridu jitwettqu mill-Frontex, ġew iddefinit fl-ewwel Regolament (KE) 2007/2004 dwar il-Frontex. Fir-Regolament (UE) 2016/1624 il-ġdid dwar il-Frontex, ix-xogħlijiet relatati mal-analiżi tar-riskju huma estiżi wkoll meta mqabbla mal-istat preċedenti. L-istruttura organizzazzjonali tal-Frontex nbidlet reċentement u nħolqot id-Diviżjoni għall-Għarfien dwar is-Sitwazzjoni u l-Monitoraġġ sabiex jintlaħqu r-rekwiżiti l-ġodda.</P><P>Ir-rwol tas-Softwer SAS u l-importanza tiegħu għall-proċess ta' analiżi tar-riskju fi Frontex</P><P>It-teknoloġija SAS hija l-għodda li tappoġġja x-xogħlijiet ta' analiżi tar-riskju fi Frontex. L-ewwel implimentazzjoni tat-teknoloġija SAS saret fl-2008. Mill-2008 Frontex investiet ammont sinifikanti ta' riżorsi f'termini ta' ħin, riżorsi umani u mezzi finanzjarji għal:</P><P>— Liċenzji tas-Softwer SAS u l-integrazzjoni tiegħu fl-arkitettura tal-Frontex,</P><P>— Ħardwer speċifiku sabiex jintlaħqu r-rekwiżiti tas-Softwer SAS użat,</P><P>— Taħriġ u sessjonijiet ta' ħidma li twettqu biex jiġi faċilitat għall-persunal ta' Frontex il-ksib tal-għarfien xieraq. Issa hemm korp sostanzjali ta' għarfien stabbilit fi Frontex ibbażat fuq it-teknoloġija SAS.</P><P>Illum il-ġurnata, it-teknoloġija SAS hija waħda mill-komponenti ewlenin u kritiċi tal-proċess ta' analiżi tar-riskju.</P><P>It-tibdil potenzjali tat-teknoloġija SAS għal teknoloġija ekwivalenti jeħtieġ deċiżjoni strateġika sabiex jinbeda proċess li jdum bosta snin u li jeħtieġ investimenti finanzjarji u mhux finanzjarji sinifikanti sabiex jintlaħaq livell ta' maturità simili għal dak attwali. Matul dan il-perijodu, jeħtieġ li s-soluzzjonijiet ibbażati fuq it-teknoloġija SAS jiġu tal-anqas mantnuti.</P><P>SAS Institute u l-pożizzjoni tiegħu fis-suq.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. huwa l-uniku manifattur u pubblikatur tas-Softwer SAS. SAS Institute Inc. huwa s-sid tad-drittijiet ta' proprjetà intellettwali tas-Softwer SAS. SAS Institute sp. z o.o. kumpanija sussidjarja ta' SAS Institute Inc., għandha d-dritt esklussiv li tagħti liċenzji għas-Softwer SAS għall-benefiċċju tal-entitajiet obbligati li jużaw il-Liġi dwar il-Ksib Pubbliku fil-Polonja.</P><P>L-għażla tal-proċedura tal-ksib.</P><P>Il-proċedura tal-ksib għal-liċenzji tas-Softwer SAS se tkun proċedura nnegozjata mingħajr pubblikazzjoni minn qabel ta' avviż dwar kuntratt skont il-Punt 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) tal-Anness I FR (preċedentement l-Art. 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) RAP), minħabba l-eżistenza ta' raġunijiet tekniċi u l-ħtieġa ta' protezzjoni tad-drittijiet esklussivi. Għalhekk il-kuntratt jista' jingħata biss lil operatur ekonomiku partikolari wieħed. Minħabba l-fatt li SAS Institute huwa l-uniku sid tal-liċenzji, intgħażlet il-proċedura msemmija hawn fuq.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Qafas ta' Kuntratt għall-ksib ta' liċenzji tas-softwer SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Il-Qorti Ġenerali</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Il-Qorti Ġenerali</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Il-Qorti Ġenerali</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="PL"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Europejska Agencja Straży Granicznej i Przybrzeżnej</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Umowa ramowa o zakup licencji oprogramowania SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Przedmiotem niniejszego zamówienia jest stworzenie kanału nabywczego w formie umowy ramowej umożliwiającej za kup licencji oprogramowania SAS:</P><P>1) w celu odnowienia i utrzymania zestawu licencji oprogramowania używanego przez Frontex;</P><P>2) w celu ewentualnego rozszerzenia zestawu licencji oprogramowania SAS używanego przez Frontex poprzez:</P><P>a) zakup większej liczby nowych licencji będących w użyciu; i/lub</P><P>b) zakup licencji na inne produkty SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLAND</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Celem niniejszego zamówienia jest zapewnienie licencji oprogramowania SAS w ramach umowy ramowej.</P><P>Od oferenta oczekuje się zapewnienia następujących usług i dostaw:</P><P>A. Opłata za przedłużenie głównych licencji systemu SAS</P><P>a) oferta musi zawierać szczegółową specyfikację oprogramowania SAS i jego komponentów, w tym szereg powiązanych licencji, które składają się na główny system SAS Fronteksu.</P><P>b) oferta musi zawierać tylko opłatę za przedłużenie.</P><P>B. Oferta na dodatkowy zestaw licencji oprogramowania SAS, uzupełniających główny system SAS Fronteksu w celu zwiększenia jego wydajności i/lub dostępności.</P><P>a) Oferentów uprasza się o przedstawianie wyłącznie rozwiązań odpowiednich technicznie.</P><P>b) Oferta musi zawierać szczegółową specyfikację oprogramowania SAS i jego składowych, w tym szereg powiązanych licencji oprogramowania, niezbędnych do osiągnięcia planowanego wzrostu wydajności i/lub dostępności systemu.</P><P>c) Oczekuje się, że oferent zaproponuje kilka wariantów wykonalnych pod względem technicznym, które umożliwią wzrost wydajności i/lub dostępności, o np.: 10 %, 20 % i 50 %. Warianty muszą być przejrzyście opisane i zaznaczone w ofercie technicznej i w ofercie finansowej jako B1, B2 itd.</P><P>d) Oferta musi zawierać 2 rodzaje cen: opłata za pierwszy rok i opłata za odnowienie.</P><P>e) Jeśli konieczna jest usługa instalacji, to oferta musi zawierać jej wycenę.</P><P>C. Oferta na dodatkowy zestaw licencji oprogramowania SAS i jego składowych, w celu rozszerzenia głównych systemów SAS Fronteksu poprzez wprowadzenie innych produktów oprogramowania SAS w celu rozszerzenia obecnego głównego systemu SAS o dodatkowe moduły oprogramowania i powiązane komponenty umożliwiające poprawę zarządzania dzięki zintegrowanemu nowoczesnemu narzędziu ETL klasy korporacyjnej, wspierającemu rozwój interfejsu graficznego użytkownika. Oferent powinien zaproponować zestawy licencji oprogramowania w zakresie:</P><P>i) integracji danych SAS,</P><P>ii) jakości danych SAS.</P><P>Zestawy muszą być jasno opisane i zaznaczone w ofercie technicznej i w ofercie finansowej jako C1, C2 itd.</P><P>a) Proponowane zestawy licencji oprogramowania muszą być w pełni zgodne z głównym systemem Fronteksu, tj. muszą być technicznie możliwe do zastosowania w tym systemie.</P><P>b) Oferta musi zawierać listę wszystkich wymagań lub warunków, które muszą zostać spełnione, aby można było wprowadzić rozszerzenie (np. minimalne wymagania dotyczące serwerów itp.).</P><P>c) Oferta musi odpowiadać głównemu systemowi SAS Fronteksu w zakresie skali i ilości przetwarzanych danych oraz musi być zgodna z jego przeznaczeniem.</P><P>d) Wdrażanie, rozmieszczenie i oczekiwane dzienne obciążenie proponowanych komponentów nie może wpływać negatywnie na wydajność istniejących rozwiązań systemu SAS Fronteksu (np. czasy odpowiedzi, wydajność w zakresie przetwarzania danych, pojemność magazynowa, dostępność i interaktywność raportów).</P><P>e) Proponowane rozwiązanie musi prowadzić do uzasadnionego wzrostu wykorzystania systemu dzięki potencjalnemu zwiększeniu ilości danych, liczby użytkowników, wprowadzeniu nowych obszarów zastosowania itp.</P><P>f) proponowany wybór komponentów i liczba proponowanych licencji muszą zostać pokrótce uzasadnione w ofercie.</P><P>g) Oferta musi zawierać szczegółową specyfikację oprogramowania SAS i jego komponentów, w tym liczbę powiązanych licencji oprogramowania, wymaganych do rozszerzenia głównego systemu SAS Fronteksu za pomocą planowanej funkcjonalności.</P><P>h) Oferta musi zawierać 2 rodzaje cen: opłata za pierwszy rok i opłata za odnowienie.</P><P>i) Jeśli konieczna jest usługa instalacji, to oferta musi zawierać jej wycenę.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>kwalifikacje, wiedza fachowa, stosowność i kompetencje zawodowe wykonawcy, przejrzystość i zwięzłość ogólnej oferty technicznej oraz zrozumienie celów</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Od początków istnienia Fronteksu analiza ryzyka jest jednym z kluczowych działań, stanowiąc podstawę dla innej działalności. Zadania związane z analizą danych, które ma wykonywać Fronteks, zostały określone w pierwszym rozporządzeniu w sprawie Fronteksu (WE) 2007/2004. W nowym rozporządzeniu w sprawie Fronteksu (UE) 2016/1624 zadania związane z analizą danych zostały jeszcze rozszerzone w stosunku do stanu poprzedniego. Niedawno zmieniła się struktura organizacyjna Fronteksu; aby spełnić nowe wymagania, utworzono Dział ds. Świadomości Sytuacyjnej i Monitorowania.</P><P>Rola oprogramowania SAS i jego znaczenie w procesie analizy ryzyka prowadzonej przez Fronteks</P><P>Technologia SAS to narzędzie wspierające zadania analizy ryzyka we Fronteksie. Po raz pierwszy technologię SAS wdrożono w 2008 roku. Od 2008 roku Fronteks przeznaczył znaczne zasoby czasowe i finansowe, a także zasoby ludzkie na:</P><P>— licencje oprogramowania SAS i jego integrację z architekturą Fronteksu,</P><P>— specjalne urządzenia informatyczne w celu spełnienia wymagań użytkowanego oprogramowania SAS,</P><P>— szkolenia i warsztaty przeprowadzone w celu umożliwienia pracownikom Fronteksu nabycie stosownej wiedzy. We Fronteksie na technologii SAS bazuje znaczne kompendium wiedzy.</P><P>Dziś technologia SAS jest jednym z głównych i krytycznych elementów procesu analizy ryzyka.</P><P>Potencjalne zastąpienie technologii SAS równorzędną technologią wymagałoby podjęcia strategicznej decyzji inicjującej proces, który trwałby wiele lat i mógłby wymagać znacznych nakładów finansowych i niefinansowych w celu osiągnięcia stopnia dojrzałości podobnego do takiego, na jakim znajduje się obecna technologia. W tym czasie rozwiązania oparte na technologii SAS wymagałyby przynajmniej utrzymywania.</P><P>SAS Institute i jego pozycja na rynku.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. jest jedynym producentem i wydawcą oprogramowania SAS. SAS Institute Inc. jest właścicielem praw intelektualnych do oprogramowania SAS. SAS Institute sp. z o.o., spółka zależna SAS Institute Inc., ma wyłączne prawa do udzielania licencji oprogramowania SAS na rzecz podmiotów, które udzielają zamówień na podstawie polskiego Prawa zamówień publicznych.</P><P>Wybór procedury przetargowej.</P><P>Procedura przetargowa dotycząca licencji oprogramowania SAS będzie procedurą negocjacyjną bez wcześniejszej publikacji ogłoszenia o zamówieniu zgodnie z pkt 11 ust. 1 lit. b) ppkt i) oraz iii) załącznika I do rozporządzenia finansowego (wcześniej art. 134 ust. 1 lit. b) ppkt ii) oraz iii) zasada stosowania, z powodów technicznych i przez wzgląd na ochronę praw wyłącznych. W związku z tym umowa może zostać przyznana tylko jednemu podmiotowi gospodarczemu. Wybrano tę procedurę, ponieważ SAS Institute jest jedynym właścicielem licencji.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Umowa ramowa o zakup licencji oprogramowania SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Sąd</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Sąd</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Sąd</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="SK"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Európska agentúra pre pohraničnú a pobrežnú stráž</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Rámcová zmluva na obstaranie softvérových licencií SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Predmetom tejto zmluvy je vytvorenie kanála na obstaranie softvéru vo forme rámcovej zmluvy umožňujúceho zakúpenie licencií na softvér SAS:</P><P>1) s cieľom obnoviť a udržiavať súbor licencií softvéru SAS, ktorý sa používa v agentúre Frontex,</P><P>2) s možnosťou rozšírenia súboru licencií softvéru SAS, ktoré sa používajú v agentúre Frontex:</P><P>a) nadobudnutie ďalších licencií na používanie produktov a/alebo</P><P>b) nákupné licencie na ďalšie softvérové ​​produkty spoločnosti SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POĽSKO</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Predmetom tejto zmluvy je poskytnutie licencií na softvér SAS v rámci rámcovej zmluvy.</P><P>Od uchádzača sa požadovalo poskytnutie týchto služieb a dodávok:</P><P>A. Poplatok za obnovenie pre základné licencie systému SAS agentúry Frontex</P><P>a) Návrh musí obsahovať podrobnú špecifikáciu softvéru SAS a jeho podzložiek vrátane počtu súvisiacich softvérových licencií, ktoré tvoria základný systém SAS agentúry Frontex.</P><P>b) Návrh obsahuje iba poplatok za obnovenie.</P><P>B. Návrh obsahujúci dodatočné súbory licencií softvéru SAS na doplnenie základného systému SAS agentúry Frontex s cieľom zvýšiť jeho spracovateľskú kapacitu a/alebo dostupnosť.</P><P>a) Od uchádzača sa požaduje, aby navrhol len technicky použiteľné riešenia.</P><P>a) Návrh musí obsahovať podrobnú špecifikáciu softvéru SAS a jeho podzložiek vrátane počtu súvisiacich softvérových licencií, ktoré sú potrebné na dosiahnutie plánovaného zvýšenia spracovateľskej kapacity a/alebo dostupnosti.</P><P>c) Od uchádzača sa požaduje, aby navrhol niekoľko technicky uplatniteľných variantov umožňujúcich zvýšenie výrobnej kapacity a/alebo dostupnosti napr. o: 10 %, 20 % a 50 %. Varianty by mali byť jasne opísané a označené v technickom návrhu a vo finančnom návrhu ako B1 a B2 atď.</P><P>d) Návrh musí obsahovať oba typy cien: Poplatok za prvý rok a poplatok za obnovenie.</P><P>e) Ak je to potrebné, návrh by mal obsahovať cenu príslušnej inštalačnej služby.</P><P>C. Návrh obsahujúci dodatočné súbory licencií na softvér SAS a jeho podzložky s cieľom rozšíriť základný systém SAS agentúry Frontex zavedením ďalších softvérových produktov SAS s cieľom rozšíriť súčasný základný systém SAS agentúry Frontex o ďalšie softvérové ​​moduly a súvisiace podzložky umožňujúce lepšie riadenie údajov prostredníctvom integrovaného, komerčného, moderného nástroja ETL, ktorý podporuje vývoj na základe grafického rozhrania. Od uchádzača sa žiada, aby navrhol súbory softvérových licencií pre:</P><P>i) integráciu údajov SAS,</P><P>ii) kvalitu údajov SAS.</P><P>Súbory by mali byť jasne opísané a označené v technickom návrhu a vo finančnom návrhu ako C1 a C2.</P><P>a) Navrhované súbory softvérových licencií musia byť v plnom súlade s hlavným systémom SAS agentúry Frontex, t. j. musia byť technicky použiteľné pre tento systém.</P><P>b) Návrh musí obsahovať zoznam všetkých povinných požiadaviek/podmienok, ktoré musia byť splnené na realizáciu rozšírenia (napríklad minimálne technické požiadavky na servery atď.).</P><P>c) Návrh musí zodpovedať hlavnému systému SAS agentúry Frontex z hľadiska rozsahu a objemu spracovaných údajov ako aj účelu použitia.</P><P>d) Uplatnenie navrhovaných komponentov, zavedenie a očakávané denné pracovné zaťaženie nemôže mať negatívny vplyv na existujúcu účinnosť systémových riešení systému SAS agentúry Frontex (napríklad reakčné časy, výkonnosť spracovania údajov, kapacita pamäte, prístupnosť správ a interaktivita).</P><P>e) Navrhované riešenie by malo umožniť oprávnený nárast využívania systému v dôsledku potenciálneho zvýšenia objemu údajov, zvýšenia počtu používateľov, nových oblastí využitia systému atď.</P><P>f) Navrhovaný výber komponentov ako aj navrhovaný počet licencií sú v návrhu stručne odôvodnené.</P><P>a) Návrh musí obsahovať podrobnú špecifikáciu softvéru SAS a jeho podzložiek vrátane počtu súvisiacich softvérových licencií, ktoré sú potrebné na rozšírenie hlavného systému SAS agentúry Frontex o zamýšľanú funkciu.</P><P>h) Návrh musí obsahovať oba typy cien: Poplatok za prvý rok a poplatok za obnovenie.</P><P>i) Ak je to potrebné, návrh by mal obsahovať cenu príslušnej inštalačnej služby.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Kvalifikácia, odbornosť, vhodnosť a odborná spôsobilosť dodávateľa, jasnosť a zrozumiteľnosť celkového technického návrhu a pochopenie cieľov.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Od samotného začiatku činnosti agentúry Frontex je analýza rizík jednou z kľúčových prevádzkových činností, ktoré tvoria základ pre ďalšie činnosti. Úlohy súvisiace s analýzou rizík, ktoré má vykonať agentúra Frontex, boli vymedzené v prvom nariadení (ES) 2007/2004 o agentúre Frontex. V novom nariadení o agentúre Frontex (EÚ) 2016/1624 budú úlohy spojené s analýzou rizík v porovnaní s predchádzajúcim stavom dokonca rozšírené. Organizačná štruktúra agentúry Frontex bola nedávno zmenená a s cieľom splniť nové požiadavky bol vytvorený Oddiel situačného povedomia a monitorovania.</P><P>Úloha softvéru SAS a jeho význam pre proces analýzy rizík v agentúre Frontex</P><P>Technológia SAS je nástroj, ktorý podporuje úlohy analýzy rizík v agentúre Frontex. Technológia SAS bola prvýkrát uplatnená v roku 2008. Od roku 2008 investovala agentúra Frontex značné množstvo zdrojov z hľadiska času, ľudských zdrojov a finančných prostriedkov do:</P><P>– softvérových ​​licencií SAS a ich integrácie do štruktúry agentúry Frontex,</P><P>– konkrétneho hardvéru s cieľom splniť požiadavky používaného softvéru SAS,</P><P>– školení a workshopov, ktoré sa uskutočnili s cieľom uľahčiť zamestnancom agentúry Frontex získať príslušné znalosti. Momentálne je značná časť znalostí zavedených v agentúre Frontex založená na technológii SAS.</P><P>V súčasnosti je technológia SAS jednou z kľúčových a rozhodujúcich prvkov procesu analýzy rizík.</P><P>Potenciálna náhrada technológie SAS za rovnocennú technológiu by si vyžadovala strategické rozhodnutie s cieľom začať proces, ktorý by trval niekoľko rokov a vyžadoval by významné finančné a nefinančné investície, aby bola dosiahnutá úroveň splatnosti podobná tej súčasnej. Počas tohto obdobia by riešenia založené na technológii SAS museli byť aspoň udržiavané.</P><P>Inštitút SAS a jeho postavenie na trhu.</P><P>Spoločnosť SAS Institute Inc. je jediným výrobcom a vydavateľom softvéru SAS. Spoločnosť SAS Institute Inc. je vlastníkom práv duševného vlastníctva týkajúcich softvéru SAS. SAS Institute sp. z o.o., dcérska spoločnosť spoločnosti SAS Institute Inc., má výlučné právo udeľovať licencie softvéru SAS v prospech subjektov, ktoré sú povinné uplatňovať zákon o verejnom obstarávaní v Poľsku.</P><P>Výber obstarávacieho konania.</P><P>Obstarávacie konanie pre softvérové licencie SAS bude rokovacím konaním bez predchádzajúceho zverejnenia oznámenia o vyhlásení verejného obstarávania v súlade s bodom 11 ods. 1 písm. b) bodmi ii), iii) prílohy I nariadenia o rozpočtových pravidlách (predtým čl. 134 ods. 1 písm. b) bod ii), (iii) pravidiel uplatňovania) z technických dôvodov a z dôvodu potreby ochrany výhradných práv. Zmluva teda môže byť udelená iba jednému konkrétnemu hospodárskemu subjektu. Vzhľadom na skutočnosť, že spoločnosť SAS Institute je jediným vlastníkom licencií, bol zvolený vyššie uvedený postup.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Rámcová zmluva na obstaranie softvérových licencií SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Všeobecný súd</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Všeobecný súd</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Všeobecný súd</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="SL"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Evropska agencija za mejno in obalno stražo</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Okvirno naročilo za nakup licenc za programsko opremo SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>To naročilo zajema vzpostavitev nabavnega kanala v obliki okvirne pogodbe za nakup licenc za programsko opremo SAS:</P><P>(1) da bi podaljšali in vzdrževali sklop licenc za programsko opremo SAS, ki se uporablja na agenciji Frontex;</P><P>(2) da bi po potrebi razširili sklop licenc za programsko opremo SAS, ki se uporablja na agenciji Frontex, in sicer z:</P><P>(a) nakupom več licenc za izdelke, ki se uporabljajo, in/ali</P><P>(b) nakupom licenc za druge programske izdelke SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLJSKA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Predmet tega naročila je zagotovitev licenc za programsko opremo SAS na podlagi okvirnega naročila.</P><P>Ponudnik je moral zagotoviti naslednje storitve in blago:</P><P>A. Pristojbina za podaljšanje licenc za osnovni sistem SAS agencije Frontex</P><P>(a) Ponudba mora vsebovati podrobne specifikacije programske opreme SAS in njenih podkomponent, vključno s številom povezanih licenc za programsko opremo, ki sestavljajo osnovni sistem SAS agencije Frontex.</P><P>(b) Ponudba mora vsebovati samo pristojbino za podaljšanje.</P><P>B. Ponudba, ki vsebuje dodatne sklope licenc za programsko opremo SAS, da bi dopolnili osnovni sistem SAS agencije Frontex in povečali njegovo zmogljivost obdelave in/ali razpoložljivost.</P><P>(a) Ponudnik mora predlagati samo tehnično uporabne rešitve.</P><P>(b) Ponudba mora vsebovati podrobne specifikacije programske opreme SAS in njenih podkomponent, vključno s številom povezanih licenc, ki so potrebne za doseganje načrtovanega povečanja zmogljivosti obdelave in/ali razpoložljivosti.</P><P>(c) Ponudnik mora predlagati nekaj tehnično uporabnih različic, ki omogočajo povečanje zmogljivosti obdelave in/ali razpoložljivosti, npr. za: 10 %, 20 % in 50 %. Različice je treba podrobno opisati ter jih v tehnični in finančni ponudbi označiti kot B1, B2 itd.</P><P>(d) Ponudba mora vsebovati oba tipa cen: pristojbino za prvo leto in pristojbino za podaljšanje.</P><P>(e) Ponudba mora po potrebi vsebovati ceno ustrezne storitve za namestitev.</P><P>C. Ponudba, ki vsebuje dodatne sklope licenc za programsko opremo SAS in njene podkomponente, da bi razširili osnovni sistem SAS agencije Frontex z uvedbo drugih programskih izdelkov SAS ter dodatnimi programskimi moduli in povezanimi podkomponentami, kar bi omogočilo boljše upravljanje podatkov s sodobnim integriranim orodjem za zajemanje, obdelavo in polnjenje podatkov (extract, transform, load – ETL), ki je namenjeno podjetjem in podpira razvoj, ki temelji na uporabniškem grafičnem vmesniku (graphical user interface – GUI). Ponudnik mora predlagati sklope licenc za programsko opremo za:</P><P>(i) integracijo podatkov SAS;</P><P>(ii) kakovost podatkov SAS.</P><P>Sklope je treba podrobno opisati ter jih v tehnični in finančni ponudbi označiti kot C1 in C2.</P><P>(a) Predlagani sklopi licenc za programsko opremo morajo biti popolnoma skladni z osnovnim sistemom SAS agencije Frontex, kar pomeni, da morajo biti tehnično uporabni v sistemu.</P><P>(b) Ponudba mora vsebovati seznam vseh obveznih zahtev/pogojev, ki jih je treba izpolniti za razširitev (npr. minimalne tehnične zahteve za strežnike itd.).</P><P>(c) Ponudba mora ustrezati svojemu namenu in osnovnemu sistemu SAS agencije Frontex v smislu njegovega obsega in količine obdelanih podatkov.</P><P>(d) Uvedba in uporaba predlaganih komponent ter povezana dnevna delovna obremenitev ne smejo negativno vplivati na učinkovitost obstoječih rešitev za sistem SAS agencije Frontex (npr. na odzivne čase, zmogljivost obdelave podatkov, zmogljivost shranjevanja, dostopnost in interaktivnost poročil).</P><P>(e) Predlagana rešitev mora omogočati utemeljeno večje izkoriščanje sistema zaradi morebitnega povečanja količine podatkov, večjega števila uporabnikov, novih področij uporabe sistema itd.</P><P>(f) V ponudbi je treba na kratko utemeljiti predlagan izbor komponent in predlagano število licenc.</P><P>(g) Ponudba mora vsebovati podrobne specifikacije programske opreme SAS in njenih podkomponent, vključno s številom povezanih licenc za programsko opremo, ki so potrebne za razširitev osnovnega sistema SAS agencije Frontex s predvideno funkcijo.</P><P>(h) Ponudba mora vsebovati oba tipa cen: pristojbino za prvo leto in pristojbino za podaljšanje.</P><P>(i) Ponudba mora po potrebi vsebovati ceno ustrezne storitve za namestitev.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Kvalifikacije, strokovno znanje, ustreznost in strokovne kompetence izvajalca, jasnost in jedrnatost celotne tehnične ponudbe ter razumevanje ciljev.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Analiza tveganja je že od začetka delovanja agencije Frontex ena od ključnih operativnih dejavnosti, ki tvorijo podlago za druge dejavnosti. Naloge, ki so povezane z analizo tveganja in jih mora izvajati agencija Frontex, so bile opredeljene v prvi uredbi o ustanovitvi agencije, tj. v Uredbi (ES) št. 2007/2004. V novi uredbi o agenciji Frontex, in sicer v Uredbi (EU) št. 2016/1624, so naloge, povezane z analizo tveganja, celo razširjene v primerjavi s prejšnjim stanjem. Organizacijska struktura agencije Frontex se je nedavno spremenila in ustanovljena je bila enota za situacijsko zavedanje in spremljanje, ki bo izpolnjevala nove zahteve.</P><P>Vloga programske opreme SAS in njen pomen za proces analize tveganja na agenciji Frontex</P><P>Tehnologija SAS je orodje, ki na agenciji Frontex podpira naloge analize tveganja. Tehnologija SAS se je prvič uporabila leta 2008. Agencija Frontex je od leta 2008 veliko časa, človeških virov in finančnih sredstev vložila v:</P><P>— licence za programsko opremo SAS in njeno integracijo v arhitekturo agencije Frontex,</P><P>— specifično strojno opremo, da bi izpolnil zahteve uporabljene programske opreme SAS,</P><P>— usposabljanja in delavnice, ki so se izvajali z namenom ustreznega izobraževanja osebja agencije Frontex. Na agenciji Frontex trenutno obstaja znatna količina znanja, pridobljenega na podlagi tehnologije SAS.</P><P>Tehnologija SAS je danes ena od osnovnih in ključnih komponent procesa analize tveganja.</P><P>Za morebitno menjavo tehnologije SAS z enakovredno tehnologijo bi bila potrebna strateška odločitev o sprožitvi postopka, ki bi trajal več let in za katerega bi bile potrebne znatne finančne in nefinančne naložbe, da bi dosegli zrelost, podobno trenutni. V tem obdobju bi bilo treba vsaj vzdrževati rešitve, ki temeljijo na tehnologiji SAS.</P><P>SAS Institute in njegov tržni položaj</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. je edini proizvajalec in izdajatelj programske opreme SAS. SAS Institute Inc. je lastnik pravic intelektualne lastnine za programsko opremo SAS. SAS Institute sp. z o.o. je odvisno podjetje družbe SAS Institute Inc. in ima izključno pravico do podeljevanja licenc za programsko opremo SAS subjektom, ki morajo spoštovati zakonodajo o javnem naročanju na Poljskem.</P><P>Izbira razpisnega postopka</P><P>Razpisni postopek za licence za programsko opremo SAS bo postopek s pogajanju brez predhodne objave obvestila o naročilu v skladu s točko 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) Priloge I k finančni uredbi (prej člen 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) pravil uporabe), in sicer zaradi tehničnih razlogov in potrebe po zaščiti izključnih pravic. Tako se lahko naročilo odda samo določenemu gospodarskemu subjektu. Glede na to, da je SAS Institute edini lastnik licenc, je bil izbran zgoraj navedeni postopek.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Okvirno naročilo za nakup licenc za programsko opremo SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Splošno sodišče</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Splošno sodišče</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Splošno sodišče</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="GA"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — an Ghníomhaireacht Eorpach um an nGarda Teorann agus Cósta</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Creatchonradh le haghaidh ceadúnas bogearraí SAS a fháil</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Is é ábhar an Chonartha seo é bealach fála a chur ar bun trí Chreatchonradh ina gcumasaítear ceadúnais bogearraí SAS a cheannach:</P><P>1) d’fhonn an tsraith ceadúnas bogearraí SAS atá in úsáid ag Frontex a athnuachan agus a chothabháil;</P><P>2) d’fhonn an tsraith ceadúnas bogearraí SAS atá in úsáid ag Frontex a leathnú ar bhonn roghnach tríd an méid a leanas:</P><P>(a) Breis ceadúnas a cheannach do tháirgí atá in úsáid agus/nó</P><P>(b) Ceadúnais a cheannach do tháirgí eile bogearraí SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, AN PHOLAINN</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Is é ábhar an chonartha seo é ceadúnais bogearraí SAS a sholáthar faoi chreatchonradh.</P><P>Iarradh ar an tairgeoir na seirbhísí agus na soláthairtí a leanas a sholáthar:</P><P>A. Táille athnuachana do phríomhcheadúnais córas SAS Frontex</P><P>(a) Sa togra cuimseofar cur síos mionsonraithe ar bhogearraí agus ar fho-chomhpháirteanna SAS lena n-áirítear líon na gceadúnas bogearraí comhghaolmhar a chuimsíonn croíchóras SAS Frontex.</P><P>(b) Ní bheidh ach Táille Athnuachana sa togra.</P><P>B. Togra ina gcuimsítear sraitheanna breise ceadúnas bogearraí SAS chun croíchóras Frontex a chomhlánú d’fhonn a chumas próiseála agus/nó infhaighteachta a mhéadú.</P><P>(a) Iarrtar ar an tairgeoir na réitigh atá infheidhme ar bhonn teicniúil a mholadh, agus iad sin amháin.</P><P>(b) Sa togra cuimseofar cur síos mionsonraithe ar bhogearraí agus ar fho-chomhpháirteanna SAS lena n-áirítear líon na gceadúnas bogearraí comhghaolmhar is gá chun an méadú ar chumas próiseála agus/nó infhaighteachta a bhaint amach.</P><P>(c) Iarrtar ar an tairgeoir roinnt malairtí atá infheidhme ar bhonn teicniúil a mholadh lena gcumasaítear méadú ar chumas próiseála agus/nó infhaighteachta mar shampla: 10 %, 20 % agus 50 %. Ba cheart cur síos soiléir a dhéanamh ar na malairtí agus iad marcáilte i dtogra teicniúil agus i dtogra airgeadais mar B1, B2, etc.</P><P>(d) Beidh an dá chineál praghais sa togra: Táille don chéad bhliain agus táille athnuachana.</P><P>(e) Más gá ba cheart go gcuimseofaí sa togra an praghas ar sheirbhís suiteála ábhartha.</P><P>C. Togra in gcuimsítear sraitheanna breise ceadúnas do Bhogearraí SAS agus a fho-chomhpháirteanna, d’fhonn croíchóras SAS Frontex a leathnú trí tháirgí bogearraí eile SAS a thabhairt isteach. Cur le croíchóras reatha SAS Frontex trí mhodúil bhreise bogearraí agus na fo-chomhpháirteanna comhghaolmhara lena gcumasaítear rialachas sonraí níos fearr trí uirlis chomhtháite, nua-aimseartha, de chineál fiontraíochta ETL a thacaíonn le forbairt atá bunaithe ar GUI. Iarrtar ar an tairgeoir sraitheanna de cheadúnais bogearraí a mholadh le haghaidh:</P><P>(i) Comhtháthú sonraí SAS</P><P>(ii) Cáilíocht sonraí SAS</P><P>Ba cheart cur síos soiléir a dhéanamh ar na sraitheanna agus iad marcáilte i dtogra teicniúil agus i dtogra airgeadais mar C1 agus C2.</P><P>(a) Ní foláir nó go gcomhlíonfaidh na sraitheanna de cheadúnais bogearraí atá molta croíchóras SAS Frontex i.e. ní mór dó a bheith infheidhme go teicniúil leis an gcóras sin.</P><P>(b) Ní foláir nó go gcuimseofar liosta de na riachtanais/coinníollacha ar fad atá le comhlíonadh d’fhonn síneadh a chur chun feidhme (e.g. íosriachtanais theicniúla do fhreastalaithe, etc.).</P><P>(c) Beidh an togra leordhóthanach do chroíchóras SAS Frontex i dtéarmaí scála agus méid na sonraí a phróiseáiltear chomh maith le bheith oiriúnach chuige sin.</P><P>(d) Ní fhéadfaidh cur chun feidhme, imscaradh agus ualach oibre ionchasach laethúil na gcomhpháirteanna tionchar diúltach a thabhairt isteach ar éifeachtúlacht réiteach córais SAS Frontex reatha (e.g. agaí freagartha, feidhmíocht próiseála sonraí, cumas stórála, inrochtaineacht tuairiscí agus idirghníomhaíocht).</P><P>(e) Ba cheart go gcumasódh an réiteach a mholtar fás inchosanta maidir le húsáid an chórais de bharr méid méadaithe féideartha sonraí, líon méadaithe úsáideoirí, réimsí nua chur chun feidhme an chórais etc.</P><P>(f) Tabharfar údar maith le roghnúchán na gcomhpháirteanna a mholtar chomh maith le líon molta na gceadúnas go hachomair sa togra.</P><P>(g) Sa togra cuimseofar cur síos mionsonraithe ar bhogearraí agus ar fho-chomhpháirteanna SAS lena n-áirítear líon na gceadúnas bogearraí comhghaolmhara a theastaíonn chun croíchóras SAS Frontex a leathnú faoin bhfeidhmiúlacht atá beartaithe.</P><P>(h) Beidh an dá chineál praghais sa togra: Táille don chéad bhliain agus táille athnuachana.</P><P>(e) Más gá ba cheart go gcuimseofaí sa togra an praghas ar sheirbhís suiteála ábhartha.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Cáilíochtaí, saineolas, oiriúnacht agus cumais ghairmiúla conraitheora, soiléire agus achomaireacht an togra theicniúil ar an iomlán agus tuiscint ar na cuspóirí.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Ó chuireadh tús le Frontex tá an anailís rioscaí ar cheann de na príomhghníomhaíochtaí oibriúcháin ar bunús é do ghníomhaíochtaí eile. Sainíodh tascanna a bhaineann le hanailís riosca, le feidhmiú ag Frontex, sa chéad Rialachán de chuid Frontex (CE) 2007/2004. I Rialachán nua Frontex (AE) 2016/1624 leathnaítear fiú na tascanna a bhaineann le hanailís riosca i gcomparáid leis an gcaoi ina raibh siad. Tá athrú tagtha ar struchtúr eagraíochtúil Frontex le déanaí agus tá feasacht ar dhálaí agus rannóg faireacháin cruthaithe anois d’fhonn na ceanglais nua a chomhlíonadh.</P><P>Ról bhogearraí SAS agus a thábhacht maidir le próiseas anailís ar rioscaí in Frontex</P><P>Is uirlis í teicneolaíocht SAS a thacaíonn le tascanna anailíse riosca in Frontex. Tharla an chéad chur chun feidhme maidir le teicneolaíocht SAS in 2008. Ó 2008 tá Frontex tar éis líon suntasach acmhainní a infheistiú ó thaobh ama, acmhainní daonna agus airgeadais le haghaidh:</P><P>— Ceadúnais bhogearraí SAS agus á gcomhtháthú le hailtireacht Frontex,</P><P>— Crua-earraí sonrach d’fhonn riachtanais na mbogearraí SAS a úsáidtear a chomhlíonadh,</P><P>— Oiliúint agus ceardlanna a rinneadh chun cabhrú le foireann Frontex teacht ar an eolas cuí. Tá corpas téagartha eolais anois curtha ar bun in Frontex atá bunaithe ar an teicneolaíocht SAS.</P><P>Sa lá atá inniu ann tá teicneolaíocht SAS ar cheann de na croí-chomhpháirteanna atá ríthábhachtach sa phróiseas anailíse riosca.</P><P>Níor mhór cinneadh straitéiseach chun athsholáthar féideartha a dhéanamh ar theicneolaíocht SAS le haghaidh teicneolaíocht choibhéiseach d’fhonn próiseas a thionscnamh a mhairfidh roinnt blianta agus a mbeidh infheistíochtaí suntasacha airgeadais agus neamhairgeadais ag teastáil chun leibhéal aibíochta comhchosúil leis an gceann reatha a bhaint amach. Le linn na tréimhse sin d’éileofaí go gcoimeádfaí ar a laghad na réitigh atá bunaithe ar theicneolaíocht SAS.</P><P>SAS Institute agus a shuíomh ar an margadh.</P><P>Is é SAS Institute Inc. an t-aon mhonaróir agus foilsitheoir ar bhogearraí SAS. Is é SAS Institute Inc. úinéir na gceart maoine intleachtúla i mbogearraí SAS. Tá an ceart eisiach ag SAS Institute sp. z o.o., fochuideachta de chuid SAS Institute Inc., chun ceadúnais a dheonú le haghaidh bogearraí SAS chun tairbhe eintiteas a bhfuil oibleagáid orthu dlí soláthair phoiblí a úsáid sa Pholainn.</P><P>Rogha de nós imeachta soláthair.</P><P>Nós imeachta idirbheartaithe gan fógra conartha a fhoilsiú roimh ré a bheidh i gceist leis an nós imeachta soláthair do cheadúnais bogearraí SAS i gcomhréir le Pointe 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) d’Iarscríbhinn I FR (roimhe sin Airteagal 134(1)(b)(ii)(iii) RAP), mar gheall go bhfuil cúiseanna teicniúla ann agus go bhfuil gá le cearta eisiacha a chosaint. Dá bhrí sin ní féidir an conradh a dhámhachtain ach ar aon oibreoir eacnamaíoch amháin. Ós rud é gurb í an Institiúid SAS an t-aon úinéir ar na ceadúnais roghnaíodh an nós imeachta thuasluaite.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Creatchonradh le haghaidh ceadúnas bogearraí SAS a fháil</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>An Chúirt Ghinearálta</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>An Chúirt Ghinearálta</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>An Chúirt Ghinearálta</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="BG"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Европейска агенция за гранична и брегова охрана</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Рамков договор за набавяне на лицензи за софтуер SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Предметът на тази поръчка е да се създаде канал за набавяне под формата на рамков договор, позволяващ закупуване на лицензи за софтуер SAS:</P><P>1) с оглед да се поднови и поддържа наборът от лицензи за софтуер SAS, който се използва в Frontex;</P><P>2) с оглед да се разшири по избор наборът от лицензи за софтуер SAS, който се използва в Frontex чрез:</P><P>а) закупуване на повече лицензи за продукти, които се използват; и/или</P><P>б) закупуване на лицензи за други софтуерни продукти SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, ПОЛША</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Предметът на тази поръчка е предоставянето на лицензи за софтуер SAS съгласно рамковия договор.</P><P>От оферента се изискваше да предостави следните услуги и доставки:</P><P>А. Такса за подновяване (RF) на лицензите за основната SAS система на Frontex:</P><P>а) предложението трябва да съдържа подробна спецификация на софтуера SAS и подкомпонентите, включително броя на свързаните софтуерни лицензи, които съставят основната система SAS на Frontex;</P><P>б) предложението трябва да съдържа само такса за подновяване (RF).</P><P>Б. Предложение, съдържащо допълнителни набори от лицензи за софтуер SAS за допълване на основната система SAS на Frontex с цел увеличаване на нейния капацитет за обработка и/или наличност:</P><P>а) от оферента се изисква да предложи само технически приложими решения;</P><P>б) предложението трябва да съдържа подробна спецификация на софтуера SAS и подкомпонентите, включително броя на свързаните софтуерни лицензи, които са необходими за постигане на планираното увеличение на капацитета за обработка и/или наличност;</P><P>в) от оферента се изисква да предложи няколко технически приложими варианта, позволяващи увеличаване на капацитета за обработка и/или наличност напр. с: 10 %, 20 % и 50 %. Вариантите следва да бъдат ясно описани и обозначени в техническото предложение и във финансовото предложение като Б1, Б2 и т.н;</P><P>г) предложението трябва да съдържа и двата вида цени: такса за първата година (FYF) и такса за подновяване (RF);</P><P>д) при необходимост, предложението следва да съдържа цена за съответната инсталационна услуга.</P><P>В. Предложение, съдържащо допълнителни набори от лицензи за софтуер SAS и неговите подкомпоненти, с цел разширяване на основната система SAS на Frontex чрез въвеждане на други софтуерни продукти на SAS. За разширяване на текущата основна система SAS на Frontex с допълнителни софтуерни модули и свързаните подкомпоненти, позволяващи по-добро управление на данните чрез интегриран, модерен ETL инструмент от корпоративен клас, който поддържа GUI-базирани разработки. От оферента се изисква да предложи набори от софтуерни лицензи за:</P><P>i) интеграция на SAS данни;</P><P>ii) качество на SAS данни.</P><P>Вариантите следва да бъдат ясно описани и обозначени в техническото предложение и във финансовото предложение като В1 и В2.</P><P>а) предложените набори от софтуерни лицензи трябва да отговарят напълно на основната система SAS на Frontex, т.е. трябва да бъдат технически приложими за тази система;</P><P>б) предложението трябва да съдържа списък на всички задължителни изисквания/условия, които трябва да бъдат изпълнени, за да се осъществи дадено разширение (например минимални технически изисквания за сървъри и т.н.);</P><P>в) предложението трябва да бъде подходящо за основната система SAS на Frontex по отношение на мащаба и количеството на обработваните данни, както и за целта;</P><P>г) въвеждането, внедряването и очакваното ежедневно натоварване на предложените компоненти не трябва да водят до отрицателно въздействие върху ефективността на съществуващите решения на системата SAS на Frontex (напр. време за отговор, ефективност на обработката на данни, капацитет за съхранение, достъпност на докладите и интерактивност);</P><P>д) предложеното решение следва да даде възможност за обосновано увеличаване на използването на системата поради потенциално увеличен обем данни, увеличен брой потребители, нови области на приложение на системата и др.;</P><P>е) изборът на предложените компоненти, както и предложеният брой лицензи трябва да бъдат накратко обосновани в предложението;</P><P>ж) предложението трябва да съдържа подробна спецификация на софтуера SAS и подкомпонентите, включително броя на свързаните софтуерни лицензи, които са необходими за разширяване на основната SAS система на Frontex с предвидената функционалност;</P><P>з) предложението трябва да съдържа и двата вида цени: такса за първата година (FYF) и такса за подновяване (RF);</P><P>и) при необходимост, предложението следва да съдържа цена за съответната инсталационна услуга.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Квалификации, експертен опит, пригодност и професионални компетенции на изпълнителя, яснота и краткост на цялостното техническо предложение и разбиране на целите.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>От самото създаване на Frontex, анализът на риска е една от ключовите оперативни дейности, които представляват основа за други дейности. Задачите, които трябва да бъдат извършени от Frontex по отношение на анализа на риска, бяха определени в първия Регламент (ЕО) 2007/2004 относно Frontex. В новия Регламент (ЕС) 2016/1624 относно Frontex, задачите свързани с анализа на риска, дори се разширяват в сравнение с предишното състояние. Наскоро беше променена организационната структура на Frontex и беше създаден отдел за осведоменост и наблюдение на ситуацията, за да бъдат изпълнени новите изисквания.</P><P>Ролята на софтуера SAS и неговото значение за процеса на анализ на риска в Frontex:</P><P>Технологията SAS е инструментът, който поддържа задачите за анализ на риска във Frontex. Първото прилагане на технологията SAS е осъществено през 2008 г. От 2008 г. насам Frontex е инвестирала значително количество ресурси по отношение на време, човешки ресурси и финансови средства за:</P><P>— лицензи за софтуер SAS и неговата интеграция в архитектурата на Frontex,</P><P>— специфичен хардуер, който да отговаря на изискванията на използвания софтуер SAS,</P><P>— обучения и семинари, които бяха проведени с цел улесняване на персонала на Frontex да придобие необходимите знания. Понастоящем във Frontex има значителен набор от знания, базирани на технологията SAS.</P><P>В днешно време технологията SAS е един от основните и критични компоненти на процеса на анализ на риска.</P><P>Потенциалното заместване на технологията SAS с еквивалентна технология би изисквало стратегическо решение, за да започне процес, който ще продължи няколко години и ще изисква значителни финансови и нефинансови инвестиции, за да се достигне ниво на зрялост, подобно на настоящото. През този период, ще се изисква решенията на базата на технологията SAS да бъдат поне поддържани.</P><P>SAS Institute и неговата пазарна позиция.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc е единствен производител и издател на софтуер SAS. SAS Institute Inc е собственик на правата върху интелектуалната собственост за софтуер SAS. SAS Institute sp. z o.o, дъщерно дружество на SAS Institute Inc., има изключителното право да предоставя лицензи за софтуер SAS в полза на лица, задължени да използват Закона за обществените поръчки в Полша.</P><P>Избор на процедура за обществена поръчка.</P><P>Процедурата за обществена поръчка за лицензи за софтуер SAS ще бъде договорена без предварително публикуване на обявление за поръчка в съответствие с точка 11, параграф 1, буква б), ii), iii) от приложение I към Финансовия регламент (FR) (преди това член 134, параграф 1, буква б), точки ii) и iii) от правилата за прилагане (RAP), поради съществуването на технически причини и необходимостта от защита на изключителни права. Поради това договорът може да бъде възложен само на един конкретен икономически оператор Предвид факта че SAS Institute е едноличен собственик на лицензите, е избрана посочената по-горе процедура.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Рамков договор за набавяне на лицензи за софтуер SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Общ съд</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Общ съд</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Общ съд</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="RO"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex – Agenția Europeană pentru Poliția de Frontieră și Garda de Coastă</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Contract-cadru pentru achiziționarea de licențe de software SAS</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Obiectul acestui contract este de a stabili un canal de achiziție sub forma unui contract-cadru care să permită achiziționarea de licențe de software SAS:</P><P>1) pentru a reînnoi și a menține setul de licențe ale software-ului SAS care este utilizat în Frontex;</P><P>2) pentru a extinde opțional setul de licențe ale software-ului SAS care este utilizat în Frontex prin:</P><P>(a) Achiziționarea mai multor licențe pentru produsele în curs de utilizare și / sau</P><P>(b) Achiziționarea de licențe pentru alte produse software SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLONIA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Obiectul acestui Contract este furnizarea de licențe pentru software-ul SAS în temeiul contractului-cadru.</P><P>Ofertantului i s-a solicitat să furnizeze următoarele servicii și bunuri:</P><P>A. Taxă de reînnoire (TR) pentru licențele sistemului de bază SAS al Frontex</P><P>(a) Propunerea va conține o specificație detaliată a software-ului SAS și a sub-componentelor, inclusiv numărul de licențe software conexe care compun sistemul de bază SAS al Frontex.</P><P>(b) Propunerea conține numai taxa de reînnoire (TR).</P><P>B. O propunere care va conține un set suplimentar de licențe pentru software-ul SAS pentru a completa sistemul de bază SAS al Frontex cu scopul de a-și spori capacitatea de procesare și / sau disponibilitatea.</P><P>(a) Ofertantul trebuie să propună numai soluțiile care se aplică din punct de vedere tehnic.</P><P>(a) Propunerea va conține o specificație detaliată a software-ului SAS și a sub-componentelor, inclusiv numărul de licențe software conexe care sunt necesare pentru a atinge creșterea planificată a capacității de procesare și / sau a disponibilității.</P><P>(c) Ofertantul este invitat să propună câteva variante aplicabile din punct de vedere tehnic care să permită o creștere a capacității de procesare și / sau a disponibilității, de exemplu cu: 10 %, 20 % și 50 %. Variantele trebuie să fie clar descrise și marcate în propunerea tehnică și în propunerea financiară ca B1, B2 etc.</P><P>(d) Propunerea va conține ambele tipuri de prețuri: Taxa pentru primul an (TPA) și taxa de reînnoire (TR).</P><P>(e) Dacă este necesar, propunerea ar trebui să conțină un preț al unui serviciu de instalare relevant.</P><P>C. Propunere care conține seturi suplimentare de licențe pentru software-ul SAS și subcomponentele acestuia pentru a extinde sistemul SAS de bază al Frontex prin introducerea altor produse software SAS. Extinderea sistemului de bază SAS actual al Frontex prin module software suplimentare și sub-componentele aferente, permițând o mai bună gestionare a datelor printr-un instrument ETL modern integrat pentru întreprinderi, care suportă dezvoltarea bazată pe GUI. Ofertantul este invitat să propună seturi de licențe software pentru:</P><P>(i) SAS Data Integration</P><P>(ii) SAS Data Quality</P><P>Variantele trebuie să fie clar descrise și marcate în propunerea tehnică și în propunerea financiară ca C1 și C2.</P><P>(a) seturile de licențe de software propuse trebuie să respecte pe deplin sistemul de bază SAS al Frontex, adică trebuie să fie aplicabile din punct de vedere tehnic pentru acest sistem.</P><P>(b) Propunerea trebuie să conțină o listă a tuturor cerințelor / condițiilor obligatorii care trebuie îndeplinite pentru a pune în aplicare o extensie (de exemplu, cerințele tehnice minime pentru servere, etc.).</P><P>(c) Propunerea trebuie să fie adecvată sistemului central SAS al Frontex în ceea ce privește amploarea și cantitatea de date prelucrate, precum și pentru a se potrivi scopului.</P><P>(d) punerea în aplicare, utilizarea și volumul de muncă zilnic preconizat pentru componentele propuse nu pot avea un impact negativ asupra eficienței soluțiilor existente ale sistemului Frontex SAS (de ex. timpii de răspuns, performanța procesării datelor, capacitatea de stocare, accesibilitatea rapoartelor și interactivitatea).</P><P>(e) Soluția propusă ar trebui să permită o creștere justificată a utilizării sistemului din cauza volumului potențial crescut de date, numărului crescut de utilizatori, noilor domenii de aplicare a sistemului, etc.</P><P>(f) Selecția propusă a componentelor, precum și numărul de licențe propuse sunt justificate pe scurt în propunere.</P><P>(g) Propunerea va conține o specificație detaliată a software-ului SAS și a sub-componentelor, inclusiv numărul de licențe software care sunt necesare pentru extinderea sistemului de bază SAS al Frontex prin funcționalitatea prevăzută.</P><P>(h) Propunerea va conține ambele tipuri de prețuri: Taxa pentru primul an (TPA) și taxa de reînnoire (TR).</P><P>(i) Dacă este necesar, propunerea ar trebui să conțină un preț al unui serviciu de instalare relevant.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Calificările, expertiza, caracterul adecvat și competențele profesionale ale Contractantului, claritatea și concizia propunerii tehnice în ansamblu și înțelegerea obiectivelor.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Încă de înființarea Frontex, analiza riscurilor este una dintre principalele activitățile operaționale care constituie o bază pentru alte activități. Sarcinile legate de analiza riscurilor, care urmează să fie realizate de Frontex, au fost definite în primul regulament (CE) 2007/2004 al Frontex. În noul Regulament (UE) 2016/1624 al Frontex, sarcinile legate de analiza riscurilor sunt chiar extinse în comparație cu statul anterior. Structura organizațională Frontex a fost recent modificată și Divizia de Conștientizare Situațională și Monitorizare a fost creată pentru a îndeplini noile cerințe.</P><P>Rolul software-ului SAS și importanța acestuia în procesul de analiză a riscurilor în cadrul Frontex</P><P>Tehnologia SAS este instrumentul care sprijină sarcinile de analiză a riscurilor în cadrul Frontex. Prima punere în aplicare a tehnologiei SAS a avut loc în 2008. Începând cu anul 2008, Frontex investește o sumă semnificativă de resurse în materie de timp, resursele umane și mijloacele financiare pentru:</P><P>— Licențele software SAS și integrarea sa în arhitectura Frontex,</P><P>— Hardware specific pentru a îndeplini cerințele software-ului SAS utilizate,</P><P>— Cursuri de formare și ateliere de lucru care au fost organizate pentru a ajuta personalul Frontex să dobândească cunoștințele corespunzătoare. În Frontex există acum un volum substanțial de cunoștințe bazat pe tehnologia SAS.</P><P>În prezent, tehnologia SAS este una dintre componentele esențiale și critice pentru procesului de analiză a riscurilor.</P><P>Înlocuirea potențială a tehnologiei SAS cu o tehnologie echivalentă ar necesita o decizie strategică pentru a iniția un proces care să dureze câțiva ani și ar necesita investiții financiare și nefinanciare semnificative pentru a atinge un nivel de maturitate similar cu cel actual. În această perioadă soluțiile bazate pe tehnologia SAS ar trebui să fie cel puțin menținute.</P><P>Institutul SAS și poziția sa pe piață.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. este singurul producător și editor al software-ului SAS. SAS Institute Inc. este proprietarul drepturilor de proprietate intelectuală în SAS Software. SAS Institute sp. z o.o. o filială a SAS Institute Inc., are dreptul exclusiv de a acorda licențe Software SAS în beneficiul entităților obligate să respecte Legea privind achizițiile publice în Polonia.</P><P>Alegerea procedurii de achiziții.</P><P>Procedura de achiziții pentru licențele software-ului SAS va fi procedura negociată fără publicarea prealabilă a unui anunț de participare în conformitate cu punctul 11(1)(b)(ii)(iii) din anexa I FR (anterior art. 134 (1) (b) (ii) (iii) RAP), din cauza existenței unor motive tehnice și a necesității de protecție a drepturilor exclusive. Astfel, contractul poate fi atribuit doar unui singur operator economic. Dat fiind faptul că Institutul SAS este singurul deținător al licențelor, a fost aleasă procedura menționată mai sus.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Contract-cadru pentru achiziționarea de licențe de software SAS</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunalul</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunalul</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Tribunalul</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014><F03_2014 CATEGORY="TRANSLATION" FORM="F03" LG="HR"><LEGAL_BASIS VALUE="32014L0024"/><CONTRACTING_BODY><ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Frontex — Agencija za europsku graničnu i obalnu stražu</OFFICIALNAME><NATIONALID>140232006</NATIONALID><ADDRESS>pl. Europejski 6</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>00-844</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><CONTACT_POINT>Frontex Procurement Team</CONTACT_POINT><PHONE>+48 222059500</PHONE><E_MAIL>procurement@frontex.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+48 222059501</FAX><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL911"/><URL_GENERAL>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_GENERAL><URL_BUYER>https://frontex.europa.eu/</URL_BUYER></ADDRESS_CONTRACTING_BODY><CA_TYPE VALUE="EU_INSTITUTION"/><CA_ACTIVITY VALUE="GENERAL_PUBLIC_SERVICES"/></CONTRACTING_BODY><OBJECT_CONTRACT><TITLE><P>Okvirni ugovor za nabavu licenci za softver sustava za statističku analizu (Statistical Analysis System — SAS)</P></TITLE><REFERENCE_NUMBER>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</REFERENCE_NUMBER><CPV_MAIN><CPV_CODE CODE="48463000"/></CPV_MAIN><TYPE_CONTRACT CTYPE="SERVICES"/><SHORT_DESCR><P>Predmet je ugovora uspostavljanje kanala za nabavu u obliku okvirnog ugovora kojim se omogućuje nabava licenci za softver sustava za statističku analizu (SAS):</P><P>1) u cilju obnavljanja i održavanja skupa licenci za softver SAS koji se koristi u Frontexu;</P><P>2) kako bi se neobvezno produžio skup licenci za softver SAS koji se koristi u Frontexu s pomoću:</P><P>(a) nabave više licenci za proizvode koji se koriste i/ili</P><P>(b) nabava licenci za druge proizvode softvera SAS.</P></SHORT_DESCR><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL><NO_LOT_DIVISION/><OBJECT_DESCR ITEM="1"><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/><MAIN_SITE><P>Frontex, pl. Europejski 6</P><P>00-844 Warszawa, POLJSKA</P></MAIN_SITE><SHORT_DESCR><P>Predmet je ugovora nabava licenci za softver SAS u skladu s okvirnim ugovorom.</P><P>Od ponuditelja se tražilo da pruži sljedeće usluge i robu:</P><P>A. Naknada za obnavljanje (renewal fee - RF) Frontexove osnovne licence sustava SAS</P><P>(a) Ponuda mora sadržavati detaljnu specifikaciju softvera SAS i podkomponenti, uključujući broj povezanih softverskih licenci koje čine Frontexov osnovni sustav SAS.</P><P>(b) Ponuda mora sadržavati samo naknadu za obnavljanje (RF).</P><P>B. Ponuda koja sadrži dodatne skupove licenci za softver SAS za dopunu Frontexovog osnovnog sustava SAS kako bi se povećala njegova sposobnost obrade i/ili dostupnost.</P><P>(a) Od ponuditelja se traži da predloži samo tehnički primjenjiva rješenja.</P><P>(b) Ponuda mora sadržavati detaljnu specifikaciju softvera SAS i podkomponenti, uključujući broj povezanih softverskih licenci koje su potrebne za postizanje planiranog povećanja sposobnosti obrade i/ili dostupnosti.</P><P>(c) Od ponuditelja se traži da predloži nekoliko tehnički primjenjivih varijanti koje omogućuju povećanje sposobnosti obrade i/ili dostupnosti za npr.: 10 %, 20 % i 50 %. Varijante trebaju biti jasno opisane i označene u tehničkoj ponudi i u financijskoj ponudi kao B1, B2, itd.</P><P>(d) Ponuda mora sadržavati obje vrste cijena: naknada za 1. godinu (First Year Fee - FYF) i naknada za obnavljanje (Renewal Fee - RF).</P><P>(e) Ako je potrebno, prijedlog treba sadržavati cijenu relevantne usluge ugradnje.</P><P>C. Ponuda koja sadrži dodatne skupove licenci za softver SAS i njegove podkomponente, kako bi se proširio Frontexov osnovni sustav SAS uvođenjem drugih softverskih proizvoda SAS-a za produženje trenutnog Frontexovog osnovnog sustava SAS dodatnim softverskim modulima i povezanim podkomponentama, što će omogućiti bolje upravljanje podacima integriranim, suvremenim ETL alatom koji podržava razvoj zasnovan na GUI-ju. Od ponuditelja se traži da predloži skupove softverskih licenci za:</P><P>(i) integraciju podataka SAS-a</P><P>(ii) kvalitetu podataka SAS-a</P><P>Skupovi trebaju biti jasno opisani i označeni u tehničkoj ponudi i u financijskoj ponudi kao C1 i C2.</P><P>(a) Predloženi skupovi softverskih licenci moraju biti u potpunosti u skladu s Frontexovim osnovnim sustavom SAS, tj. moraju biti tehnički primjenjivi na ovaj sustav.</P><P>(b) Ponuda mora sadržavati popis svih obveznih zahtjeva/uvjeta koje treba ispuniti kako bi se provela dopuna (npr. minimalni tehnički zahtjevi za poslužitelje itd.).</P><P>(c) Ponuda mora biti primjerena Frontexovom osnovnom sustavu SAS s obzirom na opseg i količinu obrađenih podataka, kao i da odgovara svrsi.</P><P>(d) Provedba, raspoređivanje i očekivano dnevno radno opterećenje predloženih komponenti ne smiju imati negativan učinak na učinkovitost postojećih rješenja Frontexova sustava SAS (npr. vrijeme odaziva, učinkovitost obrade podataka, sposobnost pohrane, dostupnost izvješća i interaktivnost).</P><P>(e) Predloženo rješenje trebalo bi omogućiti opravdani rast korištenja sustava zbog potencijalno povećanog opsega podataka, povećanog broja korisnika, novih područja primjene sustava itd.</P><P>(f) Odabir predloženih komponenti kao i predloženi broj licenci bit će ukratko obrazloženi u ponudi.</P><P>(g) Ponuda mora sadržavati detaljnu specifikaciju softvera SAS i podkomponenti, uključujući broj povezanih softverskih licenci koje su potrebne za proširenje Frontexovog osnovnog sustava SAS na planiranu funkcionalnost.</P><P>(h) Ponuda mora sadržavati obje vrste cijena: naknada za 1. godinu (First Year Fee - FYF) i naknada za obnavljanje (Renewal Fee - RF).</P><P>(i) Ako je potrebno, ponuda treba sadržavati cijenu relevantne usluge ugradnje.</P></SHORT_DESCR><AC><AC_QUALITY><AC_CRITERION>Kvalifikacije, stručnost, prikladnost i stručne sposobnosti izvoditelja, jasnoća i sažetost ukupne tehničke ponude i razumijevanje ciljeva.</AC_CRITERION><AC_WEIGHTING>60</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_QUALITY><AC_PRICE><AC_WEIGHTING>40</AC_WEIGHTING></AC_PRICE></AC><NO_OPTIONS/><NO_EU_PROGR_RELATED/></OBJECT_DESCR></OBJECT_CONTRACT><PROCEDURE><PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_PROTECT_RIGHTS/></D_ACCORDANCE_ARTICLE><D_JUSTIFICATION><P>Od samog početka Frontexa analiza rizika jedna je od ključnih operativnih aktivnosti koje čine osnovu za druge aktivnosti. Zadaci povezani s analizom rizika, koje će Frontex provesti, navedeni su u prvoj Frontexovoj uredbi (EZ) 2007/2004. U novoj Uredbi Frontexa (EU) 2016/1624 zadaće povezane s analizom rizika čak su proširene u usporedbi s prethodnim stanjem. Frontexova organizacijska struktura nedavno je promijenjena i stvoren je Odsjek za situacijsku osviještenost i praćenje kako bi se ispunili novi zahtjevi.</P><P>Uloga softvera SAS i njegova važnost za proces analize rizika u Frontexu</P><P>Tehnologija SAS alat je koji podržava zadatke analize rizika u Frontexu. Prva provedba tehnologije SAS održana je 2008. Od 2008. Frontex je uložio značajnu količinu sredstava u smislu vremena, ljudskih resursa i financijskih sredstava za:</P><P>— licence za softver SAS i njegovu integraciju u Frontexovu arhitekturu,</P><P>— specifični hardver koji ispunjava zahtjeve softvera SAS,</P><P>— osposobljavanja i radionice koje su provedene kako bi se osoblju Frontexa olakšalo stjecanje odgovarajućeg znanja. Sada je u Frontexu osnovano značajno znanje utemeljeno na tehnologiji SAS.</P><P>Danas je tehnologija SAS jedna od ključnih i kritičnih komponenti procesa analize rizika.</P><P>Moguća zamjena tehnologije SAS ekvivalentnom tehnologijom zahtijevala bi stratešku odluku kako bi se pokrenuo proces koji će trajati nekoliko godina i zahtijevala bi značajna financijska i nefinancijska ulaganja kako bi se dostigla razina zrelosti slična sadašnjoj. Tijekom tog razdoblja rješenja koja se temelje na tehnologiji SAS zahtijevala bi barem održavanje.</P><P>SAS Institute i njegova tržišna pozicija.</P><P>SAS Institute Inc. je jedini proizvođač i izdavač softvera SAS. SAS Institute Inc. vlasnik je prava intelektualnog vlasništva za softver SAS. SAS Institute sp. z o.o. podružnica je poduzeća SAS Institute Inc., ima isključivo pravo izdavanja licenci za softver SAS u korist subjekata koji su obvezni koristiti Zakon o javnoj nabavi u Poljskoj.</P><P>Izbor postupka nadmetanja.</P><P>Postupak nabave za licence softvera SAS bit će pregovarački postupak bez prethodne objave poziva na nadmetanje u skladu s točkom 11. stavak 1. točka (b) podtočke (ii) i (iii) Priloga I. FR (prethodno čl. 134. stavak 1. točke (b) podtočke (ii) i (iii) RAP-a), zbog postojanja tehničkih razloga i potrebe zaštite isključivih prava. Stoga se ugovor može dodijeliti samo 1 određenom gospodarskom subjektu. S obzirom na to da je SAS Institute jedini vlasnik licenci odabran je gore navedeni postupak.</P></D_JUSTIFICATION></PT_AWARD_CONTRACT_WITHOUT_CALL><FRAMEWORK/><NO_CONTRACT_COVERED_GPA/></PROCEDURE><AWARD_CONTRACT ITEM="1"><CONTRACT_NO>Frontex/NP/1486/2018</CONTRACT_NO><TITLE><P>Okvirni ugovor za nabavu licenci za softver sustava za statističku analizu (Statistical Analysis System — SAS)</P></TITLE><AWARDED_CONTRACT><DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT>2018-12-21</DATE_CONCLUSION_CONTRACT><TENDERS><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED><NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS>1</NB_TENDERS_RECEIVED_EMEANS></TENDERS><CONTRACTORS><NO_AWARDED_TO_GROUP/><CONTRACTOR><ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><OFFICIALNAME>SAS Institute Polska Sp. z o.o.</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>ul. Gdańska 27/31</ADDRESS><TOWN>Warszawa</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>01-633</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="PL"/><PHONE>+48 225604600</PHONE><n2016:NUTS CODE="PL"/></ADDRESS_CONTRACTOR><NO_SME/></CONTRACTOR></CONTRACTORS><VALUES><VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_ESTIMATED_TOTAL><VAL_TOTAL CURRENCY="EUR">1350000.00</VAL_TOTAL></VALUES></AWARDED_CONTRACT></AWARD_CONTRACT><COMPLEMENTARY_INFO><ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Opći sud</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_BODY><ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><OFFICIALNAME>Opći sud</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_MEDIATION_BODY><ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><OFFICIALNAME>Opći sud</OFFICIALNAME><ADDRESS>Rue du Fort Niedergrünewald</ADDRESS><TOWN>Luxembourg</TOWN><POSTAL_CODE>L-2925</POSTAL_CODE><COUNTRY VALUE="LU"/><PHONE>+352 4303-1</PHONE><E_MAIL>cfi.registry@curia.europa.eu</E_MAIL><FAX>+352 4303-2100</FAX><URL>http://curia.europa.eu/</URL></ADDRESS_REVIEW_INFO><DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE>2019-01-17</DATE_DISPATCH_NOTICE></COMPLEMENTARY_INFO></F03_2014></FORM_SECTION></TED_EXPORT>